Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help, so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in
!¡Vámonos!
♪ You can lead the way
♪ Hey, hey!
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Hi, I'm Dora.
I'm looking for my friend
Boots the monkey.
Do you see Boots?
[ giggles]
Where?
In the tree?
There he is!
!¡Gracias!
Thanks!
Boots!
Dora!
Help!
Bugga bugga
bugga bugga...
Boots, did you hear that?
Help!
!¡Ayudame!
Bugga bugga
bugga bugga...
Look, Dora!
It's Mami Bugga Bugga
and her Bugga Bugga babies!
Help! Help!
BABIES:
Bugga bugga bugga bugga...
What's wrong,
Mami Bugga Bugga?
Oh, Dora, Boots--
I need your help.
I have ten Bugga Bugga babies
but one is lost!
Don't worry,
Mami Bugga Bugga.
We'll help you find
your Bugga Bugga baby.
Will you help us
find the Bugga Bugga baby?
Great.
What sound does
a baby Bugga Bugga make?
Bugga bugga.
Right!
Let's listen to the sounds
to find the baby bug.
Bottle bottle.
Bugga bugga.
Burger burger.
Bubble bubble.
I know.
The baby bug's
behind the flowers!
Bubble bubble.
That's not
the Bugga Bugga baby.
Bottle bottle.
Bugga bugga.
Burger burger.
Where's the
Bugga Bugga baby?
Behind the rock?
[ click, beep]
Bugga bugga.
Right,
there he is!
!¡Mamá!
!¡Mi bebé!
Thanks for helping us
find the Bugga Bugga baby.
Oh, Dora, Boots, !¡gracias!
!¡Gracias!
Thank you!
[ both laugh]
Oh, we better fly.
There's a big party
at the tree house.
And you're invited!
You've got to come!
!¡Vengan!
Sera divertido.
It will be fun.
You've got to come!
A big party
at the tree house!
And we're invited!
Party! Party!
I love parties!
Come on, Boots!
Let's go to the big party
at the tree house!
Dora, how do we get
to the tree house?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help when
we don't know which way to go?
The Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us
how to get to the tree house!
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find out how to get
to the tree house?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map," say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know
♪ I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet
♪ I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map!
Dora and Boots want to get to
the big party at the tree house.
[ cheering]
Well, I know how to get
to the tree house.
First you cross Crocodile Lake.
Then you go over the stone wall.
And that's how you get to
the big party at the tree house.
[ cheering]
So you tell Dora:
Lake...
wall...
tree house.
Say it with me.
Lake...
wall...
tree house.
Lake...
wall...
tree house.
Lake...
wall...
tree house...!
How do we get to the tree house?
Lake...
wall..
tree house.
First we have to cross
CROCODILE LAKE...
then we go
over the stone wall...
and that's how we'll get
to the big party
at the tree house.
[ cheering]
Thanks for helping.
So first we have to find
Crocodile Lake.
Do you see a lake?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's the lake.
Crocodile Lake!
Ooh... there
are crocodiles
at Crocodile Lake.
!¡Vámonos!
Let's go to the big party
at the tree house!
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Lake, wall, tree house!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tree house!
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tree house!
ALL:
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Tree house!
BOOTS:
Look, it's Tico!
DORA: !¡Hola, Tico!
Hi, Tico!
!¡Hola, Dora!
!¡Hola, Boots!
!¡Tengo globos
para la fiesta!
Oh! Tico's bringing
these balloons
to the party!
[ rustling]
Oh, no!
That sounds like
Swiper the fox.
That sneaky fox
is always trying
to swipe our stuff.
Ooh, Swiper!
He'll try to swipe
Tico's balloons!
Will you help us watch out
for Swiper the fox?
Great! If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
You see Swiper?
Where?
Yeah,
there he is!
ALL: Swiper, no...
ALL: ...swiping.
You're too late!
!¡Mis globos! !Mis globos!
You'll never find them now!
[ laughs]
Aw, don't worry,
Tico.
We'll help you
find your balloons.
Will you help us
find Tico's balloons?
Great!
Look for Tico's balloons.
Do you see balloons?
Do you see the yellow balloon?
[ click, beep]
You found it!
Where's the red balloon?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Do you see the orange balloon?
[ click, beep]
Good looking.
Now find the purple balloon.
[ click, beep]
You found it!
Can you find the green one?
[ click, beep]
Right, there it is!
!¡Excelente!
Hay cinco globos.
Right.
There should be
five balloons.
Let's count in Spanish
with Tico
to see if we found
all five balloons.
Repeat after us.
ALL:
Uno...
dos...
tres...
cuatro...
cinco!
Did we find
all five balloons?
Yes!
!¡Gracias!
De nada.
Yeah, thanks for helping us.
Now let's give Tico
his balloons.
Count with us.
ALL: !¡Uno, dos, tres, cuatro, cinco!
!¡Gracias, gracias, gracias!
De nada.
Whee...!
BOTH:
Tico!
Whee...!
!¡Nos vemos
en la fiesta grande!
!¡Nos vemos!
Tico's going
to the big party.
Look!
He's floating
right over Crocodile Lake!
Hey, Dora... how are wegoing
to get across Crocodile Lake?
Good question.
Ahoy,
mateys!
[ whistles]
Look, it's
Pirate Parrot.
He can take us
across Crocodile Lake!
Aye, it's me,
but look at me boat.
It's broken to pieces!
[ squawks]
I have to fix me boat
to get across Crocodile Lake.
[ squawks, whistles]
DORA:
Don't worry.
We'll help you.
Will you help us put
Pirate Parrot's boat
back together?
Great.
Which piece goes here?
[ click, beep]
Right!
Which piece goes here?
[ click, beep]
And which piece
goes here?
[ click, beep]
Which piece goes here?
And which piece goes here?
[ click, beep]
Fantástico. Muy bien.
You fixed Pirate Parrot's boat!
Gracias,me hearties.
Thank you! Thank you!
And now I can sail you
across Crocodile Lake
so you can get
to the big party
at the tree house!
[ squawks]
BOTH:
Yay!
Wow! We're going
really fast!
Aye, me
monkey friend.
We're going
superfast.
Always a good idea
to go super fast
on CROCODILE LAKE!
[ squawks] Ho-ho!
[ play happy tune]
We made it across
Crocodile Lake!
[ squawks]
I've got to hurry,
mateys.
I'll see you at the party!
Where do we go next?
Lake...
wall...
tree house.
We made it over the lake
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
wall, right.
The stone wall.
Do you see a wall?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's the stone wall!
!¡Vámonos!
Let's go to the big party
at the tree house!
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Lake, wall, tree house!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tree house!
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tree house!
ALL:
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Tree house!
Help! Help!
Look, it's
Isa the Iguana.
Hi, Dora.
Hi, Boots.
What's wrong,
Isa?
My scooter is broken.
And I need to get
to the party.
Do you see what's wrong
with Isa's scooter?
BOOTS:
Yeah! It's missing a wheel.
I might have a wheel
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
to find a wheel for the scooter?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need
♪ I got inside for you
♪ Backpack, Backpack
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah!
!¡Hola!
I have lots of wheels.
But Dora needs you to find
a wheel for Isa's scooter
so she can get to the party!
Can you use this wheel
on a scooter?
No, that's a Ferris wheel.
Can you use this wheel
on a scooter?
That's the right wheel
but that wheel is flat.
Can you use this wheel
on a scooter?
[ click, beep]
Right!
!¡Excelente!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
!¡Delicioso!
!¡Gracias! !Gracias!
Thank you! Thank you!
I've got to hurry.
See you
at the tree house!
Come on!
Let's go to the big party
at the tree house!
[ grunting
and groaning]
Here's the wall!
[ grunting
and groaning]
Look! Someone's
stuck in the wall.
Hello! Who is this?
It's me,
Benny the Bull.
I got stuck
in the wall.
Aw, Benny,
don't worry.
We'll get you out.
[ whispers]:
How are we going
to do that, Dora?
Hmm... Let's climb
over the wall.
Then we can
pull him out.
Gracias, Boots.
De nada.
Gracias, Dora!
[ play happy tune]
BOTH:
Hi, Benny.
Hi. I'm stuck.
We made it
OVER the wall
but Benny's still
stuck IN the wall.
We'll get you out.
It's no use.
Go to the big party without me.
I don't want you to miss it.
Just... bring me
three pieces of cake.
Aw, Benny,
we'll help you.
Right, Boots?
Right!
Benny, can we try
pulling you out?
Yeah, great idea!
Okay, come on, Boots.
[ all grunting and groaning]
Aw, Benny, you're really stuck.
We need your help.
Will you help us
pull Benny out of the wall?
Great.
Put your arms out
in front of you
and get ready to pull.
Now pull, pull, pull!
Pull, pull, pull!
BOTH: Yay!
!¡Gracias!Thanks!
Ooh, ooh!
I've got to hurry
to get
to the tree house
so I can get ready
for the party.
See you there!
Where do we go next?
Lake...
wall...
tree house.
We went across the lake...
we went over the wall...
so next comes the...
[ beep, click]
tree house, right!
Do you see the tree house?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the tree house!
And that's where
the big party is!
Let's go to the big party
at the tree house!
!¡Vámonos!
Oh, it's going to be big.
It's going to be fun.
It's going to be...
Hey, everybody!
What are you doing out here?
Yeah, why aren't you
up in the tree house
at the big party?
The tree house door
got stuck.
We can't get in.
Dora, if we can't get
inside the tree house
we can't have a party.
Don't worry,
we'll help you.
Come on!
[ all cheer]
Dora can do it!
She'll get us in!
Dora and Boots
to the rescue!
ALL:
Go, Dora! Go, Boots!
Vamos, Boots.
[ both grunting]
Wow! It's really
stuck tight.
But we have to
push open the door
so we can have
a party!
We need your help.
Will you help us
push open the door?
Great! Put your hands
up in the air and reach.
Now push.
BOTH:
Push, push, push, push...!
Yay!
[ all cheering]
!¡Qué bueno!
!¡Excelente!
Wow! What a big party!
Look, everybody's here!
Señor Tucán!
Baby Bluebird!
The Fiesta Trio!
The Big Red Chicken!
[ squawks]
Hooray for Dora and Boots!
OTHERS:
Hooray!
Dora, it's
a party for us!
Yeah, Boots.
I wonder why our friends
threw us a party?
ISA:
It's a thank you party.
!¡Gracias! !Gracias!
We're having this party
to say thank you
because you're always
helping us.
You helped me out of the wall.
Thank you.
Me ayudaron a buscar
mis globos. !¡Gracias!
You helped fix
my scooter.
Thank you.
You've helped
every one of us.
And that's why
we're having this fiesta.
So we can all say
thank you.
ALL:
!¡Gracias, Dora!
!¡Gracias, Boots!
And graciasto you!
We couldn't have gotten
to this party without your help.
!¡Gracias!
[ all cheering]
BOTH:
We did it!
[ music playing]
BOTH:
♪ We did it!
♪ Yay!
♪ !¡Lo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it!
♪ We crossed the lake
and went over the wall ♪
BOOTS AND DORA:
♪ We did it!
BOTH:
♪ We did it! Hooray!
DORA:
♪ We made it
to the party ♪
♪ it was
in the tree house ♪
♪ We did it!
♪ Benny the Bull
got stuck in the wall ♪
♪ Swiper took the balloons,
but we found them all ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
We had such an exciting trip
to the tree house today.
What was your favorite part
of the trip?
I liked that too.
My favorite part
was when we gave
Tico his balloons
and he floated
up into the sky.
My favorite part
was seeing
all our friends
at the party!
We couldn't have gotten
to the party without you.
Thanks for helping!
!¡Gracias!
[ click, beep]
DORA:
This is my friend the Map.
Find the Map!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Here I am!
[ laughs]
Uh-oh!
Yoo-hoo!
Over here!
[ click, beep]
You found me!
[ giggles, laughs]