Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Do you want to hear a story?
I have a new book
with a story about a prince
and I can't wait to read it.
If only my friend
Boots the monkey was here
we could all read it together.
Do you see my friend
Boots the monkey?
Where?
In the tree?
Boots!
Dora!
Hey Boots,
I have a new book.
Do you want to
read it together?
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
The book is
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find the book?
You have to say
"Backpack."
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iHola!
I have lots of books
but Dora needs you to find the
book with a prince on the cover.
[ click, beep]
Right! iExcelente!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
Delicioso.
Thanks for
getting the book.
[ grunting]
This book won't open.
No, sir.
Boots, this is a special book.
We have to say abreto open it.
Can you say abre?
Say abre.
BOTH:
iAbre!
The book is in Spanish
but I can tell you
what it says.
El principe y la bruja.
The Prince and the Witch.
Ooh...
Once upon a time
there was a happy
little prince, Prince Ramón
who lived in a faraway kingdom.
One day, the Prince
was playing with his ball.
He was trying to see
how far he could kick the ball.
He kicked the ball once
and it went very far.
He kicked the ball
the second time
and it went very,very far.
He kicked the ball a third time
and it went so far away
that it landed in...
el bosque de la bruja:
The Witch's Forest.
The prince was not supposed
to go into the Witch's Forest
but he wanted to get his ball.
My ball! iMi pelota!
You've been
a naughty principe
to come into my forest.
Now I will banish you
to the High Tower!
The Witch took the Prince
to the High Tower.
The only way to open
the tower door
was to say the magic word:
abre.
The Witch whispered
the magic word
so the Prince couldn't hear.
[ whispers]:
Abre.
And the tower door opened.
Inside the tower, the Witch and
the Prince climbed 12 steps
up to a little door
at the top of the tower.
[ whispers]:
Abre.
[ door creaks]
And the Witch put the Prince
in the little room.
Now the Prince was locked
in the tower.
Help me! iAyúdenme!
Many people
from near and far
tried to get the Prince
out of the tower
but no one knew the magic word
to open the tower door.
There was no one
to save the Prince.
I'll save the Prince.
Me, too!
Will you help save
the Prince?
Great!
[ grunting]
I can't open it!
We have to say the magic
word abreto open the book.
Say abre.
Louder!
Great! Now we can
jump in the book.
BOTH:
Whee...!
Are we in the book?
Cool!
Now we can save
the Prince.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
We have to go
to the High Tower
to save the Prince.
Let's go! Let's go!
Wait a minute, Boots.
We don't know how to get
to the High Tower.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map!
The Map, that's right!
The Map can tell us
how to get to the High Tower.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
to find out
how to get to the High Tower?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to know
how to get to the High Tower
to save the Prince.
Well, I know how to get
to the High Tower.
First, you go
through the Big Gate.
Then you go across
Crocodile Lake.
And that's how you get to the
High Tower to save the Prince.
Help me! iAyúdenme!
But remember:
Watch out for the Witch!
So you tell Dora:
Gate...
lake...
High Tower.
Say it with me.
Gate...
lake...
High Tower.
Gate...
lake...
High Tower.
Gate...
lake...
High Tower...!
How do we get to the High Tower?
Gate...
lake...
High Tower.
First, we go
through the Big Gate...
then we go
across Crocodile Lake...
and that's how we get to the
High Tower to save the Prince.
Help me!
iAyúdenme!
So first we need to go
through the Big Gate.
Do you see a gate?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's the Big Gate!
iVámonos!Let's go
save the Prince!
And remember,
watch out for the Witch.
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Gate, lake, High Tower!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ High Tower ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ High Tower ♪
ALL:
♪ High Tower! ♪
[ both laughing]
BOTH:
♪ High Tower! ♪
We made it to the gate--
the gate
to the Witch's Forest.
This gate won't open.
Open, open, open!
Let's use the magic word abre
to open the gate.
Say abre!
[ creaks]
Great! It worked.
And we didn't even
see the Witch.
You see the Witch?
Where?
The Witch!
Here comes
the Witch!
Oh no! We have to
close the gate quick.
Put your arms out
in front of you
and push the gate
closed.
Push, push, push!
Whoa...!
[ play happy tune]
BOTH:
Whew!
We made it through
the Big Gate!
And we stopped the Witch.
Thanks for helping!
Come on, Dora,
we've got to hurry.
Where do we go next?
Gate...
lake...
High Tower.
We went through the gate
so next comes...
[ click, beep]
The lake, right.
Crocodile Lake.
Do you see a lake?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
Crocodile Lake!
Come on!
Let's go save the Prince.
And remember to watch out
for the Witch!
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Gate, lake, High Tower!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ High Tower ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ High Tower ♪
ALL:
♪ High Tower! ♪
[ both laughing]
BOTH:
♪ High Tower! ♪
Dora, this looks like
the part of the Witch's Forest
where the Prince
lost his ball.
Yeah. Maybe we can
find the ball.
Then we can take it
to the Prince.
Tell us if you see
the Prince's ball.
You see the Prince's ball?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, look, Dora!
It's the Prince's ball!
We can take the ball
to the Prince!
[ rustling]
Boots, did you hear that?
Yeah, it sounds
like Swiper the fox.
If he sees the Prince's ball,
he'll swipe it for sure.
If you see Swiper the fox,
yell "Swiper."
Whoop!
You see Swiper?
Where?
There he is!
We have to say
"Swiper, no swiping."
BOTH:
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
We better put
the Prince's ball
in my Backpack
to keep it safe.
Yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum!
Delicioso.
Come on, Boots,
let's go save the Prince.
And remember to watch
out for the Witch.
BOTH:
Ooh... Crocodile Lake!
We made it
to Crocodile Lake.
But Dora, how are we
going to get across it?
I know. I'll tell
each crocodile
to close its mouth
so we can jump over them.
iCocodrilo,
cierra la boca!
iCierra...
cierra...
cierra!
Now we can jump across
the crocodiles.
But we better hurry
before the Witch comes.
I need your help.
Will you jump across
the crocodiles with us?
Great. You have to
stand up to jump.
Stand up.
Up, up, up,
up, up, up!
Now jump...
jump...
jump... jump!
Great jumping.
[ play happy tune]
We made it across
Crocodile Lake.
And we
didn't even
see
the Witch.
You see the Witch?
Where?
The Witch,
the Witch!
Here comes
DORA:
She's jumping
over the crocodiles!
Oh no!
What will we do?
We've got to get
the crocodiles
to open their mouths
so the Witch
can't jump on them.
I need your help.
You have to say
the magic word abre
so each crocodile
will open its mouth.
Say abre.
BOTH: iAbre
abre...
abre!
Whoa...!
BOOTS:
There goes
the Witch!
Thanks for helping us
stop the Witch.
iGracias, cocodrilos!
ALL:
De nada.
Come on, Boots.
Let's go save the Prince.
Where do we go next?
Gate...
lake...
High Tower.
We went through the gate
across the lake
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
High Tower, right.
Do you see
the High Tower?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the High Tower!
Come on!
Let's go save
the Prince!
And remember to watch out
for the Witch!
Help me!
iAyúdenme!
Prince Ramón!
We've come to save you!
Sí,but you need the magic word
to open the tower door.
BOTH:
We know the magic word!
What's the magic word?
Right, abre.
Say it with us!
BOTH:
iAbre!
[ creaks]
BOTH:
Yay!
We opened
the tower door!
Let's go!
Uh-oh, the steps
are missing.
The Witch must have
taken them.
We have to put them back
so we can climb the stairs.
Do you see
the missing steps?
[ click, beep]
Yeah,
there they are!
Ooh... there's
lots of steps!
Do you remember how many steps
lead up to the Prince's door?
Twelve, right!
Twelve steps.
Let's make sure there's 12.
Count with us.
BOTH:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight...
nine...
ten...
11...
12!
Now let's put the steps
in place.
Count with us.
BOTH:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight...
nine...
ten...
11...
12!
Twelve steps.
Good counting.
This door won't open.
We better use the magic word
to open the door.
What's the magic word?
Right. Louder!
[ creaks]
You saved me.
You knew the magic word.
Gracias, gracias, gracias.
De nada.
Come on, let's get
out of here.
PRINCE:
I'm so happy to be
out of the tower.
Thanks for saving
me, amigos.
The Witch was mean
to lock you in there.
But there's no Witch now.
What? You see the Witch?
Oh no! If only
I had my magic ball
then we'd be safe
from the Witch.
Magic ball?
Your ball is magic?
Sí,but I lost my ball
in the Witch's Forest.
We found your ball.
It's in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find the Prince's ball?
You better hurry!
Say "Backpack."
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iRápido! iRápido!
Dora needs you to find
the Prince's ball quick.
Remember, it has a star on it.
[ click, beep]
Right. Qué bueno.
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
Delicioso.
My magic ball!
This will keep us safe.
So, you got out of
the tower... esta bien.
I'll just put
another spell on you.
Too late, Witch.
Now I have my magic ball.
[ whispers]:
Abre.
Let me out!
I'm not letting you out!
Please! iPor favor!
Prince Ramón,
now you're stuck
with a witch
in your magic ball.
That's not so good.
But I can't let her out.
She might cast
another spell on me.
Maybe we could
let her out
if she promises to be
a good witch from now on.
Think it will work?
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Witch, we'll open the ball
and let you out
if you promise to be
a good witch from now on.
Do you promise?
I promise to be a good witch.
We need to say
the magic word
to open
the Prince's ball.
What's the magic word?
Again!
BOTH:
iAbre!
Friends?
OTHERS:
Friends! Yay!
We saved the Prince!
And the Witch won't
be mean anymore.
I'm a good witch now.
BOTH:
We did it!
[ music playing]
BOTH:
♪ We did it! ♪
Yay!
♪ iLo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went
through the gate ♪
♪ and across
the lake ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it!
Hooray! ♪
BOOTS:
♪ We saved the Prince
from the mean old Witch ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We said abre
in the tower ♪
♪ and it opened
the doors ♪
♪ The Witch made a promise
to be mean no more. ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such
a fun trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part
was when we jumped
across the crocodiles.
My favorite part
was saying abre
to open the tower doors
and save the Prince.
We couldn't have done it
without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
DORA:
This is my friend Sr. Tucán.
Find Sr. Tucán.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Oh!
Aqui voy.
Hey.
[ laughing]
[ click, beep]
Aha. Muy bien.
Me atra paste.
[ giggles, laughs]