DORA!
BOOTS!
COME ON, DORA!
♪ DO-DO-DO-DO-D-DORA ♪
ALL RIGHT!
LET'S GO!
♪ DORA, DORA,
DORA THE EXPLORER ♪
DORA!
♪ BOOTS AND SUPER-COOL
EXPLORER DORA ♪
NEED YOUR HELP,
SO GRAB YOUR BACKPACK.
♪ LET'S GO, JUMP IN ♪
VAMANOS!
♪ YOU CAN LEAD THE WAY ♪
♪ HEY, HEY! ♪
♪ DO-DO-DORA, DO-DO-D-DORA ♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING,
SWIPER, NO SWIPING! ♪
OH, MAN!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
HI, I'M DORA!
AND I'M BOOTS!
DO YOU LIKE ICE CREAM?
I LOVE ICE CREAM!
BOOTS, I REALLY, REALLY
WANT SOME ICE CREAM.
ME, TOO.
Both:
I SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM!
I SCREAM
FOR ICE CREAM!
I SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM!
I WANT STRAWBERRY!
I WANT CHOCOLATE.
Both:
MMM...!
WHAT'S YOURFAVORITE FLAVOR?
MMM, THAT SOUNDS YUMMY.
DORA, I GOT TO GET
SOME ICE CREAM.
I'VE GOT TO,
I'VE GOT TO, I'VE...
[ ice cream truck
playing jingle...]
BOOTS, DID YOU
HEAR THAT?
IT'S, IT'S...
Both:
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK!
HEY, WHERE DID
THE TRUCK GO?
DID YOU SEE WHICH WAY
THE TRUCK WENT?
THIS WAY?
THANKS!
HEY, WHERE'S
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK?
[ flute, tuba, piano and
ice cream truck play jingle]
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK IS.
I HEAR THE ICE CREAM TRUCK,
BUT I DON'T SEE IT.
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
LISTEN TO THE SOUNDS TO HELP US
FIND THE ICE CREAM TRUCK.
[ tuba plays jingle]
[ piano plays jingle]
[ ice cream truck plays jingle]
[ flute plays jingle]
WHERE'S
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK?
I KNOW, I KNOW!
IT'S BEHIND THE FLOWERS!
[ flute plays jingle]
OOPS... THAT'S NOT
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK.
[ tuba plays jingle]
[ piano plays jingle]
[ ice cream truck plays jingle]
WHERE'S
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK?
[ click, beep]
BEHIND THE TREES?
LET'S SEE.
[ ice cream truck
playing jingle...]
I HEAR IT, I HEAR IT!
THERE IT IS!
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK!
THANKS FOR
HELPING US FIND IT.
COME ON, LET'S GO!
[ playing jingle]
[ playing jingle,
engine starts]
UH-OH, I THINK
THE TRUCK IS LEAVING!
OH, NO!
[ playing jingle...]
Dora:
WAIT! STOP!
Boots:
PLEASE...!
DON'T GO!
[ plays jingle]
HI, BOOTS, HI, DORA.
GUESS WHAT?
YOU JUST MISSED
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK.
WE KNOW, AND WE
REALLY WANT ICE CREAM.
I KNOW WHERE
THE TRUCK IS GOING.
YOU DO? WHERE?
[ slurps]
I FORGOT.
OH...
THINK, BENNY.
WE HAVE TO CATCH UP
TO THAT ICE CREAM TRUCK
OR WE'LL NEVER GET
AN ICE CREAM CONE.
CONE!
CONEY ISLAND!
NOW I REMEMBER!
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK IS
GOING TO CONEY ISLAND!
CONEY ISLAND!
Both:
YAY!
THE TRUCK IS GOING
TO CONEY ISLAND.
HOW DO WE GET
TO CONEY ISLAND?
LET'S STOP AND THINK.
WHO DO WE ASK
FOR HELP
WHEN WE DON'T KNOW
WHICH WAY TO GO?
YOU COULD CHECK
THE MAP!
GOOD IDEA!
THANKS, BENNY.
YAY, THE MAP,
THE MAP!
I NEED YOUR HELP
TO CHECK THE MAP
AND FIND OUT HOW TO GET
TO CONEY ISLAND
SO WE CAN GET ICE CREAM.
YOU HAVE TO SAY "MAP."
SAY "MAP,"
SAY "MAP!"
LOUDER!
[ finger snapping,
music playing...]
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GO ♪
♪ I'M THE ONE YOU NEED TO KNOW ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GET ♪
♪ I CAN GET YOU THERE, I BET ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP! ♪
DORA AND BOOTS
WANT TO GO TO CONEY ISLAND
SO THEY CAN GET ICE CREAM.
MMM...
WELL, I KNOW HOW TO GET
TO CONEY ISLAND.
FIRST, YOU HAVE TO CLIMB
OVER STRAWBERRY MOUNTAIN.
THEN YOU CROSS CHOCOLATE LAKE.
AND THAT'S HOW YOU GET
TO CONEY ISLAND.
SO YOU TELL DORA...
MOUNTAIN...
LAKE...
CONEY ISLAND!
SAY IT WITH ME.
MOUNTAIN...
LAKE...
CONEY ISLAND!
MOUNTAIN...
LAKE...
CONEY ISLAND!
MOUNTAIN...
LAKE...
CONEY ISLAND!
HOW DO WE GET TO CONEY ISLAND?
MOUNTAIN...
LAKE...
CONEY ISLAND!
SO FIRST WE NEED TO GO
OVER STRAWBERRY MOUNTAIN.
THEN WE CROSS CHOCOLATE LAKE.
AND THAT'S HOW WE GET
TO CONEY ISLAND!
OKAY, SO FIRST
WE HAVE TO GO
OVER THE STRAWBERRY
MOUNTAIN.
NOW, WHERE IS
THE MOUNTAIN?
DO YOU SEE
WHERE?
[ click, beep]
STRAWBERRY MOUNTAIN,
STRAWBERRY MOUNTAIN!
YEAH, THERE IT IS!
AND LOOK, DORA...
THE MOUNTAIN
REALLY LOOKS
LIKE A GIANT
STRAWBERRY!
OKAY, BOOTS.
LET'S GO GET
ICE CREAM!
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
♪ MOUNTAIN, LAKE, CONEY ISLAND ♪
♪ MOUNTAIN, LAKE,
CONEY ISLAND! ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMANOS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT ♪
♪ I KNOW
THAT WE CAN DO IT ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO GET SOME ICE CREAM! ♪
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO GET SOME ICE CREAM! ♪
All:
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ GET SOME ICE CREAM! ♪
Dora:
WHOA! STRAWBERRY MOUNTAIN!
Both:
IT'S BIG!
Dora:
WE'VE GOT TO GET
OVER THE MOUNTAIN
IF WE'RE GOING TO CATCH
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK.
YEAH, WE NEED TO GET
OVER THIS MOUNTAIN FAST!
DO YOU SEE ANYONE THAT CAN GIVE
US A RIDE OVER THE MOUNTAIN?
YEAH, LOOK,
IT'S TICO THE SQUIRREL
AND HIS LITTLE YELLOW CAR.
TICO CAN GIVE US A RIDE
OVER THE MOUNTAIN!
BUT HE'S DRIVING AWAY!
TICO, TICO, WAIT!
BOOTS, TICO SPEAKS SPANISH
SO WE HAVE TO SAY "ESPERA."
HELP US SAY "ESPERA"
SO TICO WILL WAIT.
CAN YOU SAY "ESPERA?"
SAY IT WITH US!
Both:
iESPERA!
LOUDER!
Both:
iESPERA!
ONE MORE TIME!
Both:
iESPERA!
¿ESPERA?
HI, TICO.
HOLA, TICO.
HOLA.
TICO, CAN YOU
GIVE US A RIDE
TO THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE MOUNTAIN?
TICO, ¿PUEDES LLEVARNOS
AL OTRO LADO DE LA MONTAÑA?
SI, CON MUCHO GUSTO.
HE SAYS YES, HE'S GLAD TO.
Both:
SEATBELTS!
SO WE CAN BE SAFE.
FAST, TICO, FAST!
iRAPIDO, TICO,
RAPIDO!
iRAPIDO!
[ play happy tune]
WE MADE IT!
WE MADE IT
OVER STRAWBERRY MOUNTAIN!
Both:
ALL RIGHT!
THANK YOU.
WE COULDN'T HAVE DONE IT
WITHOUT YOU.
THANK YOU, TICO.
GRACIAS, TICO.
DE NADA.
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
MOUNTAIN...
LAKE...
CONEY ISLAND!
WE MADE IT OVER THE MOUNTAIN
SO NEXT WE HAVE TO FIND...
[ click, beep]
THE LAKE, RIGHT!
CHOCOLATE LAKE.
THEN WE'LL GET TO CONEY ISLAND
AND GET SOME ICE CREAM!
NOW, WHERE'S
CHOCOLATE LAKE?
DO YOU SEE THE LAKE?
WHERE?
[ click, beep]
THERE, THERE!
GRACIAS.
THANKS.
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
♪ MOUNTAIN, LAKE, CONEY ISLAND ♪
♪ MOUNTAIN, LAKE,
CONEY ISLAND! ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMANOS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT ♪
♪ I KNOW
THAT WE CAN DO IT ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO GET
SOME ICE CREAM! ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO GET SOME ICE CREAM! ♪
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO GET SOME ICE CREAM! ♪
All:
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ GET SOME ICE CREAM! ♪
[ boing]
[ slurps]
MMM...
IT'S CHOCOLATE!
CHOCOLATE?
MMM...
LOOK!
CHOCOLATE LAKE!
COME ON, BOOTS.
WE JUST HAVE TO GET
ACROSS THIS LAKE
AND WE CAN GET ICE CREAM!
Both:
I SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM!
I SCREAM
FOR ICE CREAM!
BUT HOW ARE WE GOING TO
GET ACROSS THIS LAKE?
DO YOU SEE ANYTHING WE CAN USE
TO GET ACROSS THE LAKE?
[ click, beep]
A CHOCOLATE BOAT!
IT'S PERFECT!
[ rustling]
BOOTS, DO YOU HEAR THAT?
WE BETTER WATCH OUT
FOR SWIPER,
THE SNEAKY FOX.
YEAH, SWIPER'S ALWAYS
TRYING TO SWIPE OUR STUFF.
IF WE'RE NOT CAREFUL
HE COULD SWIPE
OUR CHOCOLATE BOAT.
THEN WE'D NEVER GET
TO CONEY ISLAND!
I NEED YOUR HELP.
IF YOU SEE THE FOX,
YELL "SWIPER!"
WHAT'S THAT?
YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
BEHIND THE TREE?
I DON'T SEE HIM.
WHERE IS HE NOW?
BY THE BOAT?
OH, NO!
HE'S GOING TO SWIPE
OUR BOAT!
Both:
SWIPER, NO... SWIPING...
YOU'RE TOO LATE!
[ laughs]
YOU'LL NEVER
FIND IT NOW!
THAT SWIPER.
NOW WE'LL NEVER
GET ICE CREAM.
SURE WE WILL, BOOTS.
IF WE ALL LOOK TOGETHER
I BET WE CAN FIND
THE CHOCOLATE BOAT IN NO TIME!
Dora:
DO YOU SEE THE CHOCOLATE BOAT?
[ squawks]
THAT'S NOT THE CHOCOLATE BOAT!
IS THIS THE CHOCOLATE BOAT?
[ click, beep]
GREAT! YOU FOUND IT!
THE BOAT!
THE CHOCOLATE BOAT!
AND LOOK...
Both:
LIFE JACKETS!
SO WE CAN BE SAFE.
WE'VE GOT TO ROW
ACROSS CHOCOLATE LAKE
SO WE CAN GET ICE CREAM.
[ ice cream truck plays jingle]
COME ON, COME ON!
WE BETTER HURRY
IF WE'RE GOING TO CATCH
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK.
UGH...!
I'M TRYING, BUT THIS CHOCOLATE
IS REALLY GOOPY!
IT'S SO HARD TO ROW!
WILL YOU HELP US ROW
ACROSS CHOCOLATE LAKE?
YOU WILL?
THANKS.
PUT YOUR HANDS OUT IN FRONT
OF YOU AND START ROWING.
ROW, ROW, ROW!
ROW FASTER!
[ play happy tune]
WE MADE IT
ACROSS CHOCOLATE LAKE!
YAY!
THANK YOU
FOR HELPING US ROW.
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
MOUNTAIN...
LAKE...
CONEY ISLAND!
WE MADE IT OVER THE MOUNTAIN...
ACROSS THE LAKE...
SO NEXT COMES...
[ click, beep]
Both:
CONEY ISLAND!
YEAH!
DO YOU SEE CONEY ISLAND?
WHERE?
[ click, beep]
YEAH, THERE IT IS!
AND LOOK, BOOTS!
CONEY ISLAND'S GOT GIANT
ICE CREAM CONES ON IT!
LET'S GO!
NOW WE JUST HAVE TO FIND
THAT ICE CREAM TRUCK
AND WE CAN GET ICE CREAM.
HI, BOOTS.
ISA, YOU GOT ICE CREAM!
WHERE'S THE ICE CREAM TRUCK?
THE TRUCK IS
OVER THERE.
COME ON, LET'S GO!
Both:
THANKS, ISA!
ICE CREAM CONES COST
EIGHT COINS.
EIGHT COINS?
YEAH, ICE CREAM CONES
COST EIGHT COINS.
[ slurping...]
DORA, I DON'T HAVE
ANY COINS.
DON'T WORRY, BOOTS.
I HAVE ENOUGH COINS
IN MY BACKPACK
FOR BOTH OF US.
I NEED YOUR HELP
TO OPEN MY BACKPACK
AND COUNT OUT EIGHT COINS FOR
BOOTS AND EIGHT COINS FOR ME.
YOU HAVE TO SAY "BACKPACK."
SAY "BACKPACK,"
SAY "BACKPACK!"
I THINK YOU HAVE TO
SAY IT AGAIN.
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK,
BACKPACK ♪
♪ I'M THE BACKPACK, LOADED UP ♪
♪ WITH THINGS
AND KNICKKNACKS, TOO ♪
♪ ANYTHING THAT YOU MIGHT NEED ♪
♪ I GOT INSIDE FOR YOU ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK, YEAH! ♪
I HAVE LOTS OF STUFF.
BUT DORA AND BOOTS NEED COINS
TO GET THEIR ICE CREAM.
DO YOU SEE COINS?
[ click, beep]
GREAT!
NOW WE HAVE TO COUNT OUT
EIGHT COINS FOR BOOTS
AND EIGHT COINS FOR DORA.
LET'S COUNT EIGHT COINS
FOR BOOTS FIRST.
COUNT WITH ME!
ONE
TWO
THREE
FOUR
FIVE
SIX
SEVEN
EIGHT!
NOW COUNT OUT EIGHT COINS
FOR DORA.
ONE
TWO
THREE
FOUR
FIVE
SIX
SEVEN
EIGHT!
WOW, YOU'RE REALLY GOOD
AT COUNTING!
THANKS FOR HELPING.
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM,
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM!
iDELICIOSO!
YAY! WE'VE GOT
ENOUGH COINS
FOR ICE CREAM!
YES!
BUT WHERE'S
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK?
[ ice cream truck
playing jingle...]
DO YOU SEE
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK?
YEAH, THERE IT IS!
[ starts engine]
Both:
ALL RIGHT!
OH, NO!
THE TRUCK IS LEAVING!
I SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM!
GREAT IDEA, BOOTS!
IF WE ALL DO
THE ICE CREAM CHEER
I KNOW THE ICE CREAM TRUCK
WILL STOP.
WILL YOU DO
THE ICE CREAM CHEER WITH US
TO GET THE TRUCK TO STOP?
GREAT!
YOU HAVE TO STAND UP
TO DO THE ICE CREAM CHEER.
GET READY TO STAND UP.
STAND UP, PLEASE.
STAND UP!
UP, UP!
GET UP!
NOW JUMP UP AND DOWN
AND WAVE YOUR ARMS AND SAY
"I SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM!"
Both:
I SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM!
LOUDER!
Both:
I SCREAM FOR ICE CREAM!
IT'S WORKING!
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK
IS COMING BACK!
Both:
THE ICE CREAM TRUCK!
NOW WE CAN GET
ICE CREAM!
THANK YOU FOR HELPING.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU,
THANK YOU!
iHOLA,DORA!
iHOLA,BOOTS!
ALMOST MISSED YOU.
GO AHEAD, BOOTS.
HOW MANY COINS DO I NEED AGAIN?
EIGHT. EIGHT COINS.
ONE
TWO
THREE.
IS THIS ENOUGH?
FOUR
FIVE.
IS THIS ENOUGH?
SIX
SEVEN
EIGHT.
IS THIS ENOUGH?
SI.EIGHT COINS.
YOU CAN GET
AN ICE CREAM CONE.
WHAT FLAVOR
DID YOU WANT?
STRAWBERRY, PLEASE.
NOW HELP ME
COUNT OUT EIGHT COINS.
COUNT WITH ME.
ONE
TWO
THREE
FOUR
FIVE
SIX
SEVEN
EIGHT.
EIGHT COINS.
THANKS FOR COUNTING.
WHAT FLAVOR
DID YOU WANT, DORA?
CHOCOLATE, PLEASE.
SURE.
ENJOY!
THANK YOU.
GRACIAS.
DE NADA.
Both:
MMM... [ slurping]
WE DID IT!
Both:
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
YAY!
♪ LO HICIMOS!♪
Both:
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE CLIMBED
STRAWBERRY MOUNTAIN ♪
♪ AND CROSSED THE LAKE,
IT WAS CHOCOLATE ♪
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
Both:
♪ WE DID IT! HOORAY! ♪
♪ AT CONEY ISLAND,
WE GOT OUR CONES ♪
Both:
♪ ICE CREAM, ICE CREAM,
WE GOT ICE CREAM! ♪
♪ TICO HELPED US ALONG THE WAY ♪
♪ SWIPER TOOK OUR BOAT ♪
♪ BUT WE MADE IT, HOORAY! ♪
YAY!
WHOO!
HOORAY!
WE DID IT!
WHOO!
[ click, beep]
WE HAD SUCH A FUN TRIP TODAY.
WHAT WAS YOUR FAVORITE PART
OF THE TRIP?
I LIKED THAT, TOO.
MY FAVORITE PART
WAS WHEN I GOT
MY STRAWBERRY
ICE CREAM CONE.
[ slurps]
MMM...
MY FAVORITE PART
WAS GETTING MY CHOCOLATE
ICE CREAM CONE.
MMM...
[ slurps]
THANKS FOR HELPING.
WE COULDN'T HAVE GOTTEN
THE ICE CREAM WITHOUT YOU.
[ both slurp]
[ click, beep]
Dora:
THIS IS MY FRIEND BOOTS.
FIND BOOTS!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ click, beep]
[ giggles, laughs]