Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
And I'm Boots.
Do you like toys?
Me, too.
Boots and I are
at the toy store.
Boots is going to buy
a new ball.
What kind of ball
do you want to get, Boots?
Ooh-ooh ah-ah!
I want a super blue
bouncy, bouncy ball.
Will you help Boots find
a super blue
bouncy, bouncy ball?
Great.
Where's the blue ball?
[ click, beep]
A super blue
bouncy, bouncy ball!
You found it!
Thanks!
The super blue
bouncy, bouncy ball!
Good choice.
That ball is
super bouncy, bouncy.
How much
does it cost?
It costs 12 coins.
12 coins?
Here are all my coins.
Help me count to see
how many coins I have.
Both:
One
two
three
four
five
six
seven.
Seven coins.
Is that enough, Dora?
No, Boots.
The ball costs 12 coins.
Oh, I don't have
enough coins
to buy the super blue
bouncy, bouncy ball.
Don't worry, Boots.
I have some coins
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you open my Backpack
to find the coins for Boots?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack"!
Louder!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iHola!
I have lots of stuff.
But Dora needs you
to find the coins
so Boots can buy the super blue
bouncy, bouncy ball.
Are these the coins?
[ click, beep]
Right! iMuy bien!
You found the coins!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum...
iDelicioso!
Oh, I hope it's enough.
Come on, let's count
all the coins!
Both: One
two
three
four
five
six
seven
eight
nine
ten
12!
12 coins!
You canbuy the ball!
iQue bueno!
Yes!
Thanks for
helping me count!
Have fun!
♪ I love my ball,
my bouncy ball ♪
♪ I love my ball, ball,
ball, ball, ball! ♪
♪ This ball is bouncy,
this ball is blue ♪
♪ This ball is mine,
but you can use it, too. ♪
♪ I bounce it on my head,
I bounce it on my tail ♪
♪ I throw it up and down,
I put it everywhere ♪
♪ A bally bounce,
a bouncy ball ♪
♪ I love this ball! ♪
Come on, Dora!
Let's see how it bounces.
[ boinging...]
Boots:
Wait! Wait!
Dora:
iEspera! iEspera!
My ball! My ball!
How am I going to
find my ball?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map! The Map!
The Map!
That's right.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map to find
out where the ball is bouncing?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map"!
I think you have to
say it again.
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to find out
where the ball is bouncing.
Well, I know where the ball
is bouncing.
The ball is bouncing
to the volcano.
A volcano is a big mountain
that explodes!
Ka-boom!
To get to the volcano
first you go
across the Mucky Mud.
Then you go
over the Troll Bridge.
And that's how you get
to the volcano.
So you tell Dora:
mud...
bridge...
volcano.
Say it with me.
Mud...
bridge...
volcano.
Mud...
bridge...
volcano.
Mud...
bridge...
volcano.
Ka-boom!
Where is the ball bouncing?
Mud...
bridge...
volcano.
The ball is bouncing
to the volcano!
That's a big mountain
that explodes!
Ka-boom!
To get to the volcano
first we have to cross
the Mucky Mud...
then we go
over the Troll Bridge...
and that's how we'll get to
the volcano to get Boots' ball.
Thanks for helping.
First we need to find
the Mucky Mud.
Do you see the mud?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Come on!
My ball, my ball,
my ball!
iVámonos!
Let's go get Boots' ball!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Mud, bridge, volcano!
Mud, bridge,
volcano!
Mud, bridge, volcano!
Mud, bridge,
volcano!
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Volcano ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Volcano ♪
All:
♪ Volcano! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Volcano! ♪
Look, the Mucky Mud.
[ bubbling and gurgling]
How are we going to
get across it
without getting
all mucky?
We have to get across
so we can get to the volcano
and get my ball!
Ribbet!
Ribbet, ribbet, ribbet!
Boots:
Hey, look!
The frogs are getting
across the mud
by jumping
on the rocks.
Ribbet!
If we jump like frogs
we can jump
over the Mucky Mud
without getting
all mucky.
We need your help.
Will you help us
jump like frogs?
Great!
You have to stand up
to jump like a frog.
Get ready to stand up.
Stand up, please.
Stand up!
Up, up, up! Up, up, up!
Now crouch down
like a frog.
Crouch down.
And jump up!
Jump up like a frog!
Say "Ribbet!"
Both:
Ribbet, ribbet, ribbet, ribbet!
[ play happy tune]
Yay! We made it
across the Mucky Mud!
Good jumping!
Thanks for helping!
Where do we go next?
Mud...
bridge...
volcano.
We went across the mud...
so next we have to go to...
[ click, beep]
The bridge! Right!
The Troll Bridge.
We need to find
the Troll Bridge.
Do you see a bridge?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
iVámonos!
Let's go get Boots' ball!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Mud, bridge, volcano!
Mud, bridge,
volcano!
Mud, bridge, volcano!
Mud, bridge,
volcano!
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Volcano ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Volcano ♪
All:
♪ Volcano! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Volcano! ♪
[ rustling]
Did you hear that?
That sounds like
Swiper the fox.
That sneaky fox is always
trying to swipe our stuff.
Will you help us watch out
for Swiper the fox?
Great!
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper."
Do you see
Swiper the fox?
Where?
Over there?
I don't see him.
Me neither.
Where is he?
Behind the bush?
Both:
Here comes the fox!
I need your help to stop Swiper.
You have to say,
"Swiper, no swiping."
Say it with us.
Both:
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping.
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Thanks for helping
us stop Swiper.
Come on, Dora.
We've got to get
to the volcano
so I can get my ball.
Ooh, look, Dora, look!
It's the Troll Bridge.
Hey, Dora,
I don't see the troll.
Me neither.
Let's hurry over the bridge
before he shows up.
♪ I'm the grumpy, old troll ♪
♪ who lives
under the bridge, hey! ♪
♪ I'm the grumpy, old troll ♪
♪ who lives under the bridge--
who's there? ♪
♪ If you wanna come over,
all you have to do is this ♪
♪ All you have to do
is this... ♪
Solve my riddle!
Nobody goes
over my bridge!
But we have to go
over your bridge
so we can get to the volcano
and get my ball.
You can't go
over the bridge unless...
you solve my riddle.
Bouncy, bouncy,
bouncy, bounce.
Only two of these
things will bounce.
Can you pick the
things that bounce?
Bouncy, bouncy,
bouncy, bounce.
You hear that, Boots?
We've got to solve
the troll's riddle.
Will you help us solve
the troll's riddle?
Great!
The riddle
goes like this:
Bouncy, bouncy,
bouncy, bounce.
Only two of these
things will bounce.
Can you pick the things
that bounce?
Bouncy, bouncy,
bouncy, bounce.
We have to find the two things
that will bounce.
Which two things
will bounce?
[ click, beep, click, beep]
You're right!
The pogo stick and
the kangaroo will bounce.
[ boinging...]
Aw...!
You solved my riddle!
[ whistle tooting]
Now you can go over my bridge.
Both:
Thanks!
[ play happy tune]
We made it
over the Troll Bridge.
All right!
Where do we go next?
Mud...
bridge...
volcano.
We went across the mud...
over the bridge...
so next is...
[ click, beep]
The volcano!
We need to find
the volcano.
Do you see the volcano?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Come on,
let's go get my ball!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Mud, bridge, volcano!
Mud, bridge,
volcano!
Mud, bridge, volcano!
Mud, bridge,
volcano!
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Volcano ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Volcano ♪
All:
♪ Volcano! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Volcano! ♪
Dora, the volcano
is far away.
Yeah, we need to find
a fast way to the volcano
so we can get your ball.
Do you see anything
that can get us
to the volcano fast?
The car?
Yeah, the car!
Dora:
That's our friend,
Tico the Squirrel.
He can drive us
to the volcano in his car!
Wait, Wait!
Tico speaks Spanish.
We have to tell Tico
to wait.
In Spanish,
we say "espera."
Can you say "espera"?
Say "espera."
Say it with us.
Both:
iEspera!
Louder!
Both:
iEspera!
¿Espera?
It worked.
He's waiting!
Hi, Tico!
iHola, Tico!
iHola, Dora!
iHola, Boots!
Can you take us
to the volcano?
¿Puedes llevarnos
al volcán?
Con mucho gusto.
He says he'll be glad to.
Yes!
Cinturónes
de seguridad!
Right! Seatbelts...
So we can be safe!
Fast, Tico, fast!
iRápido,Tico, rápido!
iRápido!
Both:
Whoa...!
The volcano!
That was fast.
iRápido!
Both:
Gracias.
De nada.
Hey, look!
It's my ball!
My ball!
[ rustling]
Boots, did you
hear that?
[ rustling]
That sounds like Swiper,
the sneaky fox.
He'll try
to swipe my ball!
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper."
You see Swiper?
Whoop!
Oh, no!
Swiper...
Zoop!
You're too late!
Ha-ha-ha!
You'll never find it now!
My ball! My ball!
My ball's
in the volcano!
How are we going to
get my ball?
Listen!
[ rumbling]
Look, Boots.
The volcano is
starting to shake!
The ground is
Both:
We'restarting to shake!
It's going to explode!
[ rumbling]
[ pop]
My ball!
Dora:
It's going up, up, up!
It's coming
down, down, down!
The ball is
coming to you!
You, you!
You need to catch it!
Reach up
to catch the ball!
Reach up!
Both:
Catch it! Catch it! Catch it!
You caught it!
Hold it tight!
Now throw it
back to Boots.
Throw it hard!
Got it!
Good throw!
You threw it right to me!
I love my ball, I love my ball!
♪ I love my ball,
my bouncy ball ♪
♪ I love my ball, ball,
ball, ball, ball! ♪
♪ This ball is bouncy,
this ball is blue ♪
♪ This ball is mine,
but you can use it, too. ♪
♪ I bounce it on my head,
I bounce it on my tail ♪
♪ I throw it up and down,
I put it everywhere ♪
♪ A bally bounce,
a bouncy ball ♪
♪ I love this ball! ♪
Look, Boots.
The volcano is starting
to shake again!
The ground is starting
We'restarting to shake again!
It's going to
explode again!
[ rumbling]
[ boom]
Look, Dora!
It's raining bouncy,
bouncy balls!
But I have myball
and you helped me get it.
Both:
We did it!
[ music playing...]
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
iLo hicimos!
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We jumped over the mud
and passed the troll ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! Hooray! ♪
♪ We went for a ride
in a car with Tico ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We jumped like frogs ♪
♪ along the way ♪
♪ The volcano
spit the ball out ♪
♪ and you caught it.
Hooray! ♪
Yay!
Whoo!
Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such
a fun trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part was
jumping like a frog.
when the volcano exploded
and youcaught the ball.
We couldn't have gotten
the ball back without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
Dora:
This is my friend
Benny the bull.
Find Benny!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Hi!
[ laughs]
[ click, beep]
Yay!
Whoo-hoo!
[ giggles, laughs]