Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Do you want to hear a story?
Story, story, story, story...
story!
[ giggles]
I think Boots
wants to hear a story.
[ giggles]
What's the story,
Dora?
It's a new book
my mommy gave me.
It's called Te Amo.
Te amo?
Well, in English,
we say "I love you."
In Spanish,
we say "Te amo."
Can you say "Te amo"?
Say "Te amo".
Te amo.
Great!
The book is
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check
my Backpack
and find the book?
You have to say
"Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack!"
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iHola!
I have lots of books
but Dora needs you
to find Te Amo.
It's a blue book with
a small red heart on the cover.
Do you see it?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Right! You found Te Amo!
iMuy bien!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum...
idelicioso!
Thanks for the book.
Te Amo.
Once upon a time,
there lived a king and queen.
They were very happy...
King Popo and Queen Maria
loved each other very much.
Every day, they told
each other"Te amo."
Te amo.
But one day...
along came El Mago,
a mean magician.
[ laughter]
He saw the King and Queen
laughing, having fun
and being happy.
He didn't like it one bit!
iAbracadabra!
Oh no! He made the King
and Queen be far apart.
But King Popo and Queen Maria
loved each other so much
they walked
over the whole world
until they got back together.
BOTH:
Te amo.
When El Mago saw King Popo
and Queen Maria back together
he was very angry.
He didn't like it one bit.
I'll make sure
you're apart forever!
iAbracadabra!
KING AND QUEEN [ straining]:
Te... a...
El Mago cast a spell
on King Popo and Queen Maria
turning them into mountains.
King Popo and Queen Maria
could not move.
They couldn't speak.
They could not say"Te amo."
[ whistling]
The King and Queen
are still mountains.
The only way King Popo
and Queen Maria
will come back together is
if El Mago's spell is broken.
To break the spell,
two true friends,
two true heroes
must climb the mountains
and say "Te amo."
Oh no! The King and Queen
will be mountains forever!
Unless...
we break the spell.
We'll have to climb
the mountains and say "Te amo."
And then the spell
will be broken.
Come on, let's go
break the spell!
And bring King Popo
and Queen Maria
back together!
BOTH:
Whee...!
Awesome!
We have to go
to the Mountains
to break the spell!
Which way
are the Mountains?
Which way are
the Mountains?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us
how to get to the Mountains.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map and find
out how to get to the Mountains?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map"! Say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to get
to the Mountains
so they can break the spell
and bring King Popo and
Queen Maria back together.
Well, I know how to get
to the Mountains.
First you go across the Bridge.
Then you go over the Rocks.
And that's how you get to the
Mountains to break the spell!
But watch out for El Mago!
So you tell Dora:
Bridge...
Rocks...
Mountains.
Say it with me.
Bridge...
Rocks...
Mountains.
Bridge...
Rocks...
Mountains.
Bridge...
Rocks...
Mountains...!
How do we get to the Mountains?
Bridge...
Rocks...
Mountains.
First we cross the Bridge...
then we go over the Rocks...
and that's how we'll get to the
Mountains to break the spell.
But watch out for El Mago!
So first we have to
cross the Bridge.
Do yousee a bridge?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah,
there's the Bridge!
Come on! iVamonos!
Let's go break the spell...
And bring King Popo and
Queen Maria back together!
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Bridge, Rocks, Mountains!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Mountains ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Mountains ♪
ALL:
♪ Mountains! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Mountains! ♪
Look, there's the Bridge!
Good thing we haven't seen
El Mago yet.
Do you see El Mago?
[ both gasp]
Right! There he is!
iAbracadabra!
You'll never reach
the Mountains now!
[ laughing]
[ whistling]
Ooh! That El Mago
is a mean magician.
We have to put the Bridge
back together
so we can get to the Mountains
and break the spell.
Let's find the pieces
that fit on the Bridge.
Which piece fits here?
[ click, beep]
You found it!
Now, we have to find
the next piece.
Which piece fits here?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Which piece fits here?
[ click, beep]
This one?
Yeah! Good going!
Which piece fits here?
[ click, beep]
And which piece goes here?
You fixed
the Bridge!
iMuy bien!
Now we can go over the bridge!
[ play happy tune]
Where do we go next?
Bridge...
Rocks...
Mountains.
We went over the Bridge...
so next comes...
[ click, beep]
The Rocks, right!
Do you see the Rocks?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there are
the Rocks!
Come on! iVamonos!
Let's go
break the spell...
And bring King Popo and
Queen Maria back together!
But watch out
for El Mago!
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Bridge, Rocks, Mountains!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Mountains ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Mountains ♪
ALL:
♪ Mountains! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Mountains! ♪
Look, Dora!
It's Señor Burro!
iHola, Señor Burro!
Hola, Dora.
Hola, Boots.
You see El Mago?
iAbracadabra!
[ whistling]
BOOTS:
Uh-oh, I think El Mago
put a spell on Señor Burro.
Will you help me turn
Señor Burro
back to his old donkey self?
Great!
DORA:
Can you find
Señor Burro's ears?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, you found
his ears!
Now, can you
find his feet?
[ click, beep]
You found his feet!
What else do we
have to find?
His tail, right.
Which one
is his tail?
[ click, beep]
You pinned the tail
on the donkey!
And you broke
El Mago's spell!
iGracias!
BOTH:
De nada.
¿Los puedo ayudar?
Señor Burro is
going to help us.
Yay!
Look, Dora!
It's the Rocks!
iLas rocas!
Big!
Grande.
Little.
Pequeña.
Big!
Grande.
Little.
Pequeña.
You see El Mago?
Where?
Uh-oh! There he...
iAbracadabra!
Dora?
Dora, where
are you?!
Dora!
Don't worry, Boots,
we're coming!
Oh, this is terrible.
Do you see Boots?
Where?!
Dora!
We're coming, Boots!
I need your help to get
through this maze of rocks.
There are two paths.
The path with the rocks
that are big-- grandes.
Say "grandes."
The path with the rocks
that are little-- pequeñas.
Say "pequeñas."
Which path should
Señor Burro take?
¿Grandes?
¿Pequeñas?
[ click, beep]
¿Grandes!
¿Grandes?
¿Pequeñas?
[ click, beep]
iPequeñas!
¿Grandes?
¿Pequeñas?
[ click, beep]
iGrandes!
Oh, Dora!
I'm here, Boots.
We're together
again!
[ play happy tune]
Gracias, Señor Burro.
De nada.
Thanks for helping me
get back together with Boots.
Where do we go next?
Bridge...
Rocks...
Mountains.
We made it across the Bridge...
we went over the Rocks...
so next comes...
[ click, beep]
The Mountains, right!
Now, where are the King Popo
and Queen Maria Mountains?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there they are!
Come on, vámonos!
Let's go break the spell...
and bring King Popo and
Queen Maria back together!
Here we come!
Yay, we're coming!
Ssh...!
[ to tune of "Frere Jacques"]:
♪ La Lechuza, La Lechuza♪
♪ hace "ssh!"♪
♪ Hagamos silencio!
Hagamos silencio!♪
♪ Por favor, por favor.♪
[ whispers]:
It's La Lechuza,
the owl.
She's telling us
to be quiet.
Why do we
have to be quiet?
Oh, the owl is warning us
to be quiet
so we don't wake up
El Mago.
[ whispers]:
El Mago!
Will you help us
be real quiet
so we can sneak
past El Mago?
Great. We'll sing the song
really softly
and when we say "shh,"
you say "shh."
Okay, here we go.
[ softly]:
♪ La Lechuza, La Lechuza♪
♪ hace "ssh!," hace "ssh!"♪
♪ Hagamos silencio!
Hagamos silencio!♪
♪ Por favor, por favor.♪
[ snores, snorts]
[ snoring...]
♪ La Lechuza, La Lechuza♪
♪ hace "ssh!," hace "ssh!"♪
♪ Hagamos silencio!
Hagamos silencio!♪
♪ Por favor,
por favor.♪
[ normal voice]:
Yes!
We made it past El Mago
without waking him up.
Thanks for saying "shh."
iBuena suerte!
Gracias.
Okay, it's time
to break the spell.
We have to climb up the
mountains and say "Te amo."
Boots, you march
up that mountain.
I'll march up
this mountain.
Then we'll yell to each other,
"Te amo!"
I need your help!
Will you help me march up
to the top of the mountain?
Great. You have to
stand up to march.
Get ready to stand up.
Now stand up, please.
Now march... and march...
BOTH:
and march and march
and march and march and march!
We made it to the top
of the mountains!
Good marching!
You see El Mago?
Quick! We have to
break the spell
before he tries
to stop us.
We have to say "Te amo."
Can you say "Te amo"?
Say it with us!
BOTH:
iTe amo!
Louder!
BOTH:
iTe amo!
[ rumbling...]
[ whooshing...]
BOTH:
Whee...!
The spell is broken!
And look!
The falling rocks crushed
El Mago's magic wand!
iAy, ay, ay!I lost my magic!
Now you can't do
bad things anymore.
ALL:
Yay!
KING AND QUEEN:
iGracias! iGracias!
De nada.
You are two true heroes.
[ kisses]
BOTH:
Te amo.
We did it!
[ music playing]
BOTH:
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
♪ iLo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We crossed the bridge
and went over the rocks ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it!
Hooray! ♪
DORA:
♪ We made it to the mountains ♪
♪ and we broke the spell ♪
♪ We said "Te amo!"♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ El Mago tried to stop us ♪
♪ he was so mean ♪
♪ We didn't give up ♪
♪ and we saved
the King and Queen ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such an
exciting trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part
was when the King and
Queen got back together.
My favorite part was
when El Mago was sleeping
and the owl helped us
sing really softly.
We couldn't have broken
the spell without you.
Thanks for helping.
[ click, beep]
DORA:
This is my friend
Baby Blue Bird.
[ click, beep]
Find Baby Blue Bird!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ peeps]
[ click, beep]
[ giggles, laughs]