Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Do you like bugs?
Boots and I
are on a bug hunt.
We want to find
some creepy crawly bugs
just like the ones
in my bug book.
This is an ant.
This is a beetle.
This is a caterpillar.
Dora, I don't see any bugs.
No ants, no beetles,
no caterpillars.
Boot, bugs are
really small
but I bet I have
something in my Backpack
that will make the bugs
look bigger.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find something that will
make the bugs look bigger?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack"!
I think you have to
say it again.
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iHola!
I have lots of stuff
but Dora and Boots
need something
that will make the bugs
look bigger.
Will these
make the bugs look bigger?
Will this
[ click, beep]
It will?
Right, a magnifying glass
make things look bigger.
Good thinking.
iMuy bien!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Wow, this
magnifying glass
makes everything look
so much bigger.
Now we can find
some bugs.
Here, take a look.
Do you see any ants?
Where?
Hey, yeah, there are the ants!
Look, they're marching!
Do you see any beetles?
Where?
Ooh... they're dancing!
Do you see a caterpillar?
Yeah, look,
the fuzzy wuzzy caterpillar
is inching his whole fuzzy wuzzy
body across the ground!
Inch, inch, inch.
Good bug hunting!
[ squeaky voice]:
Bugga-bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bug!
Listen, Dora!
Bugga-bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bug!
Bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bugga-bug!
Come on, let's go see.
Bugga-bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bug!
Bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bugga-bug!
There it is again!
It's getting louder!
If you see a bug, say "Bug"!
Boots:
Yeah, there it is!
What kind of bug
is that?
Bugga-bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bug!
Bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bugga-bug!
It's a Bugga Bugga
bug, Dora.
And look, Boots.
She's carrying a cookie
on her back.
[ groaning]
Excuse me,
Bugga Bugga bug.
But I think that cookie is
too big for you to carry.
I've got to get home
with this cookie.
I've got to, I've got to!
My poor babies are hungry.
I've got to get home to feed
my little Bugga Bugga babies!
Both:
Aw...
Don't worry,
we'll help you.
Yeah, we'll help you.
You will?
Here, I'll carry
the cookie for you.
Oh, thank you.
Gracias, gracias.
De nada.
I'm Dora.
I'm Boots.
I'm Mami Bugga Bugga.
Where do you live,
Mami Bugga Bugga bug?
I live in the Big Blue Bush.
We need to find out how
to get to the Big Blue Bush
so Mami Bugga Bugga
can feed her babies.
Who do we ask for help when we
don't know which way to go?
The Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us
how to get
to the Big Blue Bush.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map and find
the way to the Big Blue Bush?
Say "Map,"
Say "Map"!
Both:
Louder!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots want to know
how to get to the Big Blue Bush
so Mami Bugga Bugga
can feed her babies.
Well, I know how to get
to the Big Blue Bush.
First you go
through the Flowery Garden.
Then you go through
the Spider Web.
And that's how you get
to the Big Blue Bush
so Mami Bugga Bugga
can feed her babies.
Babies:
Mami! Mami!
So you tell Dora:
Garden...
Web...
Big Blue Bush.
Say it with me.
Garden...
Web...
Big Blue Bush.
Garden...
Web...
Big Blue Bush.
Garden...
Web...
Big Blue Bush!
How do we get
to the Big Blue Bush?
Garden...
Web...
Big Blue Bush.
First we have to go
through the Flowery Garden...
then we go past the Spider Web.
That's how we'll get
to the Big Blue Bush
so Mami Bugga Bugga
can feed her babies.
Mami! Mami!
Thanks for helping!
First we have to find
the Flowery Garden.
Do you see a garden?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Hey, yeah, there's
the Flowery Garden.
Let's go.
iVámonos!
Let's take the cookie
to the Bugga Bugga babies.
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Garden, Web, Big Blue Bush.
Garden, Web,
Big Blue Bush.
Garden, Web, Big Blue Bush.
Garden, Web,
Big Blue Bush.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Big Blue Bush ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Big Blue Bush ♪
All:
♪ Big Blue Bush! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Big Blue Bush! ♪
Mami:
Look! There's
the Flowery Garden!
Boots:
Yeah, there's
Isa the iguana.
Come on, let's take the cookie
to the Bugga Bugga babies.
Both:
Hi, Isa.
Hi, Dora.
Hi, Boots.
Isa, this is
Mami Bugga Bugga.
We're helping her take
a cookie home
to feed her babies.
Nice to meet you,
Mami Bugga Bugga.
Nice to meet you, too.
What are you doing,
Isa?
I'm watering
my flowers.
This is my
whistling flower.
[ whistles]
This is
my dancing flower.
[ music playing]
And this is my...
bug trapper flower!
Bug trapper? Uh-oh!
[ slurps]
[ gasps]
Oh, no!
Open! Open! Open!
That won't work,
Boots!
The flower speaks
Spanish!
We have to say "abre"
to open the flower.
Quick! We have to get
Mami Bugga Bugga
out of the flower!
Will you say "abre"?
Say "abre"!
Say it with us.
All:
iAbre!
Louder!
All:
iAbre!
¿Abre?
Thanks for helping.
Whew! You saved me!
Come on!
Good luck.
[ play happy tune]
Yay! We made it past
the Flowery Garden.
Where do we go next?
Garden...
Web...
Big Blue Bush.
We made it past the garden
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Web. Right.
The Spider Web.
Now, where's
the Spider Web?
Do you see a web?
You do? Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, it's the web!
It's the Spider Web!
Mami:
Come on!
iVámonos!
Let's take
the cookie
to the Bugga Bugga
babies.
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Garden, Web, Big Blue Bush.
Garden, Web,
Big Blue Bush.
Garden, Web, Big Blue Bush.
Garden, Web,
Big Blue Bush.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Big Blue Bush ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Big Blue Bush ♪
All:
♪ Big Blue Bush! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Big Blue Bush! ♪
Bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bugga-bug!
Bugga-bugga-bugga-bugga-
bugga-bugga-bug!
Hey, Dora,
still have the cookie?
Right here.
[ rustling]
Did you hear that?
It's Swiper the fox!
He's going to try
to swipe this cookie!
Do you see Swiper?
Where?
Right behind us?
All: Swiper, no...
You're too late.
You'll never find it now.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
My cookie! My cookie!
That's for my babies!
Don't worry.
We'll find your cookie.
Will you help Mami Bugga Bugga
find her cookie?
Great!
Dora:
There are so many places
to look for the cookie.
Let's stop and think.
What shape is the cookie?
Round like a circle, right.
So let's look
for all the circles.
Is this the cookie?
[ click, beep]
You found it!
You found the cookie!
Boots:
All right!
Mami:
Good looking!
iVámonos!
Come on, let's take the cookie
to the Bugga Bugga babies.
Look!
It's the Spider Web!
Eww, spiders!
I have to go
through the web.
My babies are hungry.
We can do it.
We just have to watch out
for the spiders.
Will you help us get
through the Spider Web?
Great! Come on!
All:
Whoa...
We're in the Spider Web!
Mami:
Look! There are
four paths!
A circle path...
a triangle path...
a diamond path...
and a star path.
Dora, we need to
find a path
that doesn't have
any spiders on it.
Can we take
the triangle path?
Spiders!Spiders!
The triangle path
has spiders on it.
We need to find a path that
doesn't have any spiders one it.
Which path doesn't have
any spiders on it?
[ click, beep]
The circle path?
You're right!
The circle path
doesn't have any
spiders on it!
Thanks!
Come on, Boots!
Spiders:
Aw...
[ snap fingers]
[ play happy tune]
Whew, that was close.
Thanks to you,
we got out of the web
without running
into any spiders.
But-- eww!
I got slimed.
Me, too!
Goopy-gloppy!
Ooey-gooey.
We need your help.
Will you help us get
the sticky stuff off?
Great!
First put your hands
together...
Now slowly pull them apart
and say "Eww...!"
All:
Eww....!
Now shake your fingers.
Shake, shake, shake,
shake, shake, shake!
You did it!
You got all
the sticky stuff off.
Good shaking.
Where do we go next?
Garden...
Web...
Big Blue Bush.
We made it past the garden...
we made it past the web...
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Mami, Mami!
Big Blue Bush, right.
Now, where's
the Big Blue Bush?
Do you see a Blue Bush?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
My babies!
iMis bebés!
Come on!
iVámonos!
[ wind blowing]
Whoa...!
That's a big wind!
Mami Bugga Bugga,
the wind!
Look out!
Whoa!
That's a big wind!
Oh, no.
Mami Bugga Bugga!
We have to find her.
We've got to help her
take the cookie
home to her babies.
Will you help us find
Mami Bugga Bugga?
Great.
Listen to the sounds of the
forest to find Mami Bugga Bugga.
Slugga Slugga.
Wugga Wugga.
Bugga Bugga.
Mugga Mugga.
Slugga Slugga.
Wugga Wugga.
Bugga Bugga.
Mugga Mugga.
I know!
She's in the grass.
Wugga Wugga!
That's not Mami Bugga Bugga.
That's a Wugga Wugga Worm.
Where is Mami Bugga Bugga?
Slugga Slugga.
Bugga Bugga.
Mugga Mugga.
[ click, beep]
In the flowers?
You're right!
Mami Bugga Bugga!
We found you!
Dora! Boots!
iMis amigos!
Come on, I've got to
get home to my babies!
Good luck!
Good luck.
I'm coming,
my babies!
Mami's coming!
iMis bebés! iMis bebés!
My ten little babies.
I'm home! I'm home!
Mami, Mami, Mami,
Mami, Mami, Mami!
Mami!
We're hungry, Mami.
I know you are.
And thanks to my new friends,
look what I brought you.
All: Ooh!
Yay! Cookie!
We need to break
the cookie into ten pieces
so each Bugga Bugga baby
can have a piece.
Count with us.
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight...
nine...
ten!
Ten cookie pieces.
Now we can feed Mami's babies.
Okay, mis bebés,
line up for cookie.
Dora:
Let's help Mami Bugga Bugga
feed her babies.
Count with us.
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight...
nine...
ten!
Ten pieces of cookie
for ten Bugga Bugga babies.
All:
Mmm...!
Gracias.
[ burps]
[ all giggle]
[ both laugh]
Thank you, Dora.
[ kisses]
Boots.
And thank you.
[ kisses]
Both:
We did it!
[ music playing]
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
Yay!
♪ Lo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went past
the garden ♪
♪ and through
the Spider's Web ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it!
Hooray! ♪
♪ We helped Mami Bugga Bugga
feed her babies ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We got all sticky
in the Spider's Web ♪
♪ We found
a big cookie ♪
♪ And the babies got fed! ♪
Babies:
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such an
exciting trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part was when
we took the circle path
in the Spider Web
and got all icky.
My favorite part was
when we yelled "abre"
to get the bug trapper
flower to open.
We couldn't have taken
the cookie
to the Bugga Bugga
babies without you.
Thanks for helping.
[ click, beep]
Dora:
It's the Grumpy Old Troll.
Find the Grumpy Old Troll.
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Whoa!
Aah!
[ laughs]
Whoa!
Hey!
Whoo!
Whoa!
[ laughs]
Uh-oh!
[ click, beep]
Whoo, whoo, whoo...
I can't believe you got me!
Ah, you got me!
[ giggles, laughs]