Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Do you want to hear a story?
Great! I've got a story
about wishes in my backpack.
I wish my friend
Boots the monkey was here
so he can read the story
with us.
If you see Boots the monkey,
say "Boots."
What's that?
You see Boots?
Where?
In the tree?
I don't see him.
Boots?
Ooh, ooh, ah, ah!
Boots!
Dora!
Hey, Boots,
do you want to hear
a really great story
about wishes?
Wishes?
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find the book about wishes?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
I have lots of books.
But Dora needs to find
the book about wishes.
It has a star on the cover.
Does this book have
a star on the cover?
Does this book have a star
on the cover?
[ click, beep]
You're right.
iExcelente!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Thanks for getting
the book.
What's it called, Dora?
The Wizzle
and the Four Wishes.
Ooh, read it,
read it, read it.
"Once upon a time
there was a little Wizzle...
who lived with
his mommy and daddy.
Mommy!
Daddy!
He was very happy.
[ laughing]
One day the Wizzle found a bag
with four wishes.
The wishes were shiny
and shaped like stars.
The wishes whispered
to the Wizzle...
All:
Make a wish!
So the Wizzle took a wish
in his hands and made a wish.
Ice cream! Ice cream!
And ping!
His wish came true.
Yum, yum, yum.
The Wizzle reached into the bag
and took out another wish.
But just then, a big wind came
and blew the wish away.
My wish! My wish!
The Wizzle went chasing
after the wish
but he couldn't catch it.
Catch it, Wizzle!
Catch it!
Catch the wish!
Look, Boots, the wish
is coming to us!
Yeah! The wish is
coming out of the book!
Here comes the Wizzle!
The Wizzle's coming
out of the book, too!
Got it!
Dora and Boots:
Yay!
Hi, Wizzle.
Hi!
[ laughing]
He's really cute.
Oh!
Mommy?
Daddy?
Wizzle go home.
Don't worry, Wizzle.
You have more wishes.
We can wish you back home.
Home?
Let's count how many
more wishes you have.
Count with us.
All:
One...
two...
three!
Three wishes!
Okay, Wizzle,
take out a wish
and we'll wish you
back home.
Oh, no!
The wishes
are blowing away!
The wishes!
Wishes! Wishes!
Wishes!
[ wind blowing...]
Dora, where are
the wishes going?
I don't know.
We need to find
those wishes
to wish the Wizzle
back home
to his mommy and daddy.
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
Map! Map! Map!
The Map,
that's right.
The Map can tell us
where the wishes are going.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map to find
out where the wishes are going?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map"!
I think you have to
say it again.
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to find out
where the wishes are going
so they can catch a wish
and wish the Wizzle home.
Well, I know where
the wishes are going.
They're going
to the Wishing Well!
To get to the Wishing Well
first you have to go
past the Flowery Garden...
then you go through
the Nutty Forest...
and that's how you get
to the Wishing Well.
So you tell Dora:
Garden...
Forest...
Wishing Well!
Say it with me:
Garden...
Forest...
Wishing Well.
Garden...
Forest...
Wishing Well.
Garden...
Forest...
Wishing Well!
Where are the wishes going?
Garden...
Forest...
Wishing Well.
So first the wishes will go
past the Flowery Garden...
then go through
the Nutty Forest...
and that's how they'll get
to the Wishing Well.
Thanks for helping.
Wizzle go home?
Don't worry, Wizzle.
We'll get you home.
Right, Dora?
Right!
Home, home, home!
First we need to go
to the Flowery Garden.
Do you see
the Flowery Garden?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
iVamonos!
Let's go!
Say it with us.
All:
Garden, Forest, Wishing Well.
Garden, Forest,
Wishing Well.
Garden, Forest, Wishing Well.
Garden, Forest,
Wishing Well.
♪ Come on, vamonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know that we can do it ♪
Where are we going?
Wishing Well.
Both:
Where are we going?
Wishing Well.
All:
Wishing Well!
[ all laughing]
All:
Wishing Well!
Look! We made it
to the Flowery Garden.
But where are
the wishes?
Do you see
any wishes?
Yeah, there
they are!
And look--
one got stuck.
Boots:
It's right next to
Isa the Iguana.
[ whispers]:
Make a wish! Make a wish!
I wish my sunflower
would be big.
All:
Isa! Isa!
We need that wish!
Wizzlego home!
Hi, Dora.
Hi, Boots.
Isa, we need that wish
to wish the Wizzle home.
I'm sorry but I already
made a wish.
What did you
wish for, Isa?
I wished that my
little sunflower
would grow really,
really big...
[ rumbling]
This sunflower
is toobig.
We need to get down
off this sunflower
so we can get
the Wizzle home.
Home, home, home!
But how are we
going to get down?
Let's stop and think.
I know!
We can slide
down the flower.
We need your help to hug
the flower and slide down.
Will you help us hug and slide?
Great!
You have to stand up
to help us hug and
slide down the flower.
Get ready to stand up.
Stand up, please.
Stand up.
Up, up, up!
Now, wrap your arms
around you
like you're
giving a hug.
Hug, hug!
Now bend your knees
like you're going to
slide down.
Start sliding.
Slide slowly...
Others:
Whee... yay...
all the way down
to the ground!
Thanks for hugging
and sliding with us.
That was a fun ride.
Good luck
getting your wish.
[ play happy tune]
We made it through
the Flowery Garden.
Wizzle get
wish now?
Don't worry, Wizzle.
We had three wishes.
Isa made one wish
so how many wishes
do we have left?
Two, right.
We have two wishes left.
We're going to keep going
until we find a wish
and wish you home.
Both:
Yay!
Where do we go next?
Garden...
Forest...
Wishing Well.
We made it past the Garden.
So now we have to go
through the...
[ click, beep]
Forest!
Right, the Nutty Forest.
Now where's
the Nutty Forest?
Do you see a Forest?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Let's go!
Let's find a wish
and wish the Wizzle
back home.
Home, home, home!
Come on, say it with us.
All:
Garden, Forest, Wishing Well.
Garden, Forest,
Wishing Well.
Garden, Forest, Wishing Well.
Garden, Forest,
Wishing Well.
♪ Come on, vamonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know that we can do it ♪
Where are we going?
Wishing Well.
Both:
Where are we going?
Wishing Well.
All:
Wishing Well!
[ all laughing]
All:
Wishing Well!
We made it
to the Nutty Forest.
But where are
the wishes?
Where are the wishes?
Do you see a wish?
You do?
[ click, beep]
Boots:
Yeah, there's one!
It got stuck
on a nutty bush.
Dora:
Look, Tico the Squirrel
got the wish.
All:
Tico! We need that wish!
[ whispers]:
Quiero muchas nueces.
Boots:
I think Tico
made a wish.
Dora:
I think he wished
for nuts.
Boots:
Lots and lots of nuts.
Both:
Squirrels love nuts.
iAy!
Dora:
Oh, no!
We've got to save Tico
from the falling nuts!
Boots:
Here comes another nut!
Tico, watch out!
iAy!
Dora:
Boots, Tico speaks Spanish.
We have to say "cuidado!"
Can you say "cuidado?"
Say "cuidado!"
Say it with us.
Both:
iCuidado!
Dora:
It worked!
Boots:
Here comes another nut.
Dora:
Say "cuidado!"
Both:
iCuidado!
Boots:
All right!
Wizzle:
Nut!
Dora and Boots:
iCuidado!
Dora:
Louder!
Both:
iCuidado!
Yay!
Dora:
Great.
You helped us save Tico
from the nuts.
Tico! Are you okay?
Tico! ¿Estás bien?
Si, estoy bien.
He said yes,
he's fine.
Gracias.
Both:
iDe nada!
[ play happy tune]
We made it through
the Nutty Forest!
Are there
any wishes left?
There were
three wishes.
Isa made a wish.
Tico made a wish.
How many wishes
are left?
One, right.
There's only
one wish left.
Both:
Ooh!
Where do we go to find
the last wish, Dora?
Garden...
Forest...
Wishing Well.
We made it past the Garden...
through the Forest...
so next comes...
[ click, beep]
Both:
The Wishing Well!
Do you see
the Wishing Well?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Come on, Boots, let's go
find the last wish.
And wish
the Wizzle home!
Home, home, home!
Wizzle:
Wishing Well!
Dora:
Yeah, there's
the Wishing Well.
But where's the wish?
Do you see the wish?
[ click, beep]
Boots:
Yeah, there it is!
Wish, wish, wish!
Come on, Dora!
Dora, this muddy hill
is really hard to climb.
Do you see anything
we can use
to climb up
to the Wishing Well?
Right!
Look, Boots, we can climb
those stepping stones.
But look, some of the stones
are missing.
Do you see
the missing stones?
Right! There they are!
Let's count the holes
so we know how many
stones we need.
All:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six!
We need six stones.
Now let's count the stones.
All:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six!
Six stones.
Great!
Now let's put them
back in place.
Count with us.
All:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six!
Cool!
We did it!
Wizzle: Yay!
Thanks for helping us count.
Now we can climb
up to the Wishing Well
get the wish and...
Both:
Wish the Wizzle home!
Home!
Oh, no!
The wish--
it's blowing away!
Wish, wish, wish!
Dora, do something!
Got it!
Both:
Yay, Dora!
Now all we need
is the Wizzle book.
Quick, let's get
the book out of
my Backpack
so we can wish
the Wizzle home.
You have to say
"Backpack."
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
Dora needs the book
with a star on the cover.
Do you see it?
Where?
[ click, beep]
You're good at this!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Thanks for the book.
Now we can wish
the Wizzle back home!
[ rustling]
Did you hear that?
Yeah!
We better watch out
for Swiper the fox.
Swiper will try to swipe
the last wish.
Then the Wizzle
won't be able to go home
to his mommy and daddy.
No Mommy? No Daddy?
Don't worry, Wizzle.
We'll stop Swiper.
We need your help
to stop Swiper.
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
What's that?
You see Swiper?
Where?
Right behind us?
Help us stop Swiper.
You have to say
"Swiper, no swiping!"
Say it with us.
All:
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
You helped us
stop Swiper.
All:
Yay!
[ gasps]
The wish is
getting away!
Ooh, ooh, ooh!
Wish, wish, wish!
The wish is
going to you!
It's up to you!
You have to catch
the wish.
Reach out
to catch it.
Reach out to catch it!
Wizzle:
Catch it! Catch it!
You got it!
You caught
the wish!
So you have to wish
the Wizzle home.
Say "I wish the Wizzle home."
Say it with us.
I wish the Wizzle home!I wish the Wizzle home!
Louder!
Again!
I wish the Wizzle home!I wish the Wizzle home!
Mommy!
Daddy!
Whee!
Mommy!
Daddy!
He's back with
his mommy and daddy.
You did it!
You wished
the Wizzle home.
He looks happy.
Good-bye, Wizzle.
We love you.
Both:
We did it!
[ music playing...]
Both:
♪ We did it ♪
♪ We did it, yay! ♪
♪ Lo hicimos♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went
past the Garden ♪
♪ and through
the Forest ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! Hooray! ♪
♪ We caught a wish
at the Wishing Well ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it ♪
♪ We did it ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We saved Tico from the nuts
along the way ♪
♪ We wished
the Wizzle home ♪
♪ He was happy--
hooray! ♪
Yay!
Whoo!
Hooray!
We did it.
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such
a fun trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part was
saving Tico from the nuts.
My favorite part
was seeing the Wizzle
home with his mommy
and daddy.
We couldn't have done it
without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
Dora:
This is my friend Sr. Tucán.
Find Sr. Tucán.
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department Of Education
and Nickelodeon
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ laughs]
Oh!
iAqui voy!
Hey!
Hoo-hoo!
Ay-yi-yi!
[ laughs]
[ click, beep]
Muy bien.
Me atra paste.
[ giggles, laughs]