Dora!
Boots!
r Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
rand NICKELODEON]
Hola,I'm Dora.
This is my Backpack.
Do you have a backpack?
Backpack is my friend.
[ giggling]
She goes with me
wherever I go.
I remember when I
first got Backpack.
One day, I was looking
for my library books.
Where are my library books?
Do you see any books?
[ click, beep]
My library books!
I hope I have all eight books.
Count with me.
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight.
Eight books.
Good counting.
I have to take these books
back to the library
before it closes
or they'll be late.
Ooh, they're heavy.
Mamá:
Dora!
We have a surprise for you.
You do? What?
It's something
that will help you
carry your books
to the library.
iPresentamos a backpack!
[ gasps]
A backpack!
Just what
I need!
This is a
very special
backpack, Dora.
iContiene de todo!
Anything you need
she's got inside
for you.
I love it!
Thank you, Mamá.
Thank you, Papi.
Gracias.
De nada.
Hola,Dora!
Hola!
I can carry lots of stuff,
mi amiga.
Backpack speaks Spanish
and English just like me.
I can carry los libros.
[ parents chuckle]
Yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
[ giggles]
[ parents laugh]
Backpack, I'm going to
take you with me wherever I go.
iPerfecto!
iTe queda
muy bien!
Backpack, we've got to hurry
if we're going to get to
the library before it closes.
iVámonos!
Let's go!
Papi:
Remember, Dora,
anything you need
Backpack has inside
for you.
I'll remember.
[ Boots crying]
Do you hear
someone crying?
[ crying continues]
Oh, no.
I think that's
my friend Boots.
[ crying...]
Boots, what's the matter?
I fell and
got a boo-boo.
Aw, Boots...
We need to put something
on that boo-boo
to make it feel better.
Where can I find something
to put on Boots' boo-boo?
Backpack!
Hey, yeah, I can check
my new Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check
my Backpack
and find something to
put on Boots' boo-boo?
You have to say "Backpack."
[ sniffling]:
Say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
This is the first time Dora
has ever asked me for anything.
Dora needs to find something
to put on Boots' boo-boo.
What can we use to put
on Boots' boo-boo?
[ click, beep]
A soft bandage, sí.
This will make
the boo-boo feel better.
Good thinking.
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
Delicioso!
[ kisses]
[ sniffles]
Thanks, Dora.
My boo-boo
feels better.
Thanks, Backpack.
Aw... de nada.
Boots, I have to
bring my books
back to the library
before it closes.
I can help you.
Great! We've got to
get there fast.
What's the quickest way
to the library?
I don't know.
Let's stop and think.
Who can we ask
for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
Map!
Both:
A map!
There's a map
in my new Backpack.
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map! ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find the quickest way
to the library?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map," say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
This is the first time
that Dora has ever asked me
for directions.
I'm so proud.
Dora needs to find the
quickest way to the library
so she can return her books.
Well, I know the quickest way
to the library.
First you cross
the Troll Bridge.
Then you climb
over the Big Rock.
And that's how you get
to the library.
So you tell Dora:
Bridge...
rock...
library.
Say it with me.
Bridge...
rock...
library.
Bridge...
rock...
library.
Bridge...
rock...
library...!
How do we get to the library?
Bridge...
rock...
library.
First we cross the Troll Bridge.
Then we climb over the Big Rock.
And that's how we'll get
to the library.
Thanks for helping.
So first we have to find
the Troll Bridge.
Do you see a bridge?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
There's the Troll Bridge!
Let's go return my books.
Come on, say it with us.
Bridge, rock, library.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Library ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Library ♪
All:
♪ Library! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Library! ♪
Dora, it looks like
it's going to rain.
I don't see
any rain clouds.
I need your help.
If you see a rain cloud,
yell "rain cloud."
Do you see a rain cloud?
Where?
Yeah, here comes
a rain cloud.
We need something
to keep us dry.
Where can we find something
to keep us dry?
Look in
the Backpack
look in
the Backpack!
Great idea!
I need your help.
Will you check
my Backpack
for something that
will keep us dry?
Quick!
Say "Backpack."
Oh, no!
Dora and Boots
are going to get wet!
Will this keep them dry?
Will thiskeep them dry?
[ click, beep]
Right!
The umbrella will keep them dry!
iMuy bien!
Good thinking!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Gracias,Backpack.
[ disappointed]:
Oh...
[ rain cloud sighs]
Both:
Yay!
Thanks to you,
we didn't get wet.
Yum! iDelicioso!
[ both laugh]
Dora:
Look, it's
the Troll Bridge.
I see the bridge,
but I don't see the troll.
Come on!
♪ I'm the Grumpy Old Troll ♪
♪ who lives under the bridge ♪
♪ Hey! I'm
the Grumpy Old Troll ♪
♪ who lives under the bridge ♪
♪ Who's there? ♪
♪ If you want to come over ♪
♪ all you have to do is this ♪
♪ All you have to do
is this... ♪
Solve my riddle!
You can't go over my bridge
unless you solve my riddle!
They'll never solve it!
Ha-ha-ha!
Here is one of my
hardest quizzers
To cut through the net,
use a pair of...
You hear that, Boots?
We've got to solve
the Troll's riddle.
rWill you help us solve
the Troll's riddle?
Great!
The riddle goes like this.
"Here is one
of my hardest QUIZZERS.
To cut through the net,
use a pair of..."
Both: Scissors!
Oh! You got it!
Scissors!
We need scissors!
Dora, where are we
going to find
a pair of scissors?
They'll never find scissors!
They'll neverfind scissors!
Do you know where we can
find some scissors?
In my Backpack!
Say "Backpack"!
iRápido!
Dora needs safety scissors
to cut through the Troll's net.
Can you find
the safety scissors?
[ click, beep]
You found them!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Thanks for
the safety scissors.
I need your help to cut
our way through this net.
Can you make scissors
with your fingers?
Great! Make a scissors
with your fingers and...
snip, snip, snip!
Snip, snip, snip,
Good snipping!
Yes!
Aw, they cut
through the net!
But one day
I'll stump them.
I'll come up
with a Super Riddle.
They'll never get it,
they'll never get it,
they'll never get it!
iAdiós,Señor Troll!
[ play happy tune]
Where do we go
next, Dora?
Bridge...
rock...
library.
We made it past the bridge.
So next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Rock, right!
Now, where's
the Big Rock?
Do you see the rock?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
There's the Big Rock!
iVámonos!
Let's go return my books
to library.
Come on, say it with us.
Bridge, rock, library.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Library ♪r
♪ Library ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Library ♪
All:
♪ Library! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Library! ♪
Dora! Icky sticky sand!
I'm stuck!
It's okay, Boots.
I can pull you out!
I just need a rope!
Get a rope!
Hurry!
Do you know
where I can find a rope?
In my Backpack! Right!
Say "Backpack"!
Quick! Can you find the rope?
[ click, beep]
There it is! Right!
Yum, yum, yum...
iDelicioso!
Thanks for the rope.
Here it comes, Boots!
I got it!
Boots!
Dora!
You saved me!
Gracias,Backpack.
iDe nada!
Come on!
Watch your step!
Both:
It's, it's, it's...
The Big Rock!
The Big Rock
sure is big.
We've got to get
over this Big Rock
so we can return my books
to the library.
How?
Watch me!
I'm going to throw
the rope over that branch
so we can climb up.
Awesome!
Dora!
The rope!
It's starting
to rip!
We need
some sticky tape
to stick the rope
back together!
Hurry! Hurry!
Where can we get
some sticky tape?
In the Backpack!
Say "Backpack"!
iRápido!
Dora needs sticky tape
or we're all going to fall!
Find the sticky tape!
[ click, beep]
You found it!
Got it!
Thanks!
Now we have to
slide down the rock.
Will you help us
slide down the rock?
We have to hug our knees
to slide down the rock.
Hug your knees!
Both:
Whee...!
[ play happy tune]
We made it
over the Big Rock!
All right!
Where do we go next?
Bridge...
rock...
library.
We crossed the bridge...
we climbed up the rock...
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
library, right!
Do you see the library?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Let's go!
[ rustling]
Oh, no!
Did you hear that?
That sounds like
Swiper the fox.
That sneaky fox is
always trying
to swipe our stuff.
Will you keep a lookout
for Swiper the fox?
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper."
[ gasps]
Do you see
Swiper the fox?
Where?
Right behind us?
Both: Swiper, no...
Hey!
Both: ...swiping.
You're too late!
Ha-ha-ha!
Whoa...!
You'll never find
your Backpack now!
Oh, no!
Backpack!
Both:
Quack, quack!
Backpack!
Baa, baa!
Ack, ack!
This is horrible.
We have to find her
right away.
Quack, quack!
Backpack!
Baa, baa!
Ack, ack!
I need your help to listen
to the sounds
and help me find Backpack.
Baa, baa!
Quack, quack!
Backpack!
Ack, ack!
Baa, baa!
Quack, quack!
Backpack!
Ack, ack!
I know, I know!
She's behind the bush!
Baa, baa!
The sheep goes "baa, baa,"
not Backpack.
Quack, quack!
Backpack!
Ack, ack!
Where's Backpack?
[ click, beep]
In the tree?
Yes! You found
Backpack!
Both: Backpack!
Mis amigos,you saved me!
iGracias,Dora!
iGracias,Boots!
[ bell dinging]
The library bell!
That means the library
is going to close soon!
Come on! Let's go
return my books!
iRápido!
[ door creaking]
Oh, no! The library door!
It's closing!
Open! Open!
iEn español, por favor!
The door speaks Spanish.
I know Spanish!
To get the door open,
we have to say "abre."
Can you say "abre"?
Say "abre"!
Say it with us.
Both:
iAbre!
It opened!
Thanks for saying "abre."
Hola,Dora.
You're just in time.
I was about to close.
Give her
the books, Dora!
Give her the books!
You have the books,
don't you?
Do you remember
where I put the books?
Say "Backpack."
I carried the books
the whole way!
Can you find the books?
[ click, beep]
Right! There they are!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Do you have
all eight books, Dora?
Count with me.
Backpack, Boots and Dora:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight!
Eight books!
And they're all back on time.
Bien hecho,Dora.
Dora, Boots, Door:
iAbre!
All:
We did it!
[ music playing]
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
♪ iLo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We crossed
the Troll Bridge ♪
♪ and climbed up
the Big Rock ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Hooray! ♪
♪ We returned
the books ♪
♪ to the library ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ I got a new backpack ♪
♪ from my parents today ♪
♪ I had everything they needed ♪
♪ She helped us, hooray! ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
iLo hicimos!
Whoo!
[ play happy tune]
[ click, beep]
We had such an exciting trip
to the library today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part
was when we listened
to the sounds
and found Backpack
in the tree.
My favorite part
was putting the sticky
tape on the rope.
We couldn't have brought
the books back to the library
without you.
And you, Backpack.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
Dora:
Hey, look, it's Boots.
Find Boots!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Uh-oh.
[ click, beep]
[ laughs]
[ giggles, laughs]