Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way
♪ Hey, hey!
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Do you like riddles?
Me, too!
I love riddles!
Ooh-ooh, ah-ah!
Riddles are
silly questions.
I have a silly
riddle for you.
Listen carefully:
What's furry,
swings from tree to tree
and goes
"ooh-ooh, ah-ah?"
Ooh, that's
a good riddle.
What's furry, swings
from tree to tree
and goes
"ooh-ooh, ah-ah?"
[ click, beep]
A monkey. Right!
Like me.
Right, Boots!
Ooh-ooh, ah-ah!
[ both laugh]
Dora, Dora,
tell me another riddle!
I love riddles.
Okay, Boots,
here's another riddle.
Listen carefully:
What's yellow
on the outside
white on the inside
and you can peel it?
Ooh, that's a good
riddle. Hmm...
Do youknow what's
yellow on the outside
white on the inside
and you can peel it?
[ click, beep]
Oh yeah, a banana!
Right!
[ both laugh]
That's a good
riddle, Dora.
I love riddles!
Call me...
♪ Mr. Riddles.
[ playing fanfare...]
Riddle contest!
There's a riddle contest
to see who can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
ALL:
Today at the Tall Mountain.
A riddle contest!
To see who can solve
the Silliest Riddle of all.
I love riddles.
I bet we can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
Can we go
to the Tall Mountain?
Can we? Can we?
Sure, Boots...
I mean Mr. Riddles.
Yay! Let's go
to the Tall Mountain
so we can solve
the Silliest Riddle!
But Boots, we don't know
how to get to the Tall Mountain.
Oh no!
Here's another riddle:
Who can we ask for help when
we don't know which way to go?
The Map!
The Map, that's right!
The Map can tell us how
to get to the Tall Mountain
so we can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
to find out how to get
to the Tall Mountain?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map"! Say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know
♪ I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet
♪ I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map!
Dora and Boots need to get
to the Tall Mountain
so they can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
Well, I know how to get
to the Tall Mountain.
First, you go
over the Troll Bridge...
then you go through
the Knock Knock Door...
and that's how you get
to the Tall Mountain.
So you tell Dora:
Bridge...
Door...
Tall Mountain.
Say it with me.
Bridge...
Door...
Tall Mountain.
Bridge...
Door...
Tall Mountain.
Bridge...
Door...
Tall Mountain!
How do we get
to the Tall Mountain?
Bridge...
Door...
Tall Mountain.
First, we go over
the Troll Bridge.
Then we go through
the Knock Knock Door.
And that's
how we'll get
to the
Tall Mountain
so we can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
Thanks for helping.
So first we need to go
over the Troll Bridge.
Do you see a bridge?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Oh yeah,
there's the Troll Bridge!
iVámonos!Let's go
to the Tall Mountain!
So we can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Bridge, Door,
Tall Mountain!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tall Mountain
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tall Mountain
ALL:
♪ Tall Mountain!
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Tall Mountain!
Dora, Dora, tell me a riddle,
tell me a riddle.
I love riddles!
Okay, Mr. Riddles.
Listen carefully:
What goes
"hee-haw, hee-haw"
has a tail that swishes
and has four legs?
Ooh,
that's a good riddle.
Do you know what goes
"hee-haw, hee-haw"
has a tail
that swishes
and four legs?
Hee-haw, hee-haw.
[ click, beep]
A donkey. Right!
Hee-haw, hee-haw!
Look,
there's a donkey!
That's Señor Burro.
Hola, Dora,
hola, Boots.
We're going to
the Tall Mountain
so we can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
¿Nos puede dar un paseíto?
Con mucho gusto.
Señor Burro will give us
a ride, Boots.
Come on, we better get
to the Tall Mountain rápido.
Fast! iRápido!
iRápido!
Dora, help!
Boots, Señor Burro
speaks Spanish.
How do I tell him
to wait?
I need your help.
To get Señor Burro to wait,
we need to say espere.
Can you say espere?
Now tell Señor Burro
espere.
iEspere!
Louder!
¿Espere?
Great! We got
Señor Burro to wait.
Gracias, Señor Burro.
iVámonos!
DORA:
Look, the Troll Bridge.
♪ I'm the Grumpy Old Troll
♪ who lives under the bridge
♪ Hey! I'm
the Grumpy Old Troll ♪
♪ who lives under the bridge
♪ Who's there?
♪ If you want to come over
♪ all you have to do is this
♪ All you have to do
is this... ♪
Solve my riddle!
No one goes
over my bridge
unless they
solve my riddle.
I love riddles!
I bet we can solve
your riddle, Mr. Troll.
We'll see.
Listen carefully:
What goes
"hee-haw, hee-haw"
has two tails
and eight legs?
[ chuckles]
Hmm... what goes
"hee-haw, hee-haw"
has two tails,
and eight legs?
Ooh, that's
a hard riddle.
Let's stop and think.
First we have to figure out
what goes "hee-haw, hee-haw."
We know Señor Burro
goes "hee-haw, hee-haw"
but he only has
one tail.
Who has
another tail?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, I have
a tail, too!
Señor Burro goes
"hee-haw, hee-haw"
and together
we have two tails.
But the riddle says
we need eight legs.
How many legs
do we have altogether?
Let's count
all your legs.
Count with me.
BOTH:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six.
Six legs.
We only have six legs
but the riddle says
eight legs.
How many more legs
do we need?
Two more, right!
Who else has two legs?
[ click, beep]
Me!
Let's count
all our legs.
Count with me.
BOTH:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight.
Altogether we have
eight legs!
So what goes "hee-haw, hee-haw,"
has two tails and eight legs?
We do!
All of us together!
A donkey, a monkey,
and Dora!
I don't believe it!
You solved me riddle!
Now you can go
over my bridge.
I'll stump you all
next time for sure.
That's one smart monkey.
Call me...
♪ Mr. Riddles.
[ play happy tune]
We made it
over the Troll Bridge!
Thanks for helping!
[ giggling]
Thanks, Señor Burro.
Gracias.
Buena suerte.
Where do we go next?
Bridge...
Door...
Tall Mountain.
We went over the Bridge...
so next we come to...
[ click, beep]
The Door, right.
The Knock Knock Door.
Do you see a door?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the Knock Knock Door!
iVámonos!Let's go
to the Tall Mountain!
So we can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Bridge, Door,
Tall Mountain!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tall Mountain
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Tall Mountain
ALL:
♪ Tall Mountain!
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Tall Mountain!
Dora, Dora, tell me a riddle,
tell me a riddle.
I love riddles.
Okay, Mr. Riddles.
Listen carefully:
What goes up when
the rain comes down?
Ooh, that's a good riddle.
Do you know what goes up
when the rain comes down?
[ click, beep]
An umbrella, right.
Uh-oh, Boots.
I think we need an
umbrella, and quick!
I might have one
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find an umbrella?
You have to say "Backpack."
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah!
iHola!
Dora needs you to find
an umbrella quick!
Do you see the umbrella?
[ click, beep]
Right! There it is.
Excelente.
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
iDelicioso!
We got
this umbrella up
just before the rain
came down.
BOTH:
Yay!
Aw...!
Hey Boots, I have
another riddle.
What goes...
[ rustling]
...is sneaky
and is
always trying
to swipe
our stuff?
[ rustling]
BOTH:
Swiper the fox!
That sneaky fox
will try to
swipe our umbrella.
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
What's that?
You see Swiper?
Yeah, there he is!
Help us stop Swiper.
Say "Swiper, no swiping."
BOTH:
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh man!
Oh man...!
Thanks for helping
us stop Swiper.
And the rain cloud's
gone.
BACKPACK:
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
iDelicioso!
Look, Dora!
It's the Knock Knock Door.
The Knock Knock Door
won't open.
But we have to go
through the Knock Knock Door
to get to the Tall Mountain.
DOOR:
Knock, knock!
Who's there?
Boo!
Boo who?
Boo hoo? Boo-hoo!
Oh, don't cry.
It's just a joke.
[ laughs]
[ both laugh]
Boo who! That sounds
like we're crying.
That's funny.
Yeah. That's a funny
Knock Knock joke.
Knock, knock.
BOTH:
Who's there?
Chooch.
BOTH:
Chooch who?
Chooch-who!
Chugga-chugga
chooch-who!
You're a train!
[ laughs]
[ all laugh]
Your Knock Knock jokes
are so silly.
Knock Knock Door,
we need to go...
Dora, how are we
going to get
through this
Knock Knock Door?
I have an idea!
I need your help.
Will you help me knock
on the Knock Knock Door?
On the count of three,
let's knock.
One...
two...
three!
BOTH:
Knock, knock!
Who's there?
Orange.
Orange who?
Orange you going to
unlock the door
and let us through?
Orange you going to unlock
the door and let us through?!
[ laughing]
Oh, that's a good one!
Come on through.
We like playing
Knock Knock jokes with you
but we have to go
to the Tall Mountain...
So we can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
You'll be good at that.
I love riddles!
Call me
♪ Mr. Riddles.
Good luck, Mr. Riddles.
[ play happy tune]
We made it through
the Knock Knock Door!
BOTH:
Yay!
Where do we go next?
Bridge...
Door...
Tall Mountain.
We went over the Bridge...
through the Door...
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Tall Mountain, right.
Do you see
the Tall Mountain?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the Tall Mountain!
Come on, let's go solve
the Silliest Riddle.
[ fanfare plays]
ALL:
Riddle contest!
Let's see who can solve
the Silliest Riddle.
Here's the riddle.
Listen carefully:
Who can jump
higher than the
Tall Mountain?
Who can jump higher
than the Tall Mountain?
Ooh, that's a hard riddle.
I can't jump higher
than the Tall Mountain.
No puedo saltar
más alto que la montaña.
I can't jump higher than
the Tall Mountain. Bawk!
Dora and Boots
it's up to you to solve
the Silliest Riddle.
Who can jump higher
than the Tall Mountain?
That's a hard riddle.
Let's stop and think.
To jump higher
than the Tall Mountain
first you have to figure out
how high a mountain can jump.
Hmm... how high
can a mountain jump?
Can a mountain jump?
[ Mountain grunting]
No, a mountain can't jump.
But wecan all jump.
So we can all
jump higher
than the Tall Mountain
because...
BOTH:
Mountains can't jump!
Dora, we solved
the Silliest Riddle!
TRIO:
Time's up!
Who can jump higher
than the Tall Mountain?
BOOTS:
We know, we know!
Everyone can
jump higher
than the Tall Mountain
because...
BOTH:
Mountains can't jump!
Right!
[ laughs]
Let's all jump higher
than the Tall Mountain.
Will you help us jump?
Great.
You have to stand up to jump.
Stand up, please.
Stand up.
Up, up, up!
Now jump!
Jump higher.
Jump really high.
Good jumping.
See, everyone
can jump higher
than the Tall Mountain
because...
BOTH:
Mountains can't jump!
[ play happy tune]
ALL: You solved
the Silliest Riddle!
BOTH:
Yay!
We solved
the Silliest Riddle.
I love riddles.
Call me...
♪ Mr. Riddles.
BOTH:
We did it!
[ music playing]
BOTH:
♪ We did it!
♪ We did it! ♪ Yay!
♪ iLo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it!
♪ We went
over the bridge ♪
♪ and through
the door, yeah ♪
♪ We did it!
♪ We did it! Hooray!
♪ We solved the riddle
at the Tall Mountain, yeah ♪
♪ We did it!
♪ We heard
Knock Knock jokes ♪
♪ at the
Knock Knock Door ♪
♪ We love riddles,
let's find some more ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such a
silly trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part
was the Knock Knock jokes
at the Knock Knock Door.
My favorite part
was when we solved
the Silliest Riddle
by jumping higher
than the Tall Mountain.
We couldn't have done it
without you.
Thanks for helping.
[ click, beep]
DORA:
It's the Grumpy Old Troll!
Find the Grumpy Old Troll!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Whoa!
Aah! [ laughs]
Hey!
Whoa!
[ laughs]
Uh-oh!
[ click, beep]
Oh, no!
I can't believe
you got me! Oh, boy...
[ giggles, laughs]