Boots:
DORA!
Dora: BOOTS!
Boots: COME ON, DORA!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Kids:
♪ D-D-D-D-D-DORA♪
LET'S GO.
♪ DORA, DORA, DORA
THE EXPLORER♪
DORA!
♪ BOOTS AND SUPERCOOL
EXPLORADORA. ♪
Dora:
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
Boots:
GRAB YOUR BACKPACK!
♪ LET'S GO, JUMP IN...♪
VAMONOS!
♪ YOU CAN LEAD THE WAY♪
HEY! HEY!
♪ D-D-DORA, D-D-D-DORA♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING♪
OH, MAN!
HI, I'M DORA!
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
WOW, THAT'S BIG!
GUESS WHAT.
IT'S STORYTIME.
STORYTIME,
STORYTIME
STORYTIME!
[ giggling]
BOOTS!
DORA!
HEY, BOOTS, DO
YOU WANT TO READ
A REALLY GREAT BOOK?
A BOOK! YEAH,
YEAH, YEAH!
IT'S IN MY BACKPACK.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU OPEN MY BACKPACK SO I
CAN READ BOOTS THE BIG RED BOOK?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "BACKPACK."
SAY "BACKPACK"!
LOUDER!
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ I'M A BACKPACK LOADED UP WITH
THINGS AND KNICKKNACKS, TOO ♪
♪ ANYTHING THAT YOU MIGHT NEED
I GOT INSIDE FOR YOU. ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK. ♪
YEAH!
I HAVE LOTS OF BOOKS, BUT DORA
NEEDS TO FIND THE BIG RED BOOK.
LET'S LOOK FOR ALL
OF THE RED BOOKS FIRST.
IS THIS A RED BOOK?
GREAT!
NOW, WHICH ONE IS
THE BIG RED BOOK?
YOU DID IT.
NOW DORA CAN READ
THE BIG RED BOOK TO BOOTS.
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM--
DELICIOSO!
GRACIAS.
THANKS.
WHAT'S IT CALLED?
LA LEYENDA DEL
POLLO ROJO GRANDE.
THE LEGEND OF
THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
THE BOOK IS IN SPANISH
BUT I CAN TELL YOU
WHAT IT SAYS.
ONCE THERE WAS
A LITTLE RED CHICKEN
WHO LIVED ON
A BIG RED HILL.
[ clucking]
Dora:
THE LITTLE RED CHICKEN
WAS VERY, VERY LITTLE.
HE COULDN'T RUN
AS FAST AS HIS FRIENDS.
HE WAS SO LITTLE THAT
HE HAD TO BE VERY CAREFUL
OR HIS FRIENDS
WOULD STEP ON HIM.
[ clucking]
HE DIDN'T LIKE BEING SO LITTLE.
[ clucking sadly]
THEN ONE NIGHT, WHEN
THE LITTLE CHICKEN WENT TO BED
HE SAW A GROUP OF STARS
SHAPED LIKE A BIG CHICKEN.
[ clucking in awe]
HE MADE A WISH ON THE STARS
THAT HE WOULD BE BIG.
[ clucking feebly]
AND GUESS WHAT HAPPENED
IN THE MORNING.
WHEN THE LITTLE RED CHICKEN WOKE
UP, HE WASN'T LITTLE ANYMORE.
HE WAS A BIG CHICKEN.
HE WAS AS BIG AS A HOUSE.
[ clucking loudly]
THE BIG CHICKEN WAS SO HAPPY
HE DANCED THE CHICKEN DANCE
BY FLAPPING HIS ARMS
AND STAMPING HIS FEET.
[ chicken dance music playing]
AND GUESS WHAT-- IF YOU
GO TO THE BIG RED HILL
MAYBE YOU CAN MEET
THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
THEY SAY HE'S STILL
DANCING THE CHICKEN DANCE.
GREAT STORY, DORA.
I WANT TO GO SEE
THE BIG RED CHICKEN
ON THE BIG RED HILL.
GREAT IDEA!
LET'S GO FIND
THAT CHICKEN.
WHICH WAY IS
THE CHICKEN?
REMEMBER,
THE BOOK SAID
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO FIND HIM
ON THE BIG RED HILL.
LET'S CHECK THE MAP
TO FIND OUT HOW TO GET
TO THE BIG RED HILL.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
COULD YOU CHECK THE MAP FOR US
AND FIND OUT HOW TO GET
TO THE BIG RED HILL?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "MAP."
I THINK YOU HAVE
TO SAY IT AGAIN.
SAY "MAP"!
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GO ♪
♪ I'M THE ONE YOU NEED TO KNOW ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GET ♪
♪ I CAN GET YOU THERE, I BET ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
I'M THE MAP!
DORA AND BOOTS NEED TO GET
TO THE BIG RED HILL
TO FIND THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
WELL, I KNOW HOW TO GET
TO THE BIG RED HILL.
TO GET TO THE BIG RED HILL
YOU NEED TO GO
OVER THE BRIDGE...
THROUGH THE GATE...
AND THAT'S HOW YOU GET
TO THE BIG RED HILL.
[ squawking]
SO HERE'S WHAT YOU TELL DORA:
BRIDGE... GATE... BIG RED HILL.
SAY IT WITH ME.
BRIDGE, GATE, BIG RED HILL.
HOW DO WE GET TO SEE THE BIG RED
CHICKEN ON THE BIG RED HILL?
BRIDGE...
GATE...
BIG RED HILL.
SO WE NEED TO GO OVER THE BRIDGE
THROUGH THE GATE
AND THAT'S HOW WE'LL GET
TO THE BIG RED HILL
TO FIND THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
GRACIAS.
ALL RIGHT, BOOTS.
SO FIRST, WE NEED TO GO
OVER THE BRIDGE.
DO YOU SEE
THE BRIDGE?
WHERE?
YEAH, THERE'S
THE BRIDGE.
GREAT.
LET'S GO!
VAMONOS!
BRIDGE, GATE,
BIG RED HILL.
Both:
BRIDGE, GATE, BIG RED HILL.
♪ ♪ ♪
Dora and Boots:
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO. ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE BIG RED HILL. ♪
[ giggling]
BIG RED HILL!
[ song ends]
[ rustling]
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
HEY, BOOTS, WE
BETTER WATCH OUT
FOR SWIPER THE FOX.
THAT SNEAKY FOX
IS ALWAYS TRYING
TO SWIPE OUR STUFF.
COULD YOU HELP US
LOOK FOR SWIPER?
IF YOU SEE THE FOX,
YELL "SWIPER!"
YOU SEE HIM?
WHERE?
I DON'T SEE HIM.
WHERE IS HE NOW?
BEHIND THE TREE?
THERE HE IS!
WE NEED YOUR HELP
TO STOP SWIPER.
YOU HAVE TO SAY,
"SWIPER, NO SWIPING."
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
SWIPER, NO SWIPING.
OH, MAN!
THANKS FOR HELPING
US STOP SWIPER.
MMM, YUM--
DELICIOSO.
COME ON, BOOTS.
LET'S GO TO
THE BIG RED HILL
AND SEE IF WE CAN FIND
THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
DO YOU THINK HE'S
GOING TO BE THERE?
DO YOU, DO YOU?
I SURE HOPE SO.
WHAT DO YOUTHINK?
DO YOU THINK THE BIG RED CHICKEN
WILL BE THERE?
OH, I HOPE HE'S THERE,
OH, I HOPE HE'S THERE.
COME ON, BOOTS!
LET'S GO SEE.
BRIDGE, GATE, BIG RED HILL.
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO. ♪
♪ COME ON, LET'S
GET TO IT. ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE BIG RED HILL. ♪
[ giggling]
BIG RED HILL!
[ song ends]
LOOK, IT'S THE BRIDGE.
THE BRIDGE, YEAH.
WE'VE MADE IT
TO THE BRIDGE.
Both:
ALL RIGHT!
BIG CHICKEN,
HERE I COME.
WAIT, BOOTS--
CAREFUL.
THE BRIDGE IS MISSING
SOME PIECES OF WOOD.
BUT I WANT TO GO LOOK
FOR THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
WELL, MAYBE
WE CAN FIND
THE MISSING
PIECES.
DO YOU SEE
THE MISSING PIECES?
YEAH, THERE ARE
THE MISSING PIECES
DOWN THERE! SEE?
YEAH, BUT HOW ARE WE
GOING TO GET THEM?
I DON'T KNOW.
LET'S STOP
AND THINK.
[ clock ticking]
MAYBE THERE'S
SOMEONE WE COULD
ASK FOR HELP.
DO YOU SEE ANYONE
WHO CAN HELP US?
THE BIRD!
GOOD THINKING.
SEÑOR TUCAN CAN HELP
US FIX THE BRIDGE.
SEÑOR TUCAN,
WILL YOU HELP US
FIX THE BRIDGE?
¿QUE?
WHAT DID HE SAY?
HE SAID, "¿QUE?"
SEÑOR TUCAN
SPEAKS SPANISH.
WILL YOU ASK HIM
TO HELP US FIX
THE BRIDGE?
SURE.
DISCULPE, SEÑOR TUCAN.
¿PUEDE AYUDARNOS
A REPARAR EL PUENTE?
OH, SI.
WILL HE HELP US
FIX THE BRIDGE?
HE SAID YES.
YES!
REMEMBER, YOU HAVE
TO TELL SEÑOR TUCAN
WHICH PIECE WILL FILL IN
THE HOLE IN THE BRIDGE.
IF THE BIG PIECE WILL FIX
THE BRIDGE, SAY "GRANDE."
IF THE LITTLE PIECE WILL FIX
THE BRIDGE, YOU SAY "PEQUEÑO."
WHAT DO WE
SAY AGAIN?
GRANDEFOR "BIG,"
PEQUEÑOFOR "LITTLE."
GRANDE.
PEQUEÑO.
SAY IT WITH ME.
GRANDE.
PEQUEÑO.
REMEMBER, YOU HAVE
TO TELL SEÑOR TUCAN
WHICH PIECE WILL FILL IN
THE HOLE IN THE BRIDGE.
GRANDE.
PEQUEÑO.
GRANDE-- GRACIAS.
YEAH, WAY TO GO!
GRANDE--YOU PICKED
THE BIG ONE.
GRANDE.
PEQUEÑO.
OH, PEQUEÑO.
PEQUEÑO--YOU PICKED
THE LITTLE ONE.
ALL RIGHT!
GRANDE.
PEQUEÑO.
GRANDE!
[ playing little fanfare]
Dora:
THANK YOU FOR HELPING
US FIX THE BRIDGE.
GRACIAS, SEÑOR TUCAN.
DE NADA.
GOOD-BYE,
SEÑOR TUCAN.
ADIOS, SEÑOR TUCAN.
SO, WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
BRIDGE...
GATE...
BIG RED HILL.
WE MADE IT OVER THE BRIDGE,
SO NEXT WE GO TO...
THE GATE!
DO YOU SEE
THE GATE?
WHERE?
YEAH, THERE'S
THE GATE.
LET'S GO.
BRIDGE, GATE, BIG RED HILL.
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO. ♪
♪ COME ON, LET'S
GET TO IT. ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
TO THE
BIG RED HILL.
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
TO THE
BIG RED HILL.
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
TO THE BIG RED HILL.
[ giggling]
BIG RED HILL!
THE GATE, THE GATE!
WE MADE IT
TO THE GATE.
Both:
YES, ALL RIGHT.
I'M GOING TO SEE
THE BIG CHICKEN.
IT'S LOCKED.
UH-OH.
COME ON,
COME ON.
OPEN, OPEN, OPEN.
[ grunting]
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
LET'S STOP
AND THINK.
[ clock ticking]
THE GATE IS LOCKED.
WHAT DO WE USE
TO OPEN A LOCK?
A KEY! A KEY!
RIGHT, BOOTS.
THAT MEANS WE NEED
TO LOOK FOR A KEY.
DO YOU SEE A KEY?
WHERE?
GRACIAS.
THANKS.
BIG KEY.
SURE IS.
DO YOU THINK IT WILL
OPEN THE GATE?
LET'S SEE.
THE LOCK HAS ONE...
TWO...
THREE...
FOUR POINTS.
NOW LET'S COUNT
THE POINTS ON THE KEY.
ONE...
TWO...
THREE...
FOUR.
I THINK THIS KEY WILL FIT.
YES.
CAN I DO IT, DORA?
PLEASE.
SURE.
Both:
WHOA!
YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
I DON'TSEE HIM.
YOU SEE SWIPER?
Both:WHERE?
RIGHT BEHIND US?
Both:
SWIPER, NO...
[ quietly]:
SWIPING.
YOU'RE TOO LATE.
[ cackles]
YOU'LL NEVER
FIND IT NOW.
OH, NO.
DON'T WORRY, BOOTS,
WE'LL FIND THE KEY.
HOW?
LET'S SEE.
WHAT DO WE KNOW
ABOUT THE KEY?
IT'S BIG.
BUT ALL THE KEYS
ARE BIG.
WHAT ELSE DO WE KNOW
ABOUT THE KEY?
IT HAS
FOUR POINTS.
RIGHT.
LET'S COUNT THE POINTS
ON THE KEYS
TO FIND THE RIGHT ONE.
CAN YOU HELP US
COUNT THE POINTS
ON THE KEYS?
GRACIAS.
WE NEED TO FIND
THE KEY WITH...
HOW MANY POINTS?
FOUR, RIGHT.
LET'S COUNT TOGETHER.
Both:
ONE, TWO.
IS THIS THE ONE?
NO.
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR FOUR.
MAYBE THIS KEY
IS THE KEY.
REMEMBER, WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A KEY WITH FOUR POINTS.
LET'S COUNT THE POINTS
ON THE KEY AND SEE.
ONE... TWO... THREE.
IS THIS THE ONE?
WE'RE NOT GIVING UP.
NEVER!
LET'S COUNT,
LET'S COUNT.
HOW MANY POINTS
ON THIS KEY?
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR.
IS THIS THE ONE?
THIS IS THE KEY
WITH THE FOUR POINTS.
WE FOUND IT!
Boots:
THANK YOU, THANK YOU,
THANK YOU.
IT FITS, BUT...
OOH, I CAN'T
TURN IT.
WAIT, I THINK...
IT'S... TURNING.
YOU DID IT, BOOTS!
[ playing little fanfare]
WE MADE IT
THROUGH THE GATE!
ALL RIGHT!
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
WE MADE IT OVER THE BRIDGE...
THROUGH THE GATE...
AND NOW WE CAN GO TO THE...
[ clucks]
Both:
BIG RED HILL!
WHERE IS
THE BIG RED HILL?
DO YOU SEE
WHERE?
LOOK, I CAN SEE
THE BIG RED HILL.
WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
I'M COMING,
BIG RED CHICKEN.
Boots:
OH, I HOPE HE'S THERE.
I HOPE HE'S THERE.
I HOPE
HE'S THERE.
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
I HOPE HE'S THERE.
WHERE IS HE?
I'VE GOT AN IDEA.
THE BIG RED CHICKEN
LOVES THE CHICKEN DANCE.
IF WE ALL DO
THE CHICKEN DANCE,
I BET THE BIG RED
CHICKEN WILL COME.
WILL YOU DO THE
CHICKEN DANCE
WITH ME?
CAN YOU FLAP
YOUR ARMS?
FLAP YOUR ARMS.
[ chicken dance music playing]
NOW STAND UP, PLEASE.
STAND UP.
UP, UP, GET UP.
KEEP FLAPPING
YOUR ARMS.
FLAP YOUR ARMS.
NOW STAMP YOUR FEET.
CAN YOU DO THEM
TOGETHER?
NOW SAY, "CLUCK,
CLUCK, CLUCK, CLUCK."
YOU'RE DOING
THE CHICKEN DANCE.
CLUCK, CLUCK,
CLUCK, CLUCK.
Both:
CLUCK, CLUCK, CLUCK, CLUCK.
DORA, THE BIG
RED HILL--
IT'S MOVING.
WHY IS THE HILL MOVING?
WHAT COULD IT BE?
BOOTS, IT'S... IT'S...
[ squawks]
Both:
THE BIG
RED CHICKEN!
[ chicken dance music ends]
THANK YOU FOR DANCING.
YOU CAN SIT DOWN NOW.
HI, BIG RED
CHICKEN.
HELLO.
I SAW YOU
IN THE BOOK.
YOU DID?
GREAT.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
I'M BOOTS.
I'M DORA.
I'M THE BIG RED
CHICKEN.
[ clucks loudly]
I KNEW WE'D
FIND HIM.
ME, TOO.
OH, DORA,
WE DID IT.
♪ ♪ ♪
Both:
WE DID IT.
YAY!
LO HICIMOS.
WE DID IT.
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ WE WALKED OVER THE BRIDGE ♪
♪ AND THROUGH THE GATE. ♪
♪ YEAH, WE DID IT. ♪
WE DID IT.
WE DID IT-- HOORAY!
♪ AT THE BIG RED HILL
WE SAW THE BIG RED CHICKEN ♪
♪ YEAH, WE DID IT. ♪
WE DID IT.
SEÑOR TUCAN
HELPED US...
Both:
ALONG THE WAY.
HOLA.
SWIPER TOOK THE KEY...
BUT WE MADE IT.
HOORAY!
YAY!
WHOO!
HOORAY!
WE DID IT.
Tucán:
LO HICIMOS!
Dora:
WHOO!
WE HAD SUCH
A FUN TRIP TODAY.
WHAT WAS YOUR FAVORITE
PART OF THE TRIP?
I LIKED THAT, TOO.
MY FAVORITE PART
WAS WHEN WE SAW
THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
MY FAVORITE PART WAS
DOING THE CHICKEN DANCE.
WE COULDN'T HAVE MADE IT
WITHOUT YOU.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
Dora:
THIS IS MY FRIEND
BENNY THE BULL.
FIND BENNY.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
[Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ giggles]
[ children giggling]