Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Hi, I'm Dora.
And I'm Boots.
We're at the beach.
We're looking
for seashells.
Do you see
any seashells?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah! Seashells!
[ soft whooshing]
This one makes
a funny sound.
Listen.
[ soft whooshing]
I hear it,
I hear it!
I want to find
a starfish.
Do you see a starfish?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah.
Ooh, ooh, ah, ah!
Starfish, starfish!
Look, Dora.
It's shaped like a star.
[ baby sniffling and crying]
Boots, did you
hear that?
It sounds like a baby,
and he's crying.
[ sniffling and crying]
Aw, look...
it's a Baby Red Fish.
Why isn't he
in the ocean, Dora?
Yeah, Baby Red Fish.
You should be in the ocean,
not on the beach.
I know.
I swam too far from home.
And then this big wave came
and, and I've got to get home.
I've got to get home.
Mommy! Daddy!
My sisters!
My brothers!
BOTH:
Aw...
Poor fishy.
He misses his family.
Don't worry.
We'll help you
find your family.
You will?
Oh, thank you, thank you.
[ kissing]
[ giggles]
Come here, fishy,
I'll carry you.
Wait! Wait! Wait!
I need water!
Oh, sorry.
Dora, he needs water.
How are we going to
carry him home?
I bet I have
something in my Backpack
that we can fill with water
to carry the fish.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find something
we can fill with water?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
Hola.
I have lots of stuff.
But Dora and Boots
want to find
something they can
fill with water
to carry Baby Red Fish home.
Can they fill this with water?
Can they fill thiswith water?
Oops, that has holes.
Can they fill this with water?
[ click, beep]
Yes! They can fill
the pail with water
to carry Baby Red Fish.
Good thinking.
iMuy bien!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Here you go, Baby Red Fish.
Hop in.
Water! Water!
[ giggles]
Thank you.
Now we can take
the Baby Red Fish
home to his family.
ALL:
Yay!
Come on!
Where do you live,
Baby Red Fish?
By the Red Rock.
Dora, where's the Red Rock?
I don't know, Boots.
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help when
we don't know which way to go?
The Map! The Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us
how to find the Red Rock.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find out how to get
to the Red Rock?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map,"
Say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to get
to the Red Rock
so they can take Baby Red Fish
home to his family.
Well, I know how to get
to the Red Rock.
To get to the Red Rock
first you go past
the sand castle.
Then you go to the bottom
of the ocean.
And that's how you get
to the Red Rock.
ALL:
Baby Red Fish,
Baby Red Fish!
Come home,
come home!
So you tell Dora:
Castle...
ocean...
Red Rock.
Say it with me.
Castle...
ocean...
Red Rock.
Castle...
ocean...
Red Rock.
Castle...
ocean...
Red Rock...!
How do we take Baby Red Fish
home to him family?
Castle...
ocean...
Red Rock.
First we go past
the sand castle.
Then we go
to the bottom of the ocean.
And that's how we'll get
to the Red Rock
to take Baby Red Fish
home to his family.
Baby Red Fish,
Baby Red Fish!
Come home,
come home!
Thanks for helping.
First, we need to find
the sand castle.
Do you see a sand castle?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the sand castle.
I see it.
Let's go,
let's go!
Vámonos.
Let's get Baby Red Fish
home to his family.
Come on, say it with us.
BOTH:
Castle, ocean, Red Rock.
Castle, ocean,
Red Rock.
Castle, ocean, Red Rock.
Castle, ocean,
Red Rock.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Red Rock ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Red Rock ♪
ALL:
♪ Red Rock! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Red Rock! ♪
iCuidado!
Watch out!
Watch out for what?
The Big Clams, the Big Clams.
The Big Clams!
BOTH:
Ooh, the Big Clams!
Be careful or the
Big Clams will trap you.
ALL:
Ooh...
If you get stuck,
you have to say "abre."
"Abre"will open the clam.
I need your help.
If one of the clams traps us
we have to say "abre"
to open the clam.
Can you say "abre"?
Say "abre."
Uh-oh.
I'm stuck, I'm stuck!
Dora, the Big Clam...
my tail... I'm stuck!
Quick, we have to say "abre"!
Say it with us.
ALL: iAbre!
¿A... bre?
It worked!
Saying "abre"
made the clam open.
Whew.
Thanks.
Come on!
BABY RED FISH:
Whoa!
Oh, no!
The Baby Red Fish
is stuck in a clam!
BABY RED FISH
[ muffled]:
Help! Help!
We have to say "abre"
to open the clam.
Say it with us.
BOTH: iAbre!
¿A... bre?
It worked.
You said "abre"
and made the giant clam open up.
[ kisses]
Thank you for saving
Baby Red Fish
from the giant clam.
Thank you!
[ laughs]
Look, there's the sand castle!
Hola,Dora.
Hola,Boots.
It's King Crab.
BOTH:
Hola,King Crab.
Where are you going
on this fine sunny day?
We're taking this Baby Red Fish
back to his family.
Can we go
over your castle wall?
iSí!You just have to climb
like a crab and go up this net.
I need your help.
Will you help us climb
the net like a crab?
Great.
First put your hands up
in the air and make claws.
Snap your claws,
snap your claws.
Snap, snap, snap,
snap, snap, snap.
Now reach up and
climb with your claws.
BOTH:
Climb, climb, climb!
We made it to the top
of the castle wall.
Good climbing.
Wow! You can climb like a crab!
iMuy bien! iMuy bien!
Now we have to slide
down the sand slide.
Hug your knees and
get ready to slide.
Hug your knees
and say "whee!"
ALL:
Whee...!
[ all laugh]
[ play happy tune]
That was fun!
[ laughs]
Good sliding!
Where do we go next?
Castle, ocean, Red Rock.
We made it past the castle,
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
ocean, right!
Now, where's
the ocean?
Do you see the ocean?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the ocean!
I see the ocean.
Mommy! Daddy!
Here I come!
iVámonos!
Let's go take Baby Red Fish
home to his family.
Come on, say it with us.
BOTH:
Castle, ocean, Red Rock.
Castle, ocean,
Red Rock.
Castle, ocean, Red Rock.
Castle, ocean,
Red Rock.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Red Rock ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Red Rock ♪
ALL:
♪ Red Rock! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Red Rock! ♪
[ rustling]
Did you hear that?
That sounds like
Swiper the fox.
That sneaky fox is always
trying to swipe our stuff.
Oh, no...
Boots, he'll try to
swipe our pail!
If you see Swiper the
fox, yell "Swiper."
Do you see Swiper?
Behind the umbrella?
Yeah, there's the fox.
there's the fox.
Stop him, stop him!
We need your help
to stop Swiper.
We have to say,
"Swiper, no swiping."
Say it with us.
ALL:
Swiper, no swiping.
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
[ laughs]
Thanks for helping
us stop Swiper.
Look! We made it
to the ocean!
Mommy! Daddy!
My sisters! My brothers!
Here I come!
Hey, Dora, Boots
aren't you
coming with me?
We want to, Baby Red Fish
but we have to find a boat
that can go underwater.
How are we going to find
a boat like that?
I don't know, Boots.
I don't see a boat.
Do you?
No.
No boat.
What's that?
You see a boat?
BOTH:
It's a submarine!
A submarine is a boat
that can go underwater.
All right!
Yay! Yay!
Hey, look, it's
Val the octopus!
Hola,Dora.
Hola,Boots.
Oh... Baby Red Fish!
You are far from home.
We want to help
Baby Red Fish
get home
to his family.
Can we have a ride
in your submarine?
Of course.
Con mucho gusto.
OTHERS:
Yay!
[ laughs]
All aboard!
I'll swim down and lead the way.
iFantástico!
iMuy bien!
But first we have to close
our submarine snug and tight.
Are you ready to go?
Almost.
We're going down
to the bottom of the ocean.
That's very deep.
Now we'll have to start
our eight deep water engines.
Count with me.
ALL:
One
two
three
four
five
six
seven
eight!
We're going down!
BOTH:
Whoa...!
Cool!
We're underwater.
Follow me.
BOOTS:
I've never been
deep in the ocean before.
Me, neither.
Look! Sea turtles!
Dolphins!
[ laughs]
DORA:
A sea horse!
Hello.
BOOTS:
Look! Look!
Oh, no. Watch out!
VAL:
iCuidado!
We need your help
to save Baby Red Fish.
Tell Big Blue Fish
to say "abre."
What do I say to make the
Big Blue Fish open his mouth?
"Abre"?
iAbre!
¿Abre?
Whew! Thanks.
[ laughs]
BOOTS:
Oh, no!
He swallowed them both!
We need your help to save
Baby Red Fish and Big Blue Fish.
So you need to tell the fish
to say "abre."
BOTH:
What do we say?
iAbre!
¿Abre?
BOTH:
Thanks for
saying "abre."
[ laughs]
Come on.
We're almost to the
bottom of the ocean.
[ play happy tune]
Wow, we're down deep.
Where do we go next?
Castle, ocean, Red Rock.
We made it past the castle
down to the bottom of the ocean
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Red Rock, right.
Baby Red Fish,
Baby Red Fish!
Come home,
come home!
I don't see the Red Rock
Do you see
the Red Rock?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the Red Rock
there's
the Red Rock!
Mommy! Daddy!
My sisters! My brothers!
I'm coming home!
iVámonos!
Let's go take Baby Red Fish
home to his family.
BOOTS:
Red Rock! Red Rock! Red Rock!
Where's the Red Rock?
VAL:
I don't see it.
Will you help Baby Red Fish
find the Red Rock
so he can get home
to his family?
Great.
There are so many
places to look.
First let's look
for everything that's red.
Is there any red here?
Yes! Let's look.
[ click, beep]
That's a starfish!
It's red.
Is it the Red Rock?
[ click, beep]
It's a sea serpent!
Is there any red here?
[ click, beep]
It's a squid.
Where else do you see red?
Here?
Let's look.
[ click, beep]
Yeah! You found the Red Rock!
BOOTS:
And there's
Baby Red Fish's family.
Ooh...!
Mommy! Daddy!
My sisters!
My brothers!
My baby, my baby!
Where were you?
We were so worried.
OTHERS:
He's home!
BOTH:
Baby Red Fish.
Yay!
[ laughing]
Mommy, Daddy,
my sisters, my brothers...
I could never have gotten
back home
if it wasn't for my friends.
Val the Octopus.
And Boots.
And Dora.
And you!
Thank you... thank you...
Thank you.
De nada.
Dora, we got
Baby Red Fish home.
BOTH:
We did it!
[ music playing]
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
BOTH:
Yay!
♪ Lo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We got Baby Red Fish
home to his family ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! Hooray! ♪
♪ We went past the sand castle
to the ocean bottom ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Climbed like crabs
up the King Crab's net ♪
♪ We used the submarine
and we didn't get wet! ♪
Yay!
Whoo!
Hooray!
We did it!
[ click, beep]
We had such
an exciting trip
taking Baby Red Fish
home to his family.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part
was when we all
yelled "abre"
and the very big green
fish opened his mouth.
My favorite part was
when we climbed like a crab
up the King Crab's net.
We couldn't have gotten
Baby Red Fish home without you.
Thanks for helping.
[ click, beep]
DORA:
This is my friend
Tico the squirrel.
Find Tico!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ laughs]
Ay!
iHola!
[ click, beep]
[ laughs]
[ giggles, laughs]