Boots:
DORA!
Dora:
BOOTS!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
♪ D-D-D-D-D-DORA♪
LET'S GO.
♪ DORA, DORA, DORA
THE EXPLORER♪
DORA!
♪ BOOTS AND SUPERCOOL
EXPLORADORA? ♪
Dora:
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
Boots:
GRAB YOUR BACKPACK!
♪ LET'S GO, JUMP IN...♪
VAMONOS!
♪ YOU CAN LEAD THE WAY♪
HEY! HEY!
♪ D-D-DORA, D-D-D-DORA♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING♪
OH, MAN!
[ arrow beeps]
HI, I'M DORA.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
[ softly]:
CAN YOU HEAR ME NOW?
[ loudly]:
I'M PLAYING "LOUD AND SOFT."
THIS IS LOUD!
[ softly]:
THIS IS SOFT.
[ loudly]:
LOUD!
[ softly]:
SOFT.
[ shouts]:
LOUD!
[ whispers]:
SOFT.
[ giggles]
BOOTS!
DORA!
[ from a distance]:
HIC! BOOM! OHH!
BOOTS, DID YOU HEAR
SOMETHING FUNNY?
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
WHAT WAS THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
HIC! BOOM! OHH!
MAYBE IT'S THUNDER.
OR MAYBE
IT'S A MONSTER.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
I NEVER HEARD A SOUND
LIKE THAT BEFORE.
HIC! BOOM! OHH!
LET'S FIND OUT WHAT IT IS.
LET'S FIND THE SOUND.
YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
HIC! BOOM! OHH!
WE GOT TO FIND OUT
WHAT THAT SOUND IS.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW WHERE
TO FIND THE SOUND.
WHO DO WE ASK FOR HELP
WHEN WE DON'T KNOW
WHICH WAY TO GO?
MAP! MAP! MAP!
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE MAP CAN TELL US WHERE
THE SOUND IS COMING FROM.
YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
I NEED YOUR HELP
TO CHECK THE MAP
AND FIND OUT WHERE
THE SOUND IS COMING FROM.
YOU HAVE TO SAY "MAP."
SAY MAP! SAY MAP!
LOUDER!LOUDER!
[ jazzy music playing]
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GO ♪
♪ I'M THE ONE YOU NEED TO KNOW ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU'VE GOT TO GET ♪
♪ I CAN GET YOU THERE, I BET ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
♪ I'M THE MAP! ♪
DORA AND BOOTS WANT TO FIND OUT
WHERE THE SOUND IS COMING FROM.
WELL, I KNOW WHERE
THE SOUND IS COMING FROM.
IT'S COMING FROM YELLOW VALLEY.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
TO GET TO YELLOW VALLEY
FIRST YOU NEED TO GO
ACROSS THE NOISY RIVER.
[ river babbling]
THEN GO THROUGH
THE QUIET FOREST.
Voice in forest:
SHH.
AND THAT'S HOW YOU GET
TO YELLOW VALLEY.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
SO YOU TELL DORA:
RIVER...
FOREST...
YELLOW VALLEY.
SAY IT WITH ME.
RIVER...
FOREST...
YELLOW VALLEY.
RIVER...
FOREST...
YELLOW VALLEY.
RIVER...
FOREST...
YELLOW VALLEY!
WHERE DO WE GO
TO FIND THE SOUND?
RIVER...
FOREST...
YELLOW VALLEY.
SO FIRST WE HAVE TO GO
ACROSS THE NOISY RIVER...
[ river babbling]
THROUGH THE QUIET FOREST...
Voice:
SHH.
AND THAT'S HOW WE'LL GET TO
YELLOW VALLEY TO FIND THE SOUND.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
THANKS FOR HELPING.
LET'S GO! LET'S GO!
LET'S GO FIND THE SOUND.
OKAY, BOOTS.
FIRST, WE NEED TO GO
ACROSS THE NOISY RIVER.
DO YOU SEE A RIVER?
WHERE?
[ arrow beeps]
YEAH, THERE'S THE RIVER.
COME ON, BOOTS.
LET'S GO FIND THE SOUND.
YAY!
YEAH!
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
HIC! BOOM! OHH!
♪ COME ON, VAMANOS! ♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO! ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT. ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHAT'S THAT SOUND? ♪
♪ HIC-BOOM-OHH. ♪
All:
♪ WHAT'S THAT SOUND? ♪
♪ HIC-BOOM-OHH. ♪
All:
[ both giggling]
HIC! BOOM! OHH!
[ river babbling]
LISTEN, BOOTS.
THIS MUST BE
THE NOISY RIVER.
[ babbling continues]
WOW! IT REALLY IS
A NOISY RIVER.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
WE HAVE TO GET
ACROSS THE RIVER
TO FIND OUT WHAT
THAT SOUND IS.
HOW ARE WE GOING
TO GET ACROSS?
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE WE CAN FIND
SOMETHING TO USE
TO GET ACROSS THE RIVER.
DO YOU SEE ANYTHING
WE CAN USE TO GET
ACROSS THE NOISY RIVER?
[ arrow beeps]
THE BOATS?
GOOD IDEA.
WE NEED TO
CHOOSE A BOAT.
WE NEED A BOAT
WITHOUT ANY HOLES
AND IT MUST HAVE
LIFEJACKETS.
Boots:
SO WE CAN BE SAFE.
WHICH BOAT
SHOULD WE CHOOSE?
[ arrow beeps]
BLUE?
THE BLUE BOAT?
THANKS.
BUT HOW ARE WE GOING TO
GET THE BLUE BOAT, DORA?
LOOK, BOOTS!
THAT'S OUR FRIEND,
TICO THE SQUIRREL.
WE CAN ASK TICO
TO BRING US A BOAT.
TICO! TICO!
[ babbling continues]
THIS NOISY RIVER
IS SO NOISY.
TICO CAN'T HEAR US.
WE HAVE TO BE
EVEN LOUDER.
WE NEED YOUR HELP
TO CALL TO TICO.
SAY "TICO!"
TICO!
LOUDER.
Tico:
DORA! BOOTS!
TICO, EL BOTE!
¿EL BOTE?
THE BOAT!
SI!
YES!
¿CUAL BOTE?
Dora:
TICO DOESN'T KNOW
WHICH BOAT TO USE
TO GET ACROSS THE NOISY RIVER.
WE HAVE TO TELL TICO
TO TAKE THE BLUE BOAT.
TICO SPEAKS SPANISH,
SO WE NEED TO SAY "AZUL."
CAN YOU SAY AZUL?
SAY AZUL.
NOW SAY IT WITH US.
NOW SAY IT
WITH US.
AZUL! AZUL!
TICO STILL
DIDN'T HEAR US.
SAY AZULLOUDER.
AZUL! AZUL!
AZUL!
Both:
YAY! YAY! TICO!
GO, TICO!
TICO, COME ON.
YOU CAN DO IT.
[ playing fanfare]
WE DID IT!
WE MADE IT!
WE MADE IT ACROSS
THE NOISY RIVER.
YAY!YAY!
YAY!
THANKS FOR HELPING.
AND TICO HELPED, TOO.
THANKS, TICO.
MUCHAS GRACIAS,TICO.
DE NADA.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
THERE'S THE SOUND AGAIN.
WHAT CAN IT BE?
LET'S GO! LET'S GO!
LET'S GO FIND
THE SOUND.
BUT WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
RIVER...
FOREST...
YELLOW VALLEY.
WE MADE IT ACROSS
THE NOISY RIVER.
[ river babbles]
SO NOW WE HAVE TO GO TO THE...
[ arrow beeps]
FOREST-- RIGHT!
THE QUIET FOREST.
AND THEN WE'LL GET TO THE YELLOW
VALLEY AND FIND THE SOUND.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
NOW, WHERE'S
THE QUIET FOREST?
DO YOU SEE
[ arrow beeps]
RIGHT-- THERE IT IS.
COME ON, LET'S GO!
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
HIC! BOOM! OHH!
[ snoring]
IT'S THE BIG
RED CHICKEN.
OH, NO!
THE BIG RED CHICKEN
IS BLOCKING THE PATH
TO THE QUIET FOREST.
I THINK HE'S
TAKING A NAP.
WELL, WE'LL HAVE
TO WAKE HIM UP.
EXCUSE ME...
BIG RED CHICKEN
YOU HAVE TO MOVE.
BIG RED CHICKEN,
TIME TO WAKE UP!
[ snoring]
Both:
WAKE UP! WAKE UP!
[ snoring continues]
WOW! THAT CHICKEN
IS REALLY SLEEPING.
I KNOW!
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
IN MY BACKPACK
THAT WILL DEFINITELY WAKE
UP THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
YOU DO?
YEAH.
I NEED YOURHELP.
WILL YOU CHECK MY BACKPACK
AND FIND SOMETHING THAT WILL
MAKE A REALLY LOUD NOISE
TO WAKE UP THE BIG RED CHICKEN?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "BACKPACK."
SAY "BACKPACK,"
SAY "BACKPACK."
Both:
LOUDER.
[ piano and string bass playing
zippy music]
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ I'M A BACKPACK LOADED UP WITH
THINGS AND KNICKKNACKS, TOO ♪
♪ ANYTHING THAT YOU MIGHT NEED
I GOT INSIDE FOR YOU ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK. ♪
♪ YEAH! ♪
[ music ends]
DORA NEEDS US TO FIND SOMETHING
THAT WILL MAKE
A REALLY LOUD NOISE
TO WAKE UP THE BIG CHICKEN!
WILL THIS MAKE A LOUD NOISE?
[ arrow beeps]
IT WILL?
A HORN WILL MAKE A LOUD NOISE?
[ horn blares]
WOW! THAT ISA LOUD NOISE!
GOOD WORK!
YUM-YUM-YUM-YUM!
DELICIOSO!
THIS IS DEFINITELY
GOING TO WAKE UP
THE BIG RED CHICKEN.
YEAH!
[ rustling]
BOOTS, DID YOU
HEAR THAT?
THAT SOUNDS LIKE
SWIPER THE FOX.
OOH, THAT SNEAKY FOX
IS ALWAYS TRYING
TO SWIPE OUR STUFF.
HE'LL TRY TO SWIPE
THIS HORN FOR SURE.
COULD YOU HELP US
LOOK FOR SWIPER?
IF YOU SEE THE FOX,
YELL "SWIPER."
YOU SEE HIM?
WHERE?
BEHIND US?
THERE HE IS.
WE NEED YOUR HELP
TO STOP SWIPER.
YOU HAVE TO SAY
"SWIPER, NO SWIPING."
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
SWIPER, NO SWIPING.
OH, MAN!
[ rustles]
THANKS FOR HELPING US
STOP SWIPER.
NOW LET'S WAKE UP THIS CHICKEN.
[ horn blares]
[ snorting]
OOH, OOH!
I THINK HE'S WAKING UP.
[ horn blares]
WELL, HELLO THERE,
YOU TWO.
HELLO,
BIG RED CHICKEN.
SORRY TO WAKE YOU UP
BUT YOU'RE BLOCKING THE PATH
TO THE QUIET FOREST.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S SO NICE
AND QUIET HERE
I WAS JUST
TAKING A NAP.
BUT NAP TIME'S
OVER NOW
SO I'LL BE
MOVING ALONG.
THANK YOU,
BIG RED CHICKEN.
YUM-YUM-YUM-YUM.
DELICIOSO!
LISTEN, BOOTS.
DO YOU HEAR ANYTHING?
NO.
THAT MEANS WE'RE
IN THE QUIET FOREST.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
THERE'S THE SOUND AGAIN.
I THINK THE SOUND
IS GETTING LOUDER.
THAT MEANS
WE'RE GETTING CLOSER.
[ "hic-boom-ohh" sounds echo]
COME ON, BOOTS,
WE NEED TO GO THROUGH
THE QUIET FOREST
SO WE CAN GET
TO THE YELLOW VALLEY AND...
[ loud snoring and whistling]
WHAT'S THAT SOUND?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT SOUNDS LIKE
SOMEONE'S SNORING.
LET'S SEE WHO IT IS.
[ muttering]
OH, NO! IT'S SWIPER
THE SNEAKY FOX.
[ snores and whistles]
Dora:
HE'S ASLEEP.
IF SWIPER WAKES UP
HE'LL TRY TO SWIPE
OUR STUFF.
WE HAVE TO GO
PAST SWIPER
TO GET THROUGH
THE QUIET FOREST.
WHAT ARE WE
GOING TO DO?
LET'S STOP AND THINK.
I KNOW!
IF WE ALL DO
THE TIPTOE WALK
WE CAN GET PAST SWIPER
WITHOUT WAKING HIM UP.
WILL YOU DO
THE TIPTOE WALK WITH US
AND HELP US GET
AROUND SWIPER?
YOU WILL?
GREAT.
NOW YOU NEED
TO STAND UP
TO DO THE TIPTOE WALK.
STAND UP, PLEASE.
STAND UP.
UP, UP-- GET UP!
[ Swiper snores and whistles]
NOW TIPTOE
ON YOUR TIPTOES.
TIPTOE
AND SAY "SHH."
[ snores, whistles]
YOU'RE DOING
THE TIPTOE WALK.
COME ON, FOLLOW ME.
Both:
SHH, TIPTOE.
[ moans]
[ snores]
Both:
SHH, TIPTOE.
[ playing fanfare]
WE MADE IT THROUGH
THE QUIET FOREST!
AND WE MADE IT
AROUND SWIPER
WITHOUT WAKING HIM UP.
THANKS FOR DOING
THE TIPTOE WALK.
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
RIVER...
FOREST...
YELLOW VALLEY.
WE WENT ACROSS
THE NOISY RIVER...
[ river babbles]
THROUGH THE QUIET FOREST...
Voice in forest:
SHH.
AND NEXT IS...
[ arrow beeps]
YELLOW VALLEY!
[ "hic-boom-ooh" sounds echo]
DO YOU SEE
YELLOW VALLEY?
WHERE?
[ beeps]
YEAH, THERE IT IS.
THE YELLOW VALLEY!
WE'RE GOING TO
FIND THE SOUND!
I WONDER
WHAT IT COULD BE.
[ "hic-boom-ooh" sounds echo]
MAYBE... IT'S
A SLEEPING GIANT.
OR MAYBE IT'S
A DANCING POTATO.
LOOK WHO'S HERE.
IT'S BENNY
THE BULL!
HEY, LET'S GO
ASK BENNY
IF HE KNOWS
WHAT THE SOUND IS.
HI, BENNY.
WE'VE COME
TO FIND OUT
WHAT'S MAKING
THAT SOUND.
WHAT SOUND?
I DIDN'T HEAR
ANY SOUND.
YOU DIDN'T?
NO. WHAT DOES IT
SOUND LIKE?
COME ON,
WE NEED YOUR HELP
TO MAKE THE "HIC-BOOM-OH"
SOUND FOR BENNY.
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
HIC... BOOM... OH!
HMM... CAN YOU
SAY IT AGAIN?
LET'S SAY IT AGAIN
FOR BENNY.
HIC... BOOM... OH!
NOPE, I NEVER HEARD
THAT SOUND BEFORE.
OH!
WHAT COULD IT BE?
LET'S LISTEN.
[ hiccups,
then booms]
OH!
[ hiccups,
then booms]
OH!
THERE IT IS AGAIN.
WHAT'S MAKING THAT SOUND?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT'S
MAKING THAT SOUND?
WHO?
BENNY?
[ hiccups,
then booms]
OH!
BENNY!
BENNY, YOU'VEBEEN
MAKING THAT SOUND.
YOU HAVE THE HICCUPS.
OH, YEAH!
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO GET RID OF MY HICCUPS
BUT THEY JUST WON'T GO AWAY.
WE CAN HELP YOU,
BENNY.
MY MOMMY TOLD ME A WAY
TO GET RID OF HICCUPS.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS
COUNT TO TEN
IN A REALLY LOUD VOICE
AND YOUR HICCUPS
WILL GO AWAY.
BUT...
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO COUNT ALL
THE WAY UP TO TEN.
[ hiccups, then booms]
OH!
I'LL NEVER GET RID
OF MY HICCUPS!
DON'T WORRY,
BENNY.
WE CAN USE OUR FINGERS
TO HELP YOU COUNT TO TEN.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
LET'S COUNT TO TEN
ON OUR FINGERS
TO HELP BENNY GET RID
OF HIS HICCUPS.
COUNT WITH ME.
All
ONE... TWO... THREE...
FOUR... FIVE... SIX...
SEVEN... EIGHT... NINE...
TEN!
MY HICCUPS ARE GONE!
YAY!
ALL RIGHT!
All:
WE DID IT!
[ music begins]
All:
WE DID IT!
YAY!
LO HICIMOS!
♪ WE DID IT. ♪
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ WE CROSSED THE NOISY RIVER ♪
♪ TO THE QUIET FOREST ♪
♪ YEAH, WE DID IT, WE DID IT,
WE DID IT! HOORAY! ♪
♪ IN THE YELLOW VALLEY
WE FOUND THE SOUND ♪
♪ IT WAS MY HICCUPS ♪
♪ HE DID IT, WE DID IT,
WE DID IT ♪
♪ WE GOT A BOAT FROM TICO
ALONG THE WAY ♪
♪ SWIPER FELL ASLEEP,
WE GOT PAST HIM, HOORAY! ♪
YAY! WOO! HOORAY!
WE DID IT!
[ chicken clucks, music ends]
[ arrow beeps]
WE HAD SUCH
A FUN TRIP TODAY.
WHAT WAS YOUR FAVORITE
PART OF THE TRIP?
I LIKED THAT, TOO.
Boots:
MY FAVORITE PART WAS
WHEN WE DID THE TIPTOE WALK
TO GET PAST SWIPER.
Dora:
MY FAVORITE PART WAS FINDING
THE "HIC-BOOM-OHH" SOUND.
MY FAVORITE PART
WAS WHEN YOU HELPED ME
COUNT TO TEN
TO GET RID OF MY HICCUPS!
THANKS FOR HELPING.
[ arrow beeps]
Dora:
OOH, SWIPIN' FOX.
FIND SWIPER.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ arrow beeps]
OH, MAN!
[ child giggles]