DORA!
BOOTS!
COME ON, DORA!
♪ DO-DO-DO-DO-D-DORA ♪
ALL RIGHT!
LET'S GO!
♪ DORA, DORA,
DORA THE EXPLORER ♪
DORA!
♪ BOOTS AND SUPER-COOL
EXPLORER DORA ♪
NEED YOUR HELP,
SO GRAB YOUR BACKPACK.
♪ LET'S GO, JUMP IN ♪
VAMANOS!
♪ YOU CAN LEAD THE WAY ♪
♪ HEY, HEY! ♪
♪ DO-DO-DORA, DO-DO-D-DORA ♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING,
SWIPER, NO SWIPING! ♪
OH, MAN!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
HI, I'M DORA.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
A TRAIN?
BOOTS AND I CAME
TO THE TRAIN STATION.
WE CAME TO SEE
THE TRAINS.
HERE COMES A TRAIN!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
OH! A TRAIN, A TRAIN!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
DORA, I LOVE TRAINS!
ME, TOO, BOOTS.
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
Both:
CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHUGGA-CHUGGA.
I LIKE WHEN THE TRAINS
BLOW THEIR BIG WHISTLES.
CAN WE MAKE THE TRAIN
BLOW HIS BIG WHISTLE?
WE CAN TRY.
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
IT DIDN'T WORK.
WILL YOU HELP US MAKE THE TRAIN
BLOW HIS BIG WHISTLE?
GREAT!
PULL THE WHISTLE AND SAY...
"CHOO-CHOO!"
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
AGAIN!
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
IT WORKED!
YEAH!
THANKS FOR HELPING.
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
HERE COMES
THE BIG RED TRAIN!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
COME ON!
LET'S GET THE BIG RED TRAIN
TO BLOW HERBIG WHISTLE.
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
PULL THE WHISTLE HARDER!
USE YOUR WHOLE BODY.
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
...CHUGGA-CHUGGA.
YEAH!
ALL RIGHT!
Boots:
HERE COMES
THE LITTLE BLUE TRAIN!
THAT'S AZUL.
"AZUL" MEANS BLUE
IN SPANISH.
SEE HOW BLUE AZUL IS?
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
HEY, AZUL, HOW COME YOU
DIDN'T BLOW YOUR WHISTLE?
I DON'T HAVE A WHISTLE.
Both:
NO WHISTLE?
HE DOESN'T HAVE
A WHISTLE.
ATTENTION, ALL TRAINS.
ATTENTION, ALL TRAINS!
IT'S TIME
FOR THE BIG TRAIN RACE!
FIRST TRAIN
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION
WILL WIN A BIG WHISTLE!
A RACE?
DO YOU HEAR THAT?
WOW, A BIG WHISTLE?
THAT'S GREAT!
THIS IS YOUR BIG CHANCE,
AZUL.
YOU CAN WIN A WHISTLE.
OH, BOY!
A WHISTLE!
I'M GOING TO WIN
[ other trains laugh]
WIN A WHISTLE?
HA-HA-HA.
THAT'S FUNNY.
THAT'S A GOOD ONE.
HA-HA-HA.
DON'T LAUGH AT AZUL.
YEAH, THAT'S NOT NICE.
THERE'S NO WAY
HE CAN BEAT US
TO THE BIG YELLOW
STATION. HA-HA.
NE-VER!
THEY'RE RIGHT.
I CAN'T WIN
THIS RACE.
I'M TOO LITTLE.
DON'T SAY THAT.
YOU CAN WIN.
YEAH, YOU CAN WIN.
WE'LL HELP YOU.
YOU WILL?
SURE! RIGHT?
RIGHT!
RIGHT?
WILL YOU HELP ME WIN THE RACE?
THEN I'LL DO IT!
I'LL RACE... AND I'LL WIN, TOO.
I'M GOING TO WIN A BIG WHISTLE.
Both:
YEAH!
HE DOESN'T EVEN KNOW HOW TO
GET TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION.
[ both laugh]
YOU KNOW HOW TO GET
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION,
DON'T YOU?
UH-OH.
HOW DO WE GET TO
THE BIG YELLOW STATION?
LET'S STOP AND THINK.
WHO CAN WE ASK FOR HELP
WHEN WE DON'T KNOW
WHICH WAY TO GO?
THE MAP, THE MAP!
THE MAP. THAT'S RIGHT.
THE MAP CAN TELL US
HOW TO GET
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
COULD YOU CHECK THE MAP
AND TELL ME WHAT IT SAYS?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "MAP."
SAY "MAP,"
SAY "MAP!"
Both:
LOUDER!
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GO ♪
♪ I'M THE ONE YOU NEED TO KNOW ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GET ♪
♪ I CAN GET YOU THERE, I BET ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP! ♪
DORA AND BOOTS WANT TO HELP
THE LITTLE BLUE TRAIN
GET TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION.
WELL, I KNOW HOW TO GET
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION.
FIRST, YOU GO OVER THE MOUNTAIN.
THEN, YOU GO THROUGH THE TUNNEL.
AND THAT'S HOW YOU GET
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION!
SO YOU TELL DORA.
MOUNTAIN...
TUNNEL...
BIG YELLOW STATION!
SAY IT WITH ME.
MOUNTAIN...
TUNNEL...
BIG YELLOW STATION!
MOUNTAIN...
TUNNEL...
BIG YELLOW STATION!
MOUNTAIN...
TUNNEL...
BIG YELLOW STATION!
HOW DO WE GET
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION?
MOUNTAIN...
TUNNEL...
BIG YELLOW STATION.
SO FIRST WE HAVE TO HELP
THE LITTLE BLUE TRAIN
GO OVER THE MOUNTAIN...
THEN WE GO THROUGH THE TUNNEL...
AND THAT'S HOW WE'LL GET
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION
TO WIN THE WHISTLE.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
SO FIRST WE HAVE TO
FIND THE MOUNTAIN.
DO YOU SEE
THE MOUNTAIN?
WHERE?
[ click, beep]
YEAH!
THERE'S
THE MOUNTAIN!
OVER THERE!
ALL ABOARD!
TRAINS, START YOUR ENGINES!
RUM-RUM-RUM!
VROOM-VROOM!
ON YOUR MARKS...
GET SET...
GO!
LET'S GO WIN THE BIG WHISTLE!
COME ON!
SAY IT WITH US!
Both:
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMANOS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT ♪
♪ I KNOW
THAT WE CAN DO IT ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE! ♪
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE ♪
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE ♪
All:
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE! ♪
[ laughing]
Dora and Boots:
♪ WIN THE WHISTLE! ♪
LOOK, IT'S THE MOUNTAIN!
WHOO, THAT'S
A BIG MOUNTAIN!
I CAN DO IT!
WELL, HERE WE GO.
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA... [ groaning]
WHEW...
OH, BOY.
THIS IS GOING
TO BE TOUGH!
HOW CAN WE HELP AZUL
OVER THE MOUNTAIN?
WE CAN CHEER.
GREAT IDEA!
WILL YOU HELP US CHEER
FOR AZUL?
GREAT!
LET'S ALL CHEER FOR AZUL.
CAN YOU SAY "AZUL?"
SAY IT WITH US!
Both:
AZUL, AZUL...
CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
AZUL, AZUL... YEAH!
WHEE...!
[ play happy tune]
YOU MADE IT
OVER THE MOUNTAIN!
THAT WAS GREAT!
I DID IT!
I DID IT, I REALLY DID IT!
THANKS... YOU REALLY HELPED ME.
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
MOUNTAIN...
TUNNEL...
BIG YELLOW STATION.
WE MADE IT OVER THE MOUNTAIN...
SO NEXT WE HAVE TO FIND THE...
[ click, beep]
TUNNEL, RIGHT!
I DON'T SEE IT.
DO YOU SEE THE TUNNEL?
[ click, beep]
THERE! THE TUNNEL,
THE TUNNEL!
COME ON,
WE'VE GOT TO HURRY
IF WE'RE GOING TO
WIN THE WHISTLE.
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHOO, CHOO! ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMANOS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT ♪
♪ I KNOW
THAT WE CAN DO IT ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE! ♪
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE ♪
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE ♪
All:
♪ TO WIN THE WHISTLE! ♪
[ laughing]
Dora and Boots:
♪ WIN THE WHISTLE! ♪
Boots:
THE TUNNEL!
ALL RIGHT!
I'M GOING TO WIN!
I'M GOING TO WIN THE WHISTLE.
AZUL, STOP!
[ brakes squeal]
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
THE TUNNEL IS DARK.
YEAH, WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO SEE WHERE WE'RE GOING.
OH, YEAH.
SO, WHAT DO WE DO?
MAYBE I HAVE SOMETHING
IN MY BACKPACK
THAT CAN HELP US
SEE IN THE DARK.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU CHECK MY BACKPACK
TO FIND SOMETHING
THAT WILL HELP US
SEE IN THE DARK?
YOU HAVE TO SAY
"BACKPACK."
SAY "BACKPACK,"
SAY "BACKPACK!"
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK,
BACKPACK ♪
♪ I'M THE BACKPACK, LOADED UP ♪
♪ WITH THINGS
AND KNICKKNACKS, TOO ♪
♪ ANYTHING THAT YOU MIGHT NEED ♪
♪ I GOT INSIDE FOR YOU ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK,
BACKPACK, YEAH! ♪
I HAVE LOTS OF STUFF
BUT DORA NEEDS TO FIND SOMETHING
TO HELP HER SEE IN THE DARK.
WILL THIS HELP DORA
SEE IN THE DARK?
[ click, beep]
IT WILL?
A FLASHLIGHT WILL HELP DORA
SEE IN THE DARK.
YOU'RE GOOD AT THIS!
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM,
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM.
DELICIOSO!
GRACIAS!
LET'S GO!
[ echoing]:
HEY, OUR VOICES SOUND REALLY
WEIRD IN THIS BIG TUNNEL!
[ deep voice]:
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
WHAT WAS THAT?
IT SOUNDED
LIKE ANOTHER TRAIN.
HEY, WHAT DO WE DO
IF ANOTHER TRAIN COMES
THROUGH THE TUNNEL?
YEAH, WE MIGHT BUMP
INTO EACH OTHER.
IF ANOTHER TRAIN COMES
WE'LL JUST WARN THEM
THAT WE'RE COMING, TOO.
OH, YEAH.
HOW DO WE DO THAT?
WE JUST BLOW OUR...
WHISTLE.
BUT I DON'T HAVE
A WHISTLE.
WE NEED YOUR HELP!
YOU CAN BE OUR LOOKOUT.
DO YOU SEE ANOTHER TRAIN
IN THE TUNNEL?
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
YOU DO?
YOU SEE ANOTHER TRAIN?
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
WE HAVE TO WARN THE OTHER TRAIN
THAT WE'RE COMING!
PULL YOUR WHISTLE AND SAY,
"CHOO-CHOO!"
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
AGAIN!
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
LOUDER!
Both:
CHOO-CHOO!
CHUGGA... WHOA...!
Both:
WHEW!
THAT WAS CLOSE.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
THANKS FOR THE WARNING.
I'D BETTER BACK UP
OUT OF THE TUNNEL
SO YOU CAN PASS.
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA.
[ play happy tune]
WE MADE IT
THROUGH THE TUNNEL!
YES!
YEAH!
HOO-BOY, YOU GAVE ME
QUITE A SCARE.
[ chuckles]
WHY WERE YOU GOING SO FAST?
Boots:
WE'RE IN A RACE
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION!
I'M TRYING TO WIN
A BIG WHISTLE.
OH, NOW, BIG WHISTLE--
THAT'S JUST WHAT YOU NEED.
WHOO! YOU BETTER HURRY!
THANKS!
AND THANKS FOR LETTING ME
GO BY.
Boots:
THANKS!
Dora:
GRACIAS!
HOPE YOU WIN THE WHISTLE.
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
[ brakes squeal]
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
MOUNTAIN...
TUNNEL...
BIG YELLOW STATION.
WE MADE IT OVER THE MOUNTAIN.
WE MADE IT THROUGH THE TUNNEL.
SO WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
[ click, beep]
THE BIG YELLOW STATION!
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW WHERE IS
THE BIG YELLOW STATION?
DO YOU SEE
[ click, beep]
Boots:
LOOK, THERE!
IT'S THE BIG YELLOW STATION!
LET'S GO!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
WE'RE ALMOST THERE!
Dora:
KEEP GOING, AZUL!
Boots:
LOOK, THERE'S THE BIG GREEN
TRAIN AND THE BIG RED TRAIN.
[ puffing]
WENT A LITTLE TOO FAST.
OH... GOT A LITTLE HOT.
JUST NEED A LITTLE REST.
I'M STILL GOING TO WIN.
Boots:
KEEP GOING, AZUL!
YOU'RE GOING GREAT!
CHUGGA-CHUGGA, CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA,
CHUGGA-CHUGGA
CHUGGA-CHUGGA...
Dora:
YAY, AZUL!
YOU'RE WINNING!
I'M GOING TO WIN!
I'M GOING TO WIN
THE WHISTLE!
NOTHING CAN STOP US NOW.
NOT EVEN SWIPER THE FOX.
I DON'T KNOW.
THAT FOX IS PRETTY SNEAKY.
HE'S ALWAYS TRYING
TO SWIPE OUR STUFF.
WE NEED YOUR HELP TO WATCH OUT
FOR SWIPER THE FOX.
IF YOU SEE THE FOX,
YELL "SWIPER!"
Dora:
WHAT'S THAT?
YOU SEE SWIPER?
GO FASTER, AZUL! FASTER!
HA-HA!
WE GOT AWAY FROM SWIPER.
WAY TO GO, AZUL.
WHAT'S THAT?
YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
RIGHT BEHIND US?
Boots:
I DON'T SEE HIM.
WHERE IS HE NOW?
OH, NO!
SWIPER'S GOING TO
TAKE AWAY
THE TRAIN TRACKS!
Dora:
IF SWIPER SWIPES
THE TRACKS
THEN WE CAN'T
FINISH THE RACE!
Both:
SWIPER, NO...
SWIPING...
YOU'RE TOO LATE!
YOU'LL NEVER
FIND THEM NOW.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND
THOSE TRACKS SO I CAN
WIN THE WHISTLE.
WE'LL FIND THEM.
WILL YOU HELP US
FIND THE MISSING TRACKS?
GREAT!
LET'S STOP AND THINK.
WHAT SHAPE WERE THE TRAIN TRACKS
THAT SWIPER TOOK?
A CIRCLE, A TRIANGLE,
OR A SQUARE?
A SQUARE, RIGHT!
WHAT COLOR WERE THEY?
BLUE, THAT'S RIGHT!
AZUL,LIKE ME.
NOW LET'S SEE HOW MANY
TRACKS ARE MISSING.
WILL YOU HELP US COUNT
THE MISSING TRACKS?
GREAT!
LET'S COUNT
THE MISSING TRACKS.
All:
ONE...
TWO...
THREE...
FOUR...
FIVE!
Dora:
SO WE HAVE TO LOOK
FOR FIVE BLUE SQUARES.
IS THIS A BLUE SQUARE?
RIGHT.
IT'S BLUE,
BUT IT'S NOT A SQUARE.
IS THIS A BLUE SQUARE?
RIGHT!
RIGHT.
IS THIS A BLUE SQUARE?
IT'S A SQUARE,
BUT IT'S NOT BLUE.
IS THIS BLUE SQUARE?
RIGHT.
IS THIS A BLUE SQUARE?
RIGHT!
NOW THAT YOU FOUND THEM
LET'S COUNT TO MAKE SURE THAT
WE FOUND ALL FIVE SQUARES.
All:
ONE...
TWO...
THREE...
FOUR...
FIVE!
Dora:
YAY!
YOU FOUND ALL FIVE SQUARES!
THANK YOU.
YOU HELPED US FIX
THE TRAIN TRACKS.
LET'S GO WIN
THE WHISTLE!
UH-OH, WE'RE
IN LAST PLACE AGAIN.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO GO
EXTRA EXTRA FAST!
CHEER WITH US!
Dora and Boots:
AZUL! AZUL! AZUL! AZUL!
LOUDER!
AZUL! AZUL! AZUL! AZUL!...
THE WINNER IS...
AZUL! AZUL! AZUL!
AZUL!
[ all cheering]
WE WON, WE WON!
OH, WOW, OH, WOW, OH, WOW!
THAT CAN'T BE!
THERE MUST BE
SOME MISTAKE!
THERE'S NO MISTAKE.
THE WINNER IS AZUL!
All:
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH!
AND HERE'S
YOUR PRIZE, AZUL.
A WHISTLE!
WOW, THAT'S
A BIG WHISTLE!
YEAH, I HOPE SWIPER
DOESN'T TRY AND SWIPE IT.
IF YOU SEE SWIPER,
YELL, "SWIPER!"
YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
OVER THERE?
HE'S GOING TO SWIPE
THE WHISTLE!
YOU HAVE TO SAY,
"SWIPER, NO SWIPING!"
All:
SWIPER, NO SWIPING!
OH, MAN!
All:
YAY!
THANKS.
HERE YOU GO, AZUL.
IT'S ALL YOURS.
TRY THE WHISTLE,
TRY THE WHISTLE!
CHOO-CHOO!
All:
WOW, WHAT A WHISTLE.
I COULDN'T HAVE WON WITHOUT YOU.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
WE DID IT!
Both:
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
YAY!
♪ LO HICIMOS!♪
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE WENT
OVER THE MOUNTAIN ♪
♪ AND THROUGH
THE TUNNEL, YEAH ♪
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE DID IT! HOORAY! ♪
♪ AZUL, AZUL, AZUL, AZUL! ♪
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE DID IT! WE DID IT!
WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE USED THE FLASHLIGHT
IN THE TUNNEL TO FIND THE WAY ♪
♪ SWIPER TOOK
SOME TRACKS ♪
♪ BUT WE FOUND THEM,
HOORAY! ♪
YEAH!
WHOO!
HOORAY!
Both:
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
CHOO-CHOO!
[ all laughing]
[ click, beep]
WE HAD SUCH
A FUN RACE TODAY!
WHAT WAS YOUR FAVORITE
PART OF THE RACE?
I LIKED THAT, TOO.
MY FAVORITE PART
WAS HELPING AZUL
WIN THE WHISTLE.
MY FAVORITE PART
WAS WHEN AZUL TOOTED
HIS BIG NEW WHISTLE.
CHOO-CHOO!
WE COULDN'T HAVE GOTTEN
TO THE BIG YELLOW STATION
WITHOUT YOU.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
[ click, beep]
Dora:
THIS IS MY FRIEND
ISA THE IGUANA.
[ click, beep]
FIND ISA!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
[Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ click, beep]
[ laughs]
[ giggles, laughs]