Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Do you like parties?
We're having a special party
for my friend Boots the monkey.
It's his birthday.
Now where is
that little monkey?
Do you see Boots?
Where?
Boots!
Dora!
It's my birthday.
I know.
Happy birthday, Boots.
I have a special
birthday surprise for you.
What is it, Dora?
A birthday party.
Yay!
A birthday party!
Yes, sir.
I can't wait to get
to my birthday party.
Come on, come on,
come on!
[ laughing]
Dora, am I going to have
balloons at my party?
Yes.
And party hats?
And goody bags?
Yes.
And party games?
And a birthday cake?
Yes!
It's in my backpack.
Ooh, ooh, ah, ah!
Can I see it?
I need your help.
Will you open my Backpack
and get Boots' birthday cake?
You have to say
"Backpack".
Say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iHola!
I have lots of stuff
but Dora needs you to find
Boots' birthday cake.
It's in a big square box.
Is this box shaped
like a square?
Oop, that's a rectangle.
Is this box shaped
like a square?
[ click, beep]
Right!
The big square box.
You found Boots' birthday cake!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Thanks!
Here, take a look.
Ooh... banana
birthday cake!
That's my favorite.
With banana icing.
Mmm, yum.
And look-- there's
a picture of me!
Ooh, ooh, ah, ah!
Feliz cumpleaños,Boots.
I wish you a happy birthday.
Ooh... Spanish!
Will you help me sing
"Feliz Cumpleaños"to Boots?
Great.
♪ Feliz cumpleaños♪
♪ Feliz cumpleaños.♪
Say feliz.
Good.
Now say cumpleaños.
Great.
Say feliz.
Good.
Now say cumpleaños.
Very good.
Now sing...
♪ Feliz cumpleaños♪
♪ Feliz cumpleaños ♪
♪ Feliz cumpleaños.♪
Very good!
Dora, how do we get
to my party?
It's at my house,
but we have to hurry.
All your friends
are waiting for you.
What's the quickest
way to your house?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map! The Map!
The Map, that's right.
I need your help
to check the Map
and find out the quickest way
to my house.
You have to say "Map".
Say "Map," say "Map"!
Louder!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora wants to know
the quickest way
to get to her house
for Boots' birthday party.
Well, I know the quickest way.
First you have to go
up the stairs...
then you go
over the Troll Bridge.
And that's how you get
to the party at Dora's house!
So you tell Dora.
Stairs...
bridge...
party house.
Say it with me:
Stairs...
bridge...
party house.
Stairs...
bridge...
party house.
Stairs...
bridge...
party house!
What's the quickest way to get
to my house for the party?
Stairs...
bridge...
party house.
First we have to go
up the stairs
then we go
over the Troll Bridge
and that's how we'll get
to the party at my house.
Thanks for helping.
So, first we have to go
up the stairs.
Do you see the stairs?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, they are!
iVamonos!
Come on, let's go.
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Stairs, bridge, party house!
Stairs, bridge,
party house!
Stairs, bridge, party house!
Stairs, bridge,
party house!
Happy, Happy Birthday!
Both:
Will you say "feliz cumpleaños"
with us?
Here we go...
Both:
♪ Feliz cumpleaños!♪
Very good!
iMuy bien!
Look, Dora.
Both:
Ooh, the stairs!
Come on, Dora,
we have to get
to my party.
[ clucking]
Do you hear that?
What animal
does that sound like?
[ clucking]
Yeah, sounds
like chickens.
[ clucking]
Better get
out of the way.
[ chickens clucking...]
Whoa!
That was close.
Come on.
[ neighing]
What animal does
that sound like?
[ neighing]
A horse!
Dora, we better run.
Oh, no, my cake!
I left my cake on the stairs!
[ horse neighing]
Wait, wait, wait!
We have to tell the horse
to wait before he steps
on my cake.
Dora:
That's Caballito.
He speaks Spanish.
We have to say espera.
Say esperawith us!
Both:
iEspera!
¿Espera?
He waited! Yes!
Thanks for saying espera.
You made
the little horse wait.
The cake's okay!
Lo siento.
No sabía que su biscocho
estaba en el escalón.
Caballito says he's sorry.
He didn't know your cake
was on the step.
It's my birthday.
Hoy es su cumpleaños.
Oh... iFeliz cumpleaños!
[ play happy tune]
We made it up the stairs.
Yes! Where do we
go next?
Stairs, bridge, party house.
We made it up the stairs,
so next we have to go over...
[ click, beep]
The bridge, right!
Now, where is
the Troll Bridge?
Do you see a bridge?
[ click, beep]
Right! There it is!
Let's go!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Stairs, bridge, party house!
Stairs, bridge,
party house!
Stairs, bridge, party house!
Stairs, bridge,
party house!
Happy, happy birthday!
Both:
♪ Feliz cumpleaños!♪
Good singing.
[ rustling]
Oh, no! That sounds like
Swiper the sneaky fox.
That sneaky fox is always
trying to swipe our stuff.
He'll try to swipe
your birthday cake.
My cake! My cake!
I need your help
to watch out for Swiper.
If you see Swiper the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
Do you see Swiper the fox?
Where?
I don't see him.
Me neither.
Where?
Right behind us?
Both:
Swiper, no...
swiping...
You're too late.
You'll never find it now.
[ laughing]
My cake!
Don't worry, Boots,
we can find it.
There are so many
places it could be.
Let's stop and think.
What shape is the box?
It's square, right.
What color
is the cake box?
Yellow, right!
So, let's look for
all the yellow squares.
Do you see
a yellow square?
Here?
[ click, beep]
Boots:
That's a square,
but that's not my cake box.
Where's my cake box?
Dora:
Find another
yellow square.
Boots:
Is that a square?
[ click, beep]
Right, it's a square
and it's my cake box!
Dora:
You found Boots' cake.
My cake!
Good looking.
Thanks.
Look!
The Troll Bridge.
Come on, Dora,
we're almost to my party.
Whoa!
Both:
It's the grumpy old troll.
♪ I'm the grumpy old troll
who lives under the bridge ♪
♪ Hey, I'm the grumpy old troll
♪ Who's there? ♪
♪ If you want to come over ♪
♪ All you have to do is this ♪
♪ All you have to do
is this... ♪
Solve my riddle!
No one gets over
my bridge!
But I have to get
over the bridge.
It's my birthday.
I have to get
to my party.
No one gets
over my bridge
unless they solve
my riddle.
I have a riddle and
you can't be wrong.
Do you know the Spanish
happy birthday song?
You hear that, Boots?
We've got to solve
the troll's riddle.
Will you help us solve
the troll's riddle?
Great!
The riddle goes like this--
I have a riddle
and you can't be wrong.
Do you know the Spanish
happy birthday song?
What's the Spanish
Both:
"iFeliz Cumpleaños!"
Right! Everybody
loves that song.
Sing "Feliz Cumpleaños"
with us.
[ music playing]
♪ iFeliz cumpleaños!♪
[ music continues...]
Sing louder!
Both:
♪ iFeliz cumpleaños!♪
All right, you solved my riddle.
Come on, monkey.
You and your friend
can go over my bridge.
Both:
Yay!
Thanks for helping.
[ play happy tune]
We made it
over the Troll Bridge.
All right!
Where do we go next?
Stairs, bridge, party house!
We went up the stairs
we went over the bridge
so now we go to the...
[ click, beep]
Both:
Party house!
But I don't see
your house.
Do you see Dora's house?
[ click, beep]
Both:
There it is!
Let's go!
iVamonos!
Look, there's my mommy.
Hola, Mamá.
Hola, Dora!
Hola, Boots.
Hello, Señora Marquez.
It's my birthday.
I know.
♪ iFeliz cumpleaños!♪
Oh, Dora, is that Boots's cake?
I'll take it inside.
Boots, wait out here
for a second.
I want you
to be surprised.
Oh, I love surprises!
Come on.
You can help me.
All:
Hi, Dora!
Boots' friends are here.
Tico the Squirrel,
Isa the Iguana,
and Benny the Bull.
Quick, everybody listen.
Boots is waiting outside.
We have to put out
six party hats and
six goody bags.
We'll have to
count them out.
Let's count out
the party hats first.
Count with us.
Together:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six.
Great.
Now we need six goody bags.
Count with Isa.
Together:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six.
Good counting!
Thanks for helping.
Can I come in now?
Wait! Wait!
I'm waiting!
Okay, everybody, listen up.
I thought of a way we can
really surprise Boots.
I call it my surprise jump.
It goes like this.
You bend your knees
and crouch down
into a little ball
then jump up
and yell "Surprise!"
I need everybody
to do the surprise jump
so we can surprise Boots.
Will you do the surprise jump
with us
and help us surprise Boots?
Great!
First we got to practice.
Everybody has to stand up
to do the surprise jump.
Get ready to stand up.
Stand up, please.
Stand up!
Up, up, up!
First you have
to bend your knees
and crouch down
into a little ball
Crouch down!
Now jump up
and yell "surprise!"
Surprise!
iSorpresa!
Great! Okay.
Get ready to do
my surprise jump again
because we're going to
let Boots in now.
So crouch down.
Okay, on the count of three
everybody jump up
and yell "surprise!"
Ready?
One, two, three!
Surprise!
iSorpresa!
Oh, I'm so surprised!
Balloons!
Goody bags!
A piñata!
Birthday presents!
Party games!
It's time for the piñata!
iUno, dos, tres!
Tico:
iDale, Boots, dale!
Whack it, Boots!
Yeah, knock the candy
out of it!
[ cheering]
My cake! My cake!
And look!
The candle is
shaped like a banana!
My favorite!
Okay, everybody.
It's time to sing
"Feliz Cumpleaños"to Boots.
Sing it with us.
♪ iFeliz cumpleaños!♪
Okay, Boots,
blow out the candle
so we can eat!
[ others laugh]
Make a wish first.
[ cheering]
Bravo! Bravo!
[ whispers]:
I wished that
we can play together
every day
for ever and ever!
Oh, Boots!
We can! We can!
Oh, Dora! This is the best
birthday party I ever had!
Both:
We did it!
[ music playing]
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
Lo hicimos.
Both:
We did it!
♪ We went up the stairs and
across the bridge, yeah ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it. Hooray! ♪
♪ We made it to my party
at Dora's house, yeah ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We saw
a grumpy old troll ♪
♪ along the way ♪
♪ Swiper took our cake
but we found it, hooray. ♪
Yay!
Whoo!
Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such an exciting
trip to my house
for Boots' party today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part was when
you all yelled "Surprise!"
I was so surprised!
My favorite part was when
we sang "Feliz Cumpleaños"
to the grumpy old troll
and got him to dance.
We couldn't have gotten
to the party without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
Dora:
Ooh, Swiper the fox.
Find Swiper.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Ooh!
[ rustling]
Whoop!
Zoop!
[ rustling]
[ laughing]
[ click, beep]
Oh, man!
[ giggles, laughs]