Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Splish!
Splash!
Sploosh!
Hi, I'm Dora.
I'm pretending to swim.
I'm Dora the Swimmer.
Today I'm going swimming
at the beach.
Hey! Who's this?
He's bouncy and furry
and very, very ticklish.
[ laughing]
Boots!
Dora!
Hey, Boots,
do you want to go
swimming with me
at the beach?
Oh, oh, yeah, yeah!
Swimming, swimming,
swimming!
But... I'm not
a very good swimmer.
That's why I brought you
a special present.
I need your help
to open my Backpack
so I can give Boots his present.
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
Say "Backpack!"
Both:
louder!
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
I have lots of stuff!
But you need to find
Boots' present.
It's got a red bow on it.
Is this Boots' present?
[ click, beep]
Right! You found it!
iMuy bien!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
What is it, Dora?
Wait, let me blow it up.
A floaty!
You like it?
I love my new floaty!
I can use the floaty
to swim.
Aw, Boots...
Let's put it
in the Backpack
until we get
to the beach.
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Both:
To the beach!
But, Dora...
how do we get
to the beach?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask
for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
Map, Map, Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us
how to get to the beach.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find out
how to get to the beach?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map,"
say "Map!"
I think you have to
say it again.
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to
get to the beach.
Well, I know how to
get to the beach!
First, you have to go over
these big hills of yellow sand
called sand dunes!
Then you go down this wooden
bridge called a boardwalk.
And that's how you
get to the beach.
So you tell Dora:
Dunes, boardwalk, beach!
Say it with me:
Dunes, boardwalk, beach.
Dunes, boardwalk, beach!
Dunes, boardwalk, beach...!
How do we get to the beach?
Dunes...
boardwalk...
beach.
We go through
the yellow sand dunes...
then down the boardwalk...
and then we get to the beach!
All right!
Thank you.
Okay, so first
we have to get to
the yellow sand dunes.
Do you see
the yellow sand dunes?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, I see them,
I see them!
The sand dunes,
the sand dunes!
Come on, let's go
swimming at the beach!
Say it with us.
Both:
Dunes, boardwalk, beach!
Dunes, boardwalk,
beach!
Dunes, boardwalk, beach!
Dunes, boardwalk,
beach!
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ To the beach ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ To the beach ♪
All:
♪ To the beach! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ To the beach! ♪
[ rustling]
Did you hear that?
We better watch out
for Swiper the fox.
Swiper's always trying
to swipe our stuff.
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
What did you say?
You see Swiper?
Where?
Behind the tree?
I don't see him.
Where?
Behind the bush?
Both:
It's the fox!
Dora:
Uh-oh!
He's sneaking up on our friend
Tico the squirrel!
Boots:
He's going to swipe his icy!
Watch out!
Boots, Tico
speaks Spanish!
We have to
say "cuidado."
To tell him "watch out,"
I need your help
to tell Tico "cuidado."
Can you say "cuidado"?
Say "cuidado"!
[ slurping]
¿Cuidado?
Help us stop Swiper.
You have to say
"Swiper, no swiping."
Say it with us.
Both:
Swiper, no swiping!
Swiper,
no swiping!
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Gracias.
De nada.
Come on, Boots.
Let's go swimming
at the beach.
Swimming, swimming,
swimming!
Boots, it's
the yellow sand dunes.
We made it!
And look, the dunes really
are big hills of sand.
Whoa!
There are three
different paths.
A blue path...
a red path...
and a yellow path.
We need to figure out
which path to take
to get
through the dunes.
Blue, blue, blue, blue
blue!
Ow!
Benny, what
are you doing?
I'm trying to get
through these dunes.
Blue, blue, blue, blue, blue!
Ow!
Benny, let's
stop and think.
This blue path doesn't go
all the way through the dunes
so it's either the red path
or the yellow path.
But, Dora,
how do we know
which path to take?
Who can we ask for help when
we don't know which way to go?
Map, Map, Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us
which path to take
to get through the dunes.
I need your help.
Will you check
the Map for us
and find out
which path to take?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map,"
say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Hello, again.
You need to tell Dora
how to get through the dunes!
Which path goes all the way
through the dunes?
Let's trace the paths and see.
Blue...
Red...
Crabs, crabs,
crabs!
Yellow!
Which path leads
through the dunes?
[ click, beep]
That's right!
The yellow path!
Tell Dora to take
the yellow path!
Which path should we take?
[ click, beep]
Yellow?
Thanks!
Red, red!
Red, red, red!
Oh, Benny, wait!
You're going down
the wrong path!
Help us stop Benny!
Yell "Stop, Benny!"
Both:
Stop, Benny!
Red, red, red!
Both:
Crabs, crabs, crabs!
Crabs!
Both:
Wrong path!
Which is the right path
through the dunes?
[ click, beep]
The yellow path, right!
We made it past
the yellow sand dunes!
[ play happy tune]
Both:
Yay! All right!
Thanks for helping.
Now that I know the way
I'm going to play again!
Where do we go next?
Dunes...
boardwalk...
beach!
We made it past
the yellow sand dunes
so next we have to find...
[ click, beep]
The boardwalk, right!
Now, where's
the boardwalk?
Do you see the boardwalk?
Yeah!
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the boardwalk.
Let's go.
Vámonos!
Say it with us.
Both:
Dunes, boardwalk, beach!
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ To the beach ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ To the beach ♪
All:
♪ To the beach! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ To the beach! ♪
Hey, there's
the boardwalk.
But how are we going to
get up on the boardwalk?
It's too high,
it's too high!
I can't reach!
Hey, look!
We can climb up
the net ladder
to get
onto the boardwalk.
Will you help us climb
the net ladder
up onto the boardwalk?
Great!
First, put your hands
up in the air over your head.
Now grab the net ladder
with both hands.
Hold on tight.
Now climb!
Climb, climb, climb,
climb, climb, climb!
The boardwalk!
We made onto the boardwalk!
And look...
the boardwalk's really
made of boards!
Say it with us!
Both:
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on, let's get to it ♪
♪ I know that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ To the beach ♪
Both:
♪ To the beach! ♪
Whoa...!
Boots, watch out!
The boardwalk is
missing some boards.
But we have to go
down the boardwalk...
Both:
So we can go swimming
at the beach.
Do you see anything we can use
to fix the boardwalk?
What do you see?
Those boards?
Great idea!
Let's see how many boards
we need.
Count the holes with me.
Both:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven!
Seven.
So we need seven boards.
Count out seven boards with us.
Both:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven!
Good counting!
Now count one more time
to fill all the holes
in the boardwalk.
Both:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven!
Yay! You fixed
the boardwalk!
Good counting.
[ play happy tune]
Where do we go next?
Dunes...
boardwalk...
beach.
We made it past
the yellow sand dunes...
we went down the boardwalk...
so next comes...
[ click, beep]
The beach,
the beach!
Right!
Do you see the beach?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's the beach!
Come on!
Let's go swimming
at the beach!
Swimming, swimming,
swimming!
Hey, Dora, can I put on
my floaty?
Can I, can I?
Sure, and I'll put on
my bathing suit
and get my beach towel.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack?
I need Boots' floaty,
my bathing suit and my towel.
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack"!
♪ Backpack, Backpack! ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
Hello again.
Do you see Boots' floaty?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Right!
Do you see Dora's bathing suit?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Right again!
Do you see Dora's towel?
[ click, beep]
Yes!
You're really good at this!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
My floaty!
Your towel!
[ both laugh]
Now I can go swimming!
Both:
To the beach!
Remember to yell "Swiper"
if you see the fox.
Both:
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ To the beach ♪
Both:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ To the beach ♪
All:
♪ To the beach! ♪
Swiper:
Whoop!
What's that?
You see Swiper?
Right behind us?!
Both:
Swiper, no...
Zoop!
...swiping.
You're too late!
[ laughs]
You'll never find it now.
My floaty!
Aw, Boots...
It's okay.
We'll find it.
Will you help us find
Boots' floaty?
Great!
Let's stop and think.
What shape is the floaty?
Right, round like a circle.
What color is the floaty?
It's green
with yellow polka dots.
Now let's look for the floaty.
It's round like a circle.
Boots:
It's green with
yellow polka dots.
[ click, beep]
Dora:
That's not the floaty.
Well, let's keep looking.
Boots:
Yeah, let's keep looking.
Dora:
Is this Boots' floaty?
[ click, beep]
Here it is!
Boots:
It's my floaty!
You found it!
Thank you, thank you,
thank you!
Come on, come on!
I want to go
swimming!
Hola,Dora.
Hi, Boots.
Hi, Lifeguard!
Will you watch us swim?
Sure!
Come on, come on!
I want to go swimming
with my new floaty.
Boots, your boots.
Both:
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
Ooch, ouch, hot, hot, hot...
Aah...
Hey, look who's here!
Hot, hot, hot, hot,
hot, hot, hot!
Hot, hot, hot,
Cool!
[ laughs]
I hope Tico comes,
I hope Tico comes!
Tico!
Boots!
Look, Dora, I'm swimming
with my new floaty!
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
Yay!
♪ Lo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We walked
through the dunes ♪
♪ to get
to the beach ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
Both:
♪ We did it!
Hooray! ♪
♪ We walked on the boardwalk
to get to the beach ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
Both:
♪ Swiper swiped my floaty
along the way ♪
♪ We took the yellow path ♪
♪ We made it! ♪
Both:
♪ Hooray! ♪
Yay!
Whoo!
Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such a fun trip
to the beach today.
What was your favorite part
of the trip?
I liked that, too.
What was your favorite
part of the trip, Boots?
My favorite part was
when you gave me the floaty.
saving Tico from Swiper
by saying "cuidado."
"Cuidado"means
"watch out" in Spanish.
We couldn't have made it
to the beach without you.
Thanks for helping.
Gracias.
[ click, beep]
Dora:
It's the Grumpy Old Troll.
Find the Grumpy Old Troll.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Whoa!
Gotcha!
Aah!
[ laughs]
Whoa!
Hey!
Whoo!
Whoa!
[ laughs]
Uh-oh!
[ click, beep]
Whoo, whoo, whoo...
I can't believe you got me!
Ah, you got me!
[ giggles, laughs]