Boots:
DORA!
Dora:
BOOTS!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Kids:
♪ D-D-D-D-D-DORA♪
LET'S GO.
♪ DORA, DORA, DORA
THE EXPLORER♪
DORA!
♪ BOOTS AND SUPERCOOL
EXPLORADORA. ♪
Dora:
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
Boots:
GRAB YOUR BACKPACK!
♪ LET'S GO, JUMP IN...♪
VAMONOS!
♪ YOU CAN LEAD THE WAY♪
HEY! HEY!
♪ D-D-DORA, D-D-D-DORA♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING!♪
OH, MAN!
HI, I'M DORA.
I'M BOOTS.
[ pig squealing]
OINK, OINK, OINK.
WHAT ANIMALS GO
"OINK, OINK, OINK"?
PIGS-- RIGHT.
YEAH, YEAH.
PIGS, PIGS!
[ laughing]
BOOTS AND I ARE
AT THE FARM.
WE CAME TO VISIT
THE THREE
LITTLE PIGGIES.
WHERE ARE THE PIGGIES?
I DON'T KNOW,
BOOTS.
DO YOU SEE
THE PIGGIES?
WHERE?
YEAH! THERE ARE
THE PIGGIES!
I'M GOING TO PET
BOOTS, MAKE SURE
YOU CLOSE THE GATE
SO THE LITTLE PIGGIES
WON'T GET OUT.
I NEED YOUR HELP TO REMIND
BOOTS TO CLOSE THE GATE.
Dora:
DID BOOTS FORGET
TO CLOSE THE GATE?
YOU HAVE TO SHOUT "GATE"!
WHAT?
THE GATE?
DID I LEAVE THE GATE OPEN?
OH, THANKS.
WHAT?
I DID CLOSE THE GATE.
OOPS.
I'VE GOT IT.
THANKS!
HEY, PIGGIES!
AW, PIGGIES!
[ giggling]
OINK!
OINKY!
OINKY! OINKY!
HEY, DORA, LOOK!
THAT LITTLE PIGGY REALLY
LIKES YOU, BOOTS!
OINKY,
OINKY!
I'M GOING TO CALL
YOU "OINKY."
OINKY,
OINKY!
WE'VE BROUGHT A PRESENT
FOR THE LITTLE PIGGIES:
BLUE RIBBONS.
OINK!
OINKY!
[ laughing]
THE BLUE RIBBONS
ARE IN MY BACKPACK.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU OPEN MY BACKPACK
AND GET THE BLUE RIBBONS
FOR THE LITTLE PIGGIES?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "BACKPACK."
SAY "BACKPACK,"
SAY "BACKPACK."
I THINK YOU HAVE
TO SAY IT AGAIN.
♪ ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK
♪ I'M A BACKPACK LOADED UP WITH
THINGS AND KNICKKNACKS, TOO ♪
♪ ANYTHING THAT YOU MIGHT NEED
I GOT INSIDE FOR YOU. ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK.
YEAH!
I HAVE LOTS OF RIBBONS.
BUT DORA WANTS YOU
TO FIND THE BLUE RIBBONS
FOR THE LITTLE PIGGIES.
ARE THESE THE BLUE RIBBONS?
ALL RIGHT!
YOU'VE FOUND
THE BLUE RIBBONS!
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM!
DELICIOSO!
HERE'S YOUR
PRESENT,
PIGGIES.
BLUE RIBBONS FOR BEING
SUCH GREAT PIGGIES!
OINK.
OINKY!
LET'S COUNT TOGETHER
AND PUT THE BLUE RIBBONS
ON THE PIGGIES.
COUNT WITH US.
Dora and Boots:
ONE.
TWO...
THREE!
OINK!
OINKY!
[ pigs squealing]
WHAT'S THAT NOISE?
BOOTS, I THINK WE
BETTER WATCH OUT
FOR SWIPER THE FOX.
THAT SNEAKY FOX--
HE'S GOING TO
TRY AND SWIPE
THE BLUE RIBBONS.
[ pigs squealing]
WILL YOU HELP US WATCH OUT
FOR SWIPER THE FOX?
GREAT.
IF YOU SEE THE FOX,
YELL "SWIPER!"
YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
I DON'T
SEE HIM.
[ pigs squealing]
WHERE?
OH, NO!
SWIPER'S GOING
TO SWIPE
THOSE RIBBONS.
WE NEED YOUR HELP
TO STOP SWIPER.
YOU HAVE TO SAY,
"SWIPER, NO SWIPING."
SAY IT WITH US.
SWIPER, NO SWIPING.
OH, MAN!
THANKS FOR HELPING US
STOP SWIPER.
YEAH, HE WAS
GOING TO SWIPE
THE PIGGIES'
RIBBONS.
OH-OH...
SWIPER LEFT
THE GATE OPEN.
OH, NO!
OINKY'S
GETTING AWAY.
ALL THE PIGGIES
ARE GETTING AWAY.
STOP, PIGGIES, STOP.
COME BACK,
LITTLE PIGGIES.
OINKY, WAIT!
COME ON, BOOTS.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND
THOSE PIGGIES
BEFORE SWIPER DOES.
YEAH, WE HAVE
TO SAVE THE PIGGIES.
LET'S CHECK THE MAP
TO FIND OUT
WHERE THE PIGGIES
ARE GOING.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU CHECK THE MAP
TO FIND OUT WHERE
THE PIGGIES ARE GOING?
YOU HAVE TO SAY, "MAP."
SAY, "MAP,"
SAY, "MAP."
LOUDER.
♪ ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GO ♪
♪ I'M THE ONE YOU NEED TO KNOW
♪ I'M THE MAP
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GET ♪
♪ I CAN GET YOU THERE, I BET
♪ I'M THE MAP
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
I'M THE MAP!
DORA AND BOOTS NEED TO FIND
THE THREE LITTLE PIGGIES
BEFORE SWIPER SWIPES
THEIR RIBBONS.
WELL, I KNOW WHERE THE THREE
LITTLE PIGGIES WENT.
ONE LITTLE PIGGY WENT
TO THE HAYFIELD.
ONE LITTLE PIGGY
WENT TO THE BARN.
AND THE LITTLEST PIGGY WENT
"WEE, WEE, WEE, WEE"
ALL THE WAY TO THE APPLE TREE.
SO YOU TELL DORA, "HAY,"
"BARN," "APPLE TREE."
SAY IT WITH ME.
HAY.
BARN.
APPLE TREE.
HAY.
BARN.
APPLE TREE.
HAY.
BARN.
APPLE TREE.
SO WHERE DO WE GO TO FIND
THE THREE LITTLE PIGGIES?
HAY.
BARN.
APPLE TREE.
ONE LITTLE PIGGY WENT
TO THE HAYFIELD.
ONE LITTLE PIGGY
WENT TO THE BARN.
AND THE LITTLEST PIGGY
WENT "WEE, WEE, WEE, WEE"
ALL THE WAY TO THE APPLE TREE.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
SO FIRST WE HAVE TO GO
TO THE HAYFIELD.
DO YOU SEE
THE HAYFIELD?
WHERE?
YEAH, THERE IT IS.
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US.
HAY, BARN, APPLE TREE.
♪ ♪
Dora and Boots:
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO.
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT. ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING?
♪ APPLE TREE.
♪ WHERE ARE
WE GOING? ♪
♪ APPLE TREE.
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING?
♪ APPLE TREE.♪
All:
[ laughing]
♪ APPLE TREE.
WE MADE IT
TO THE HAYFIELD
BUT I DON'T SEE
THE LITTLE PIGGY.
WHERE COULD THE
PIGGY BE HIDING?
WHERE?
YEAH, LOOK.
THE HAY IS MOVING.
WILL YOU HELP US FIND
THE LITTLE PIGGY IN THE HAY?
GREAT.
MOO!
BAA.
OINK,
OINK.
MOO!
BAA.
OINK,
OINK.
Dora:
WHERE'S THE PIGGY?
OINK,
OINK.
Dora:
YOU'VE FOUND THE PIGGY!
[ fanfare]
[ Boots cheering]
COME HERE, LITTLE PIGGY.
[ squealing]
SHE STILL HAS
HER RIBBON.
GOOD THING WE FOUND HER
BEFORE SWIPER DID.
OOH, SWIPER THE FOX.
HOW MANY PIGGIES
ARE STILL MISSING,
DORA?
THERE ARE THREE PIGGIES.
WE FOUND ONE IN THE HAYFIELD.
SO HOW MANY ARE STILL MISSING?
RIGHT, TWO PIGGIES
ARE STILL MISSING.
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT, DORA?
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
HAY.
BARN.
APPLE TREE.
WE LOOKED IN THE HAY.
SO NEXT WE HAVE TO GO TO...
THE BARN, RIGHT.
NOW, WHERE'S
THE BARN?
DO YOU SEE
YEAH, I SEE IT.
THERE'S THE BARN!
LET'S GO!
COME ON,
SAY IT WITH US.
HAY, BARN, APPLE TREE.
♪ ♪
Dora and Boots:
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO.
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT. ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING?
♪ APPLE TREE.
♪ WHERE ARE
WE GOING? ♪
♪ APPLE TREE.
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING?
♪ APPLE TREE.♪
All:
♪ APPLE TREE.
[ squealing]
AW... DO YOU WANT ME
TO PICK YOU UP?
[ oinking]
COME HERE.
OOH, YOU'RE
A HEAVY LITTLE PIGGY.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO HELP, BOOTS?
[ straining]
I CAN DO IT.
I CAN DO IT!
BOOTS, THE PIGGY'S
TOO HEAVY TO CARRY
TO THE BARN.
WE NEED TO FIND SOMETHING
TO CARRY THE PIGGY
TO THE BARN.
DO YOU SEE ANYTHING
WE CAN USE
TO CARRY THE PIGGY
TO THE BARN?
WHAT CAN WE USE?
THE WAGON?
THE WAGON--
GREAT IDEA!
WE CAN PUT THE PIGGY
IN THE WAGON.
COME ON, BOOTS
LET'S GET THIS WAGON
TO THE BARN.
RIGHT!
OH, NO,
THE WAGON'S GONE.
WHICH WAY DID
THE WAGON GO?
THAT WAY?
Both:
OH, NO!
[ oinking]
Boots:
THE WAGON IS ROLLING RIGHT
TOWARDS THE GATE!
Dora:
THERE'S TICO THE SQUIRREL.
WE HAVE TO TELL TICO
TO OPEN THE GATE
SO THE WAGON DOESN'T
CRASH INTO IT.
OPEN, PLEASE, OPEN!
BOOTS, REMEMBER,
TICO SPEAKS SPANISH
SO WE HAVE TO SAY ABRE!
SAY ABRE!
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
ABRE!
LOUDER!
Both:
ABRE!
ABRE?
SI!
WHEW!
THANKS FOR HELPING.
THANKS, TICO.
GRACIAS.
DE NADA.
[ hens cackling]
ARE YOU OKAY,
PIGGY?
[ oinking]
SHE'S OKAY.
LOOK! WE MADE IT
TO THE BARN.
GREAT.
NOW WE CAN FIND
THE SECOND PIGGY.
I DON'T SEE HER.
[ oinking]
WHAT WAS THAT?
WAS THAT THE PIGGY?
YEAH, IT'S THE PIGGY,
IT'S THE PIGGY!
IT SOUNDS LIKE SHE'S
HIDING INSIDE THE BARN.
COME ON, LET'S LOOK.
[ animals calling]
I HEAR LOTS OF ANIMALS
IN THE BARN.
[ animals calling]
DORA, HOW ARE WE GOING
TO FIND THE PIGGY?
LET'S LISTEN TO THE ANIMAL
SOUNDS
TO FIND WHERE THE PIGGY
IS HIDING.
LISTEN.
MOO.
OINK, OINK.
BAA.
QUACK, QUACK, QUACK.
MOO.
OINK, OINK.
BAA.
QUACK, QUACK, QUACK.
WHERE IS THE PIGGY
HIDING?
SHE'S BEHIND THE HAY.
BAA.
NO, THAT'S THE SHEEP.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE
THE PIGGY'S HIDING?
[ arrow beeps]
[ oinking]
YOU'RE RIGHT.
HERE SHE IS.
COME HERE,
LITTLE PIGGY.
[ oinking]
WE FOUND THE SECOND PIGGY.
YAY!
LOOK, DORA
SWIPER DIDN'T SWIPE
HER RIBBON.
[ both oinking]
DON'T WORRY,
LITTLE PIGGIES
WE WON'T LET SWIPER THE FOX
SWIPE YOUR RIBBONS.
OKAY, BOOTS, THERE ARE
THREE PIGGIES.
WE FOUND ONE IN THE HAYFIELD,
ONE IN THE BARN.
HOW MANY PIGGIES ARE MISSING?
ONE.
RIGHT.
AND I KNOW WHO IT IS.
IT'S...
Both:
OINKIE!
BOOTS, COME ON.
WE'D BETTER HURRY UP
AND FIND OINKIE.
YEAH, WE HAVE TO FIND
OINKIE BEFORE SWIPER DOES.
MOO.
BAA.
QUACK, QUACK, QUACK.
WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
HAY...
BARN...
APPLE TREE.
WE LOOKED IN THE HAY
AND WE LOOKED IN THE BARN
SO THAT MEANS THE LAST LITTLE
PIGGY MUST BE HIDING AT THE...
APPLE TREE.
RIGHT!
WHERE'S THE APPLE TREE, DORA?
DO YOU SEE
THE APPLE TREE?
WHERE?
YEAH, THERE IT IS.
COME ON, BOOTS
WE HAVE TO FIND
OINKIE
BEFORE SWIPER SWIPES
HIS RIBBON.
WE'RE COMING, OINKIE,
WE'RE COMING.
[ both oinking]
[ both groaning]
COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON.
OH, NO!
WE'RE STUCK IN THE MUD.
DORA, WE HAVE TO
PULL THE WAGON
OUT OF THE MUD
OR WE CAN'T
SAVE OINKIE.
WILL YOU HELP US PULL THE WAGON
OUT OF THE MUD?
GREAT.
PUT YOUR HANDS OUT
IN FRONT OF YOU
GRAB THE HANDLE
WITH BOTH HANDS.
HOLD ON TIGHT.
NOW PULL! PULL!
PULL! PULL! PULL! PULL!
PULL!
ALL RIGHT!
WE PULLED THE WAGON
OUT OF THE MUD.
[ cheering]
[ oinking]
GREAT PULLING.
YOU'RE STRONG!
OKAY, BOOTS
LET'S GO FIND OINKIE
AT THE APPLE TREE.
WELL, THERE'S
THE APPLE TREE.
BUT WHERE'S OINKIE?
DO YOU SEE OINKIE?
RIGHT.
THERE HE IS.
OH, NO!
WHAT'S HE DOING
IN THE TREE?
Dora:
HE'S EATING APPLES.
[ gulps]
OINKIE, COME DOWN,
OINKIE, COME DOWN!
[ branch creaking]
OH, NO, THE BRANCH
IS BREAKING!
OINKIE'S GOING TO FALL!
[ branch creaking]
[ oinking]
WILL YOU HELP US SAVE OINKIE?
WE ALL HAVE TO SAY
"HOLD ON, OINKIE!"
Both:
HOLD ON, OINKIE!
SAY IT AGAIN.
Both:
HOLD ON, OINKIE!
[ branch creaking]
I HAVE SOMETHING
IN MY BACKPACK
WE CAN USE
TO CATCH OINKIE.
I NEED YOURHELP
TO OPEN MY BACKPACK.
HURRY!
YOU HAVE TO SAY
"BACKPACK."
SAY, "BACKPACK,"
SAY, "BACKPACK."
[ zippy music begins playing]
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK
♪ YEAH!
WE'D BETTER HURRY.
RAPIDO!
DORA NEEDS US TO FIND SOMETHING
WE CAN USE TO CATCH THE PIGGY.
WILL THIS WORK?
WILL THIS?
[ arrow beeps]
A NET WILL CATCH THE PIGGY.
GOOD IDEA.
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM,
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM.
DELICIOSO.
GOT IT!
Boots:
HE'S FALLING!
RUN, DORA, RUN!
YOU SAVED HIM!
AWESOME, DORA.
[ both oinking]
THANK YOU
FOR HELPING
US SAVE OINKIE.
DID WE FIND
ALL THREE
PIGGIES?
LET'S COUNT THEM
TOGETHER.
COUNT WITH ME.
Both:
ONE... TWO... THREE.
YES, THREE PIGGIES.
NOW LET'S COUNT
THE RIBBONS.
Both:
ONE... TWO... THREE.
ALL RIGHT.
WE FOUND ALL
THREE PIGGIES
AND ALL THREE RIBBONS.
NOW WE JUST HAVE TO...
[ rustling]
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
IT SOUNDED
LIKE SWIPER.
[ oinking]
DO YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
THERE HE IS!
[ oinking]
HELP US STOP SWIPER.
SAY "SWIPER, NO SWIPING."
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
SWIPER, NO SWIPING.
OH, MAN!
YOU DID IT!
YOU STOPPED SWIPER!
WAY TO GO!
THANKS FOR HELPING US
STOP SWIPER.
HERE WE ARE,
LITTLE PIGGIES
BACK HOME, SAFE AND SOUND.
[ laughing]
Both:
WE DID IT!
[ music begins]
Both:
WE DID IT!
YAY!
LO HICIMOS!
♪ WE DID IT.
♪ ♪
Boots:
♪ WE FOUND THE PIGGIES
♪ WE SAVED THEM FROM SWIPER
♪ YEAH, WE DID IT, WE DID IT,
WE DID IT! HOORAY! ♪
♪ OINKIE FELL FROM
THE APPLE TREE ♪
♪ BUT WE CAUGHT HIM
♪ WE DID IT, WE DID IT,
WE DID IT ♪
♪ THE WAGON ALMOST CRASHED
INTO THE GATE ♪
♪ SWIPER TRIED TO TAKE THE
RIBBONS, BUT HE WAS TOO LATE! ♪
YAY! WOO! HOORAY!
WE DID IT!
WOO!
[ arrow beeps]
WE HAD SUCH AN EXCITING TIME
LOOKING FOR THE PIGGIES TODAY.
WHAT WAS YOUR FAVORITE
PART OF THE DAY?
I LIKED THAT, TOO.
MY FAVORITE PART
WAS WHEN YOU CAUGHT
OINKIE IN THE NET.
THAT WAS MY
FAVORITE PART, TOO.
WE COULDN'T HAVE SAVED
THE PIGGIES WITHOUT YOU.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
[ arrow beeps]
Dora:
THIS IS MY FRIEND, THE MAP.
FIND THE MAP.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ child giggles]