Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way
♪ Hey, hey!
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Have you ever had a cold?
Did it make you sneeze?
Well, my Grandma is sneezing
and coughing a lot.
She has a cold.
She feels yucky.
That's why my Mommy and I
baked treats
to make her feel better.
Here, Dora.
Here's the basket of treats
to take to Abuela
to make her feel better.
I call my grandma Abuela.
Can you say abuela?
Say abuela.
Ooh, that was good.
Will you help me take
the basket of treats
to Abuela's house
to make her feel better?
Great.
But Dora, where is your friend
Boots the monkey?
I thought he was going
on the trip with you.
He is, Mamá, but I
don't know where he is.
Boots! Where are you?
Boots.
We need your help
to call to Boots.
Will you help us call Boots?
You have to say "Boots."
Say it with us.
Both:
Boots...?
Louder.
Both:
Boots...?!
Here I come!
Boots!
Dora!
Hola,Boots.
Hola,Señora Marquez.
Now we're ready to go
to Abuela's house.
Now remember, you two,
don't lose that basket.
Both:
We won't.
And watch out for Swiper,
the sneaky fox.
Both:
Ooh, Swiper the fox.
That fox is so sneaky.
Don't let him swipe the basket
of treats for Abuela.
We won't, Mamá.
[ kisses]
Adiós,Mamá.
Adiós,Dora.
Adiós,Boots.
Good-bye.
[ kisses]
[ both laugh]
We better hurry
to Abuela's house
before Swiper tries to
swipe the basket of treats.
Which is the quickest
way to Abuela's house?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map! The Map!
The Map!
That's right.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find the quickest way
to Abuela's house?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map"! Say "Map"!
I think you have to
say it again.
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know
♪ I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet
♪ I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map
♪ I'm the Map!
Dora and Boots want to find
the quickest way
to Grandma's house
so they can give her
the basket of treats
and make her feel better.
Well, I know the quickest way
to Grandma's house.
To get to Grandma's house
first you have to go
over the Bumpy Bridge...
then go across Turtle River.
And that's the quickest way
to Grandma's house.
So you tell Dora:
Bridge...
river...
Grandma's house.
Say it with me.
Bridge...
river...
Grandma's house.
Bridge...
river...
Grandma's house.
Bridge...
river...
Grandma's house!
How do we get
to Grandma's house?
Bridge...
river...
Turtle:
iTortugas!
Grandma's house.
First we go over
the Bumpy Bridge
then across Turtle River
and then we'll get
to Grandma's house.
Thanks for helping.
So first we have to go
to the Bumpy Bridge.
Do you see a bridge?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the Bumpy Bridge.
Come on, Dora,
let's go!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Bridge, river, Grandma's house.
Bridge, river,
Grandma's house.
Bridge, river, Grandma's house.
Bridge, river,
Grandma's house.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Grandma's house
♪ Grandma's house.
[ laughing]
Grandma's house!
[ rustling]
Boots, did you hear that?
Yeah, it sounds
like Swiper the fox.
My Mommy was right.
We better watch out
for Swiper.
[ rustling]
If Swiper swipes
the basket
I can't give the treats
to my abuela
to make her feel better.
Will you help me
watch out for
Swiper the fox?
Great.
If you see Swiper
the fox, yell "Swiper!"
You see Swiper?
Where?
Behind the bush?
I don't see him.
Me neither.
Where is he now?
The fox, the fox!
You have to say,
"Swiper, no swiping."
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping.
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Thanks for helping us
stop Swiper.
Look, Dora.
The Bumpy Bridge.
Wow! This bridge
sure isbumpy.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Careful, Boots.
Both:
Oh, no!
The basket, the basket!
Don't worry.
We'll get the basket back.
How, Dora? How are we
going to get the basket back?
I bet I have something
in my Backpack we can use.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find something we can use
to pull the basket back up?
You have to say "Backpack"!
Say "Backpack,"
Say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need
♪ I got inside for you
♪ Backpack, Backpack
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah!
I have lots of stuff
but Dora needs you
to find something
she can use
to pull the basket up.
Can she use this
to pull the basket up?
[ click, beep]
That's right.
Dora can use a fishing pole
to pull the basket up.
Good thinking.
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Thanks.
Okay.
We hooked onto
the basket.
Now we have to wind up
the fishing line
and pull up the basket.
Will you help me
wind up the fishing line?
Great!
Hold the fishing pole
with one hand.
Now make a circle
with your other hand
to wind up the line.
Wind it up!
Here it comes!
Got it.
That was great.
Thanks for helping us
wind up the basket.
[ play happy tune]
All right!
We made it
over the Bumpy Bridge.
I can't wait to get
to Abuela's house.
So where do we go next?
Bridge, river, Grandma's house.
We went over the bridge.
So next we come to...
[ click, beep]
Turtle: iTortugas!
The river, right.
Do you see a river?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
Turtle River.
iVámonos!
Let's go!
Both:
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going?
♪ Grandma's house
♪ Grandma's house.
[ laughing]
Grandma's house!
[ rustling]
Hey, Boots,
what was that?
I don't know.
[ rustling]
Do you know
what that sound is?
The fox? Where?
Yeah, look! It's Swiper!
Oh, no! He's trying to
swipe Abuela's basket.
If we don't duck down
Swiper will swing into us
and swipe the basket.
Will you help us
duck down?
Great! When I say duck,
duck your head.
Here come Swiper.
He's going to swing
into us.
Duck your head!
Ooh, that was close.
Uh-oh, here he
comes again!
Duck your head!
He missed us, and
he didn't get the basket.
Here he comes again!
Duck!
He missed us again!
Great ducking.
Swiper didn't
swing into us.
Aah...!
But I think he's
going to swing
into that tree.
Oh, man...
Whoa! This basket's
heavy.
Well, let's put it down
for a second.
Right on this rock.
Both:
Whew...
Okay. Ready?
Ready.
Hey! Where did
the basket go?
Uh-oh.
Which way did
the basket go?
That way?
Uh-oh...
I don't see the basket.
Will you help us
find the basket?
Great.
Remember, the basket
is a rectangle.
Let's look for
all the things
that are rectangles.
Is this a rectangle?
[ click, beep]
It's a rectangle,
but it's not the basket.
Is this a rectangle?
[ click, beep]
It's a rectangle,
but it's not the picnic basket.
Is this a rectangle?
[ click, beep]
Right!
It's a rectangle
and it's the basket.
You found it!
And look! A turtle!
A turtle took our basket.
[ both laugh]
Where is he going?
Look! The turtle led us
right to Turtle River.
Thanks, turtle.
But how do we get
across Turtle River?
Excuse me.
Do you know how to get
across this river?
Yo hablo español.
Ooh, Boots, he said
he speaks Spanish,
just like me.
So I'll ask him how
to cross the river
in Spanish.
Good idea.
¿Cómo cruzamos el río?
Tienen que contar hasta cinco
en español
y cinco tortugas
les harán un camino.
He says to
cross the river
count to five
in Spanish
and five turtles will
make a path for us.
Then we'll get
across Turtle River.
Yes!
We have to count to five
in Spanish
so we can get
across Turtle River.
Will you help us
count in Spanish?
Great! Repeat after me.
Uno.
I didn't hear you.
Dos.
Tres.
Cuatro.
Cinco.
Cool!
The turtles made a path
for us to go over.
As I walk
over the turtles,
repeat after me.
Uno.
Dos.
Tres.
Cuatro.
Cinco.
Yay!
I made it across
all five turtles!
Now it's my turn.
We have to
count to five
in Spanish again
while Boots crosses.
Repeat after us.
Uno.Uno.
Uno.
Dos.Dos.
Dos.
Tres.Tres.
Tres.
Cuatro.Cuatro.
Cuatro.
Cinco.Cinco.
Cinco.
[ play happy tune]
Uno, dos, tres,
cuatro, cinco!
Thanks for helping us
count in Spanish.
Let's thank the turtles.
Yeah!
We have to say gracias
to thank the turtles.
Let's say gracias.
Say it with us.
Both:
Gracias.
De nada.
They said,
"You're welcome."
Where do we go next?
Bridge... river...
Turtle: iTortugas!
Grandma's house.
We went over the bridge
across Turtle River
so next is...
[ click, beep]
Right! Grandma's house!
Now where is
my abuela's house?
Do you see Abuela's house?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is.
Come on. iVamónos!
Let's go!
Dora, I feel like
we're being followed.
Me, too.
Is that tree
following us?
It is?
That's a funny tree.
Yeah, what kind
of tree are you?
Oh, I'm just a tree.
My, what a big nose
you have there, Tree.
The better to smell with.
And I smell
some delicious treats.
Bring that basket
a little closer, monkey.
I just want to take a sniff.
[ sniffing]
Careful, Boots.
I don't think
it's just a tree.
Do you think that's just a tree?
Who's inside that tree?
It's Swiper the fox!
Swiper's trying to
swipe Abuela's basket!
Help us stop Swiper.
You have to say,
"Swiper, no swiping!"
Say it with us.
Both:
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping.
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Thanks for helping us
stop Swiper.
We made it to Abuela's house!
Both:
Yay!
Let's call to Abuela.
Both:
Abuela!
Help us call to Abuela.
Say abuela.
Say it with us.
Both:
Abuela!
Louder!
Both:
Abuela!
Woman:
Hola. Estoy aquí.
I'm here.
Come on.
Abuela!
Dora!
Boots.
Abuela, how are
you feeling?
Don't worry, Dora.
I just have
a little cold.
Look what we
brought you, Abuela.
A basket of treats
to make you feel better.
Ooh! Let me see.
Yummy cookies, mangos...
[ gasps]
iArroz con leche!
Oh, all
my favorite foods.
And what's this?
That's a picture I drew
of Boots and me.
That's me.
Oh, the picture.
Es bien lindo.
It's beautiful.
Gracias.
De nada.
Ah!
Dora and Boots...
I love all my treats.
Thanks to you,
I'm feeling better already.
Both:
Yay! We did it!
[ music playing...]
♪ We did it!
♪ Yay!
Lo hicimos.
We did it!
♪ We went over the bridge
and across the river ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it!
♪ We did it!
♪ We did it! Hooray!
♪ We brought the basket
of treats ♪
♪ to Grandma's house
♪ Yeah, we did it!
♪ We did it!
♪ We fished
for the basket ♪
♪ with a fishing pole
♪ Swiper tried
to take the treats ♪
♪ But we ducked down low
Yay!
Whoo!
Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such an exciting trip
through the woods today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part
was when Swiper
swung on the vines
but we ducked and he
got stuck in the tree.
[ both laugh]
My favorite part was
seeing my abuela.
We couldn't have made it
to Abuela's house without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
Dora:
This is my friend
Tico the squirrel.
Find Tico!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ laughs]
[ click, beep]
[ giggles, laughs]