Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
And I'm Boots.
Benny:
Sticky tape!
Did you hear that?
Benny:
Sticky tape!
It sounds like that voice
is coming from the sky
Do you see something
in the sky?
Where?
There?
Both:
A balloon!
And look, it's our friend
Benny the bull.
Sticky tape!
He's riding
in the balloon.
Sticky tape...!
Sticky tape!
What did he say, Dora?
I don't know.
Sticky tape!
Sticky tape...!
Do you know
what Benny said?
What did Benny say?
Sticky tape?
Did Benny say
"sticky tape"?
Sticky tape!
Sticky tape...!
Benny, why do you need
sticky tape?
My balloon is going to crash.
It has a hole in it and
I need sticky tape to fix it.
Uh-oh, Benny really
does need sticky tape.
Where are we going to
get sticky tape, Dora?
I might have
some sticky tape
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack and
see if there's any sticky tape?
Great!
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack",
Say "Backpack"!
Both:
Louder!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
Hola.
I have lots of stuff
but Dora needs a roll of sticky
tape to fix Benny's balloon.
The sticky tape is round
like a circle, yellow
and has a hole in the middle.
Is this the sticky tape?
[ click, beep]
Right, this is the sticky tape.
You found it.
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
iDelicioso!
Thanks for getting
the sticky tape.
We've got to take
the sticky tape to Benny.
Sticky tape!
Where's the balloon
going, Dora?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
Map, Map, Map!
The Map, right.
Let's check the Map
to find out
where the balloon
is going.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
to find out where Benny's
balloon is going?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map",
Say "Map"!
I think you have to
say it again.
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to find out
where the balloon is going
so they can give Benny
the sticky tape.
Well, I know
where the balloon is going.
The balloon is going
to Crocodile Lake.
To get to Crocodile Lake, first
you go across the Windy River.
[ wind blowing]
Then you go over
the Slippery Rock.
And that's how you get
to Crocodile Lake.
So you tell Dora:
River...
rock...
Crocodile Lake.
Say it with me.
River...
rock...
Crocodile Lake.
River...
rock...
Crocodile Lake.
River...
rock...
Crocodile Lake!
Where's the balloon going?
River...
rock...
Crocodile Lake.
The balloon is going
across the Windy River...
[ wind blowing]
over the Slippery Rock...
and then it will get
to Crocodile Lake.
Ooh, Crocodile Lake
is filled with crocodiles!
We have to take
the sticky tape to Benny
before the balloon
goes into Crocodile Lake.
Where do we go first,
Dora?
Where do we go first?
First we have to find
the Windy River.
Do you see a river?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
There's the Windy River.
Sticky tape!
And there's Benny.
Come on, we've got to take
the sticky tape to Benny.
Before he goes
into Crocodile Lake.
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
River, rock, Crocodile Lake!
River, rock,
Crocodile Lake!
River, rock, Crocodile Lake!
River, rock,
Crocodile Lake!
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ What do we need? ♪
♪ Sticky tape ♪
Both:
♪ What do we need? ♪
♪ Sticky tape ♪
All:
♪ Sticky tape! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Sticky tape! ♪
[ ripping]
iAy! iMe caí!
I fell.
Dora! Dora!
Dora!
Is someone calling me?
Who's calling me?
My Backpack?
Oh, no!
Backpack!
¿Estás bien?
Are you okay?
Si, estoy bien.
But, look, my strap broke.
Don't worry, Backpack.
We'll fix you up.
We need to fix Backpack's
broken strap quick!
What can we use to stick
the strap back together?
Sticky tape!
Good idea!
You can use sticky tape
to stick things back together.
Gracias,Dora.
Thanks for helping.
Benny:
Sticky tape!
We've go to take
the sticky tape to Benny.
Come on, Dora!
[ wind blowing]
The Windy River.
This Windy River
sure is windy.
And look how fast
the wind is pushing
the balloon
over the river.
Sticky tape!
Sticky tape...!
We need to get
across the Windy River
if we're going to take
the sticky tape to Benny.
Do you see anything we can use
to get across the river?
What?
[ click, beep]
The boat?
Yeah!
Tico's sailboat.
Tico will give us a ride.
The wind will push Tico's
sailboat across the river.
Hi, Tico!
Will you take us
across the river
in your sailboat?
Hola, Tico.
¿Puedes llevarnos
al otro lado del río
en tu bote?
Sí, pero mi vela
tiene cinco hoyos.
Tico said, yes, but his sail
has five holes in it.
The wind won't blow Tico's boat
if there are holes in his sail.
What can we stick on the holes
to fix Tico's sail?
Both:
Sticky tape!
Right.
Tico can use
the sticky tape
to fix the five holes
in his sail.
We have to give Tico
five pieces of tape.
Tico speaks Spanish,
so let's count in Spanish.
Repeat after us...
All:
Uno.
Dos.
Tres.
Cuatro.
Cinco.
Cinco--five.
Five pieces of tape.
Now, Tico's going to
fix the sail.
Let's count in Spanish.
Repeat after us.
All:
Uno.
Dos.
Tres.
Cuatro.
Cinco.
The sail's fixed!
iFantástico!
Way to go, Tico.
Thanks for counting in Spanish.
Now that the sail
is fixed
we can sail
across the river
and take the sticky tape
to Benny.
iSalvavidas!
Both:
Life jackets!
So we can be safe.
[ wind blowing...]
Boots:
Come on.
We got to take
the sticky tape to Benny.
[ play happy tune]
We made it across
the Windy River.
All right!
Gracias,Tico.
Thank you, Tico.
De nada.
Is anyone coming with
that sticky tape?
We're coming, Benny.
We better get him
the sticky tape.
Where's the balloon
going next, Dora?
River...
rock...
Crocodile Lake.
We went across the river.
So next is...
[ click, beep]
The rock!
Right. We have to find
the Slippery Rock.
Do you see a rock?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
There's the Slippery Rock.
Come on, Dora.
We've got to take
the sticky tape to Benny.
Before he goes
into Crocodile Lake.
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
River, rock, Crocodile Lake!
River, rock,
Crocodile Lake!
River, rock, Crocodile Lake!
River, rock,
Crocodile Lake!
♪ Come on, vámonos ♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ What do we need? ♪
♪ Sticky tape ♪
Both:
♪ What do we need? ♪
♪ Sticky tape ♪
All:
♪ Sticky tape! ♪
[ laughing]
Both:
♪ Sticky tape! ♪
[ wind blowing...]
All:
iAy!
Dora! iAyúdanos!
The bluebird family
needs our help.
All:
iAyúdanos! iAyúdanos!
Dora:
Uh-oh, the wind is
going to knock the nest
out of the tree again!
What can we use to stick
the nest to the tree
so it will stay?
Both:
Sticky tape!
Right!
Young bird:
Yay!
All:
Gracias,Dora.
Gracias,Boots.
Both:
De nada.
Benny:
Sticky tape!
Boots:
We're coming, Benny!
Dora:
We've got to take
the sticky tape to Benny.
Boots:
Before the balloon
goes into Crocodile Lake!
[ rustling]
That sounds like
Swiper the fox!
That sneaky fox
will try to swipe
the sticky tape.
We need your help
to stop Swiper the fox.
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
Woop!
What's that?
You see Swiper?
Where?
Behind us?
Help us stop Swiper.
You have to say
"Swiper, no swiping."
Say it with us:
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping.
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
You helped us stop Swiper.
Sticky tape!
Did you forget
about the sticky tape?
Both:
We're coming, Benny!
Whoa...!
This rock
sure is slippery.
Both:
The Slippery Rock!
But we need to get
over the Slippery Rock
to get to Benny.
And our shoes
keep slipping.
What can we use
to make our shoes
stick to
the Slippery Rock?
Sticky tape.
Both:
Right.
Now our shoes will
really stick to the rock.
[ sticky pulling sound...]
We made it!
[ play happy tune]
We made it over the rock.
Both:
All right!
[ sticky pulling sound]
This sticky tape
sticks to everything.
Where are we going
next, Dora?
River...
rock...
Crocodile Lake.
We went across the river...
over the rock...
So next is...
[ click, beep]
Crocodile Lake!
Crocodile Lake is
filled with crocodiles!
We've got to take
the sticky tape
to Benny
before the balloon
goes into the lake.
Where's Crocodile Lake?
Do you see a lake?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
There's Crocodile Lake!
And there's
Benny's balloon.
It's headed
right for the lake!
Sticky tape!
We're coming, Benny!
Come on!
[ rustling]
That sounds like Swiper.
Dora, if Swiper
swipes the sticky tape
we'll never fix
Benny's balloon.
If you see Swiper,
say "Swiper!"
Both:
Swiper, no...
Zoop!
...swiping.
You're too late!
You'll never
find it now.
[ laughing]
That Swiper.
We got to find
that tape, Dora.
We'll find it, Boots.
Let's stop and think.
What shape is the tape?
Right, round
like a circle.
What color is it?
Right.
And it has a hole
in the middle.
Good thinking.
Let's look.
Boots:
Is this the sticky tape?
[ click, beep]
Both:
That's not
the sticky tape.
Boots:
Is this the sticky tape?
[ click, beep]
Both:
That's not the sticky tape.
Dora:
Is this the sticky tape?
[ click, beep]
The sticky tape!
You found it!
All right!
Thanks for helping.
The hole is getting bigger,
the hole is getting bigger!
I'm heading down
to Crocodile Lake!
Sticky tape, sticky tape!
We got the sticky tape,
Benny!
Throw down the ladder!
We can climb the ladder
up to the balloon.
Will you help us
climb the ladder
so we can take the tape
to Benny?
You will? Great!
Reach up high with your hands.
Now grab the ladder.
Hand over hand.
Both:
Climb, climb, climb, climb!
Oh, no!
The ladder's coming apart.
We need to fix the ladder.
What can we use to stick
the ladder back together?
Both:
Sticky tape!
Right.
Super-strong sticky tape.
Dora!
Boots!
We made it.
Good climbing.
Sticky tape?
Dora, Benny, look!
All:
Crocodiles!
We got to fix the balloon!
But how are we going to
get the tape up there?
I'll do it, I'll do it.
I'll climb up and
fix the balloon.
Let's all cheer for Boots.
Sticky tape, sticky tape,
sticky tape!
Sticky tape, sticky tape!
Sticky tape!
[ wind blowing]
Dora:
iQue bueno!
Boots:Yay!
Benny:
All right!
Dora:
We did it.
[ music playing]
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
Yay!
♪ Lo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went across the river
and over the rock, yeah ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! Hooray! ♪
♪ We fixed a lot of things
with the sticky tape, yeah ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
Both:
♪ Benny's balloon
was getting away ♪
♪ We brought him the tape
and we fixed it, hooray! ♪
Yay!
Whoo!
Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such
a fun trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part was
putting sticky tape on our shoes
to get over
the Slippery Rock.
My favorite part was
using the sticky tape
to fix Benny's balloon.
We couldn't have done it
without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
Dora:
Ooh, Swiper the fox.
Find Swiper.
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ rustling]
[ laughing]
[ click, beep]
Oh, man!
[ giggles, laughs]