Boots:
DORA!
Dora:
BOOTS!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
♪ D-D-D-D-D-DORA♪
LET'S GO.
♪ DORA, DORA, DORA
THE EXPLORER♪
DORA!
♪ BOOTS AND SUPERCOOL
EXPLORADORA. ♪
Dora:
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
Boots:
GRAB YOUR BACKPACK!
♪ LET'S GO, JUMP IN...♪
VAMONOS!
♪ YOU CAN LEAD THE WAY♪
HEY! HEY!
♪ D-D-DORA, D-D-D-DORA♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING♪
OH, MAN!
HI, I'M DORA.
BOOTS AND I ARE PLAYING
HIDE-AND-SEEK.
DO YOU WANT TO PLAY?
GREAT!
LET'S GO LOOK FOR BOOTS.
NOW, WHERE COULD THAT MONKEY
BE HIDING?
YOU SEE HIM?
WHERE?
BEHIND THE TREE?
I DON'T SEE HIM.
WHERE IS HE?
UP THERE?
BOO!
DORA!
[ both giggling]
THANKS FOR HELPING
ME FIND BOOTS.
LET'S PLAY AGAIN!
OKAY, BUT THIS TIME...
Baby voice:
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
Baby:
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
WHAT COULD IT BE?
I DON'T KNOW.
COME ON.
LET'S FOLLOW THE SOUND
AND FIND OUT.
Baby:
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
THAT SOUND IS COMING FROM?
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
THERE?
OOH, LOOK!
IT'S A BABY BLUEBIRD.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
CAREFUL, BOOTS.
YOU'VE GOT
TO BE GENTLE.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
SHE'S WET.
MAYBE SHE FELL
IN A PUDDLE.
[ sneezing]:
CHOO! CHOO!
AW, POOR BABY.
SHE'S COLD.
MAYBE I'VE GOT
SOMETHING IN MY BACKPACK
TO DRY OFF
THE BABY BIRD.
YEAH, YEAH!
I NEED YOUR HELP
TO OPEN MY BACKPACK.
COULD YOU SAY "BACKPACK"?
SAY "BACKPACK"!
Both:
LOUDER!
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ I'M A BACKPACK LOADED UP WITH
THINGS AND KNICKKNACKS, TOO ♪
♪ ANYTHING THAT YOU MIGHT NEED
I GOT INSIDE FOR YOU. ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK. ♪
YEAH!
DORA NEEDS SOMETHING
TO DRY OFF THE BABY BIRD.
DO YOU SEE ANYTHING WE COULD USE
TO DRY OFF THE BABY BIRD?
CAN WE USE THIS?
YOU'RE RIGHT-- THE TOWEL!
THE TOWEL CAN DRY OFF
THE BABY BLUEBIRD.
GOOD THINKING!
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM--
DELICIOSO!
Both:
YEAH!
THANK YOU FOR HELPING.
MAMA, MAMA.
POOR LITTLE BABY.
SHE WANTS HER MOMMY.
I BET SHE FELL
OUT OF HER NEST.
OH!
NOW SHE'S LOST.
MAMA, MAMA.
DORA, CAN WE HELP HER
FIND HER MOMMY?
CAN WE? CAN WE?
YOU BET WE CAN!
DON'T WORRY,
BABY BIRD.
WE'LL HELP YOU
FIND YOUR MOMMY.
WHERE DO YOU LIVE,
BABY BIRD?
¿QUE?
OH! THE BABY BLUEBIRD
SPEAKS SPANISH.
¿DONDE VIVES?
[ sniffles]
ARBOL.
TREE!
ARBOL!
SHE MUST LIVE IN A TREE.
A TREE, A TREE!
SHE LIVES IN A TREE.
PEQUEÑO.
THE TREE IS LITTLE.
AZUL, AZUL, AZUL.
THE TREE IS BLUE.
THE TREE IS
LITTLE AND BLUE.
Dora and Boots:
THE LITTLE BLUE TREE!
YEAH, YEAH!
BUT, DORA,
HOW DO WE GET
TO THE LITTLE
BLUE TREE?
LET'S STOP
AND THINK.
WHO CAN WE ASK
FOR HELP
WHEN WE DON'T KNOW
WHICH WAY TO GO?
THE MAP!THE MAP!
THE MAP--
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE MAP CAN TELL US
HOW TO GET TO
THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
COULD YOU CHECK THE MAP
AND TELL ME WHAT IT SAYS?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "MAP."
SAY "MAP"!
Both:
LOUDER!
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GO ♪
♪ I'M THE ONE YOU NEED TO KNOW ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GET ♪
♪ I CAN GET YOU THERE, I BET ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
I'M THE MAP!
[ song ends]
DORA AND BOOTS NEED
TO TAKE THE BABY BIRD
BACK TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.
WELL, I KNOW HOW TO GET
TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.
TO GET TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE,
YOU NEED TO GO PAST THE BANANAS
THROUGH THE CORNFIELD
AND SOON YOU'LL COME
TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.
MI BEBE!
SO HERE'S WHAT YOU TELL DORA:
BANANAS... CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE.
SAY IT WITH ME.
BANANAS...
CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE.
BANANAS...
CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE.
BANANAS...
CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE!
HOW DO WE GET
TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE?
BANANAS...
CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE.
MI BEBE!
SO FIRST WE GO
PAST THE BANANAS...
THROUGH THE CORNFIELD...
AND THAT'S HOW WE GET
TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.
MI BEBE!
OKAY, BOOTS.
FIRST WE NEED TO GET
TO THE BANANAS.
DO YOUSEE
THE BANANAS?
WHERE?
YEAH!
THERE THEY ARE.
COME ON, BOOTS.
LET'S TAKE THIS BABY BIRD
HOME TO HER MOMMY.
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
BANANAS...
CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE.
BANANAS...
CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE.
♪ ♪ ♪
Dora and Boots:
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO. ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT. ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE LITTLE
BLUE TREE. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE
WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE LITTLE
BLUE TREE. ♪
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.♪
All:
♪ TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE. ♪
[ laughing]
♪ LITTLE BLUE TREE! ♪
[ song ends]
HEY, DORA, I'M GETTING HUNGRY.
WHEN ARE WE GOING TO GET
TO THE BANANAS?
I DON'T KNOW, BOOTS.
WE SHOULD BE THERE SOON.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP!
I THINK THE BABY
BLUEBIRD IS HUNGRY, TOO.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP!
IF YOU SEE ANY BANANAS
SAY "BANANAS."
YOU SEE BANANAS?
WHERE?
THE BANANAS!
YEAH, WE MADE IT
TO THE BANANAS!
Dora and Boots:
ALL RIGHT!
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP!
YUM!
I'LL CLIMB UP
AND GET SOME.
HOW MANY BANANAS
DO WE NEED?
LET'S SEE.
ONE FOR THE BABY BIRD,
ONE FOR YOU
AND ONE FOR ME.
ONE...
TWO... THREE.
THREE BANANAS.
HOW MANY BANANAS DO WE NEED?
OKAY, THREE BANANAS.
IS THIS ENOUGH?
YES?
ONE...
TWO...
THREE BANANAS.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP!
GOOD GOING,
BOOTS.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
MMM, YUM!
Dora and Boots:
DELICIOSO.
[ rustling]
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
BOOTS, WE BETTER
WATCH OUT
FOR SWIPER THE FOX.
YEAH, THAT SNEAKY FOX
IS ALWAYS TRYING
TO SWIPE OUR STUFF.
WE'RE NOT GOING
TO LET HIM TAKE
OUR BANANAS.
NO WAY!
IF YOU SEE THE FOX,
YELL "SWIPER!"
YOU SEE SWIPER?
PEEP!
WHERE?
IN THE BUSH?
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP!
HELP US STOP SWIPER.
YOU HAVE TO SAY,
"SWIPER, NO SWIPING."
SAY IT WITH US.
Dora and Boots:
SWIPER, NO SWIPING.
OH, MAN!
THAT WAS CLOSE.
THANKS FOR
HELPING US.
HE ALMOST SWIPED
OUR BANANAS.
HEY...
WHERE DID
THE BABY BIRD GO?
SWIPER MUST
HAVE SCARED HER.
BABY BIRD!
PAJARITO!
DID YOU SEE WHICH WAY
THE BABY BIRD WENT?
THIS WAY?
THANKS.
COME ON!
BABY BIRD!
PAJARITO!
WHERE ARE YOU?
¿DONDE ESTAS?
OH, THIS IS AWFUL.
WE'VE GOT
TO FIND HER.
LET'S STOP AND THINK.
HOW DID WE FIND
THE BABY BIRD
WHEN SHE WAS HIDING
IN THE BUSH?
SHE WENT "PEEP,
PEEP, PEEP!"
RIGHT!
MAYBE IF WE'RE
REAL QUIET
WE CAN HEAR HER GO
"PEEP, PEEP, PEEP" AGAIN.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
LISTEN TO THE SOUNDS
TO HELP US FIND THE BABY BIRD.
Voice:
BUZZ.
Voice:CRICKET,CRICKET.
Voice:
RIBBET,
RIBBET.
Voice:
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
I KNOW,
I KNOW!
SHE'S BEHIND
THE LEAF!
[ buzzing]
SORRY.
THAT'S NOT
THE BABY BIRD.
CRICKET,CRICKET.
RIBBET,
RIBBET.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
WHERE IS THE BABY
BLUEBIRD HIDING?
BEHIND THE FLOWERS?
[ crying]
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
HERE SHE IS.
THE FOX REALLY
SCARED HER.
THAT'S SO MEAN.
IT'S OKAY,
BABY BIRD.
ESTA BIEN, ESTA BIEN.
[ crying]
PEEP.
SHE'S STILL CRYING.
HOW CAN WE CHEER HER UP?
I KNOW!
[ monkey dance music playing]
THAT'S FUNNY.
THIS IS MY MONKEY DANCE.
I TICKLE MY SIDES
AND JUMP UP AND DOWN.
[ both laughing]
[ laughing]
THANK YOU FOR HELPING
US FIND HER.
GOOD-BYE.
BYE.
WE'VE GOT TO GET
THIS BABY BIRD HOME
TO HER MOMMY.
WHERE DO WE
GO NEXT?
BANANAS...
CORNFIELD...
LITTLE BLUE TREE.
WE MADE IT PAST THE BANANAS,
SO NEXT WE GO TO...
THE CORNFIELD-- RIGHT.
DO YOU SEE
THE CORNFIELD?
WHERE?
YEAH, THERE'S
THE CORNFIELD!
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US.
♪ ♪ ♪
Both:
♪ BANANAS, CORNFIELD,
LITTLE BLUE TREE! ♪
♪ ♪ ♪
Dora and Boots:
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO. ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT. ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE LITTLE
BLUE TREE. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE
WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE LITTLE
BLUE TREE. ♪
Both:
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.♪
All:
♪ TO THE LITTLE BLUE TREE. ♪
[ laughing]
♪ LITTLE BLUE TREE! ♪
[ song ends]
IT'S A CORNFIELD!
WE MADE IT!
WE'RE ALMOST
THERE.
ALL RIGHT!
COME ON.
Boots:
HEY, LOOK-- THERE'S A SCARECROW.
YEAH!
BOO!
[ crying]:
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP...
SCARECROW, WHY
DID YOU DO THAT?
I'M SORRY, BUT I'M A SCARECROW.
MY JOB IS TO SCARE BIRDS.
I'M REALLY VERY SORRY.
[ crying]
WELL, DON'T CRY,
SCARECROW.
WE NEED YOU TO HELP US
CHEER UP THE BABY BIRD.
[ crying]:
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP...
I KNOW HOW TO
CHEER HER UP.
[ monkey dance music playing]
GOOD THINKING.
YOUR MONKEY DANCE
CHEERED HER UP BEFORE.
I BET IF WE ALL DO
THE MONKEY DANCE
WE CAN CHEER UP
THE BABY BLUEBIRD.
WILL YOU DO THE MONKEY DANCE
WITH US?
GREAT!
YOU HAVE TO STAND UP.
NOW STAND UP, PLEASE.
STAND UP!
UP! UP!GET UP!
[ crying]
CAN YOU TICKLE YOUR SIDES?
TICKLE YOUR SIDES.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP.
NOW JUMP UP AND DOWN.
TICKLE YOUR SIDES.
JUMP UP AND DOWN.
WE'RE DOING
THE MONKEY DANCE.
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP... PEEP!
[ laughing]
IT WORKED!
THANKS FOR HELPING US CHEER UP
THE BABY BIRD.
YOU CAN SIT DOWN NOW.
SORRY I SCARED YOU.
FRIENDS?
SO, YOU'RE GOING
THROUGH
THE CORNFIELD, HUH?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE CORN LOOKS TALL.
WE DON'T WANT
TO GET LOST.
DON'T WORRY.
LOOK FOR THE PATH
WITH THE BLUE STONES
AND YOU WON'T
GET LOST.
AZUL! AZUL!
RIGHT-- FOLLOW
THE BLUE STONES.
OH, DON'T TAKE
THE PATH WITH
THE RED STONES
BECAUSE IT HAS
THE MEAN RED ANTS.
OOH!
FOLLOW THE PATH
WITH THE BLUE
STONES
AND YOU'LL FIND
YOUR WAY THROUGH
THE CORNFIELD.
GRACIAS.
OKAY, BOOTS, LET'S GO.
DID YOU SEE
WHERE THE BABY
BIRD WENT?
Boots:
BABY BIRD, WAIT!
Dora:
PAJARITO, ESPERATE!
DO YOU SEE THE BABY BLUEBIRD?
Ants:
ANTS! ANTS! ANTS!
Boots:
WHAT IF THE BABY BIRD RUNS
INTO THE MEAN RED ANTS?
Dora:
YOU HAVE TO TELL HER TO TAKE
THE PATH WITH THE BLUE STONES.
REMEMBER, BABY BLUEBIRD
SPEAKS SPANISH
SO LET'S SAY AZUL.
CAN YOU SAY AZUL?
Boots:
SAY AZUL!SAY AZUL!
Both:
LOUDER!
AZUL!
Dora:
IT'S WORKING!
KEEP SAYING AZUL.
AZUL!
Ants:
ANTS! ANTS! ANTS!
Dora:
KEEP SAYING AZUL.
AZUL!
Dora:
LOUDER!
AZUL!
[ laughing]
PAJARITO!
YOU MADE IT!
MUY BIEN.
VERY GOOD!
THANK YOU.
GRACIAS.
COME ON, GUYS,
WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
HEY, WHERE IS
SHE GOING NOW?
MAMA.
Dora:
AH, BOOTS, I THINK SHE WANTS TO
GIVE THAT FLOWER TO HER MOMMY.
[ rustling]
WHAT'S THAT?
DO YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
BEHIND THE TREE?
THAT MEAN FOX.
HE WANTS
TO SWIPE
HER FLOWER.
Bluebird:
PEEP, PEEP, PEEP!
Dora:
HELP US STOP SWIPER.
YOU HAVE TO SAY,
"SWIPER, NO SWIPING."
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
SWIPER, NO SWIPING!
OH, MAN!
YOU DID IT!
WAY TO GO, YOU
BRAVE BABY BIRD.
FANTASTICO!
WE MADE IT PAST THE BANANAS...
THROUGH THE CORNFIELD...
AND NOW WE CAN GO TO THE...
LITTLE BLUE TREE!
NOW, WHERE IS
THE LITTLE BLUE TREE?
DO YOU SEE
YEAH, THERE'S
THE LITTLE BLUE TREE.
Bluebird:
MAMA! MAMA!
MAMA!
MI BEBE!
MAMA.
[ kisses]
OH.
MAMA.
MUCHAS GRACIAS.
DE NADA.
WE COULDN'T HAVE DONE IT
WITHOUT YOU.
DORA, WE DID IT!
LO HICIMOS!
♪ ♪ ♪
Both:
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
WE DID IT.
YAY!
♪ LO HICIMOS.♪
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE FOUND
THE BABY BIRD... ♪
♪ AND WE BROUGHT
HER HOME. ♪
Both:
♪ YEAH, WE DID IT ♪
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE DID IT, HURRAY! ♪
♪ WE FOUND HER MOMMY
IN THE LITTLE BLUE TREE ♪
♪ YEAH, WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE DID IT! WE DID IT! ♪
♪ WE PASSED THE BANANAS
ALONG THE WAY ♪
♪ WE WALKED THROUGH
THE CORNFIELD ♪
♪ AND WE MADE IT,
HURRAY! ♪
[ cheering]
WE DID IT!
LO HICIMOS!
[ song ends]
WHOO!
WE HAD SUCH
A GREAT TRIP TODAY.
WHAT WAS YOUR FAVORITE
PART OF THE TRIP?
I LIKED THAT, TOO.
MY FAVORITE PART
OF THE TRIP WAS
WHEN WE ALL DID
THE MONKEY DANCE
AND THE BABY
BLUEBIRD LAUGHED.
THAT WAS FUNNY.
MY FAVORITE PART WAS
WHEN THE BABY BLUEBIRD
SAW HER MOMMY.
WE COULDN'T HAVE DONE IT
WITHOUT YOU.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
FIND TICO.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ giggles]
[ children giggling]