Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
Do you like snacks?
I love snacks.
Look what my mommy gave me
for a snack...
Blueberries!
How many blueberries
did my Mommy give me?
Count with me.
One
two
three
four
five!
Five yummy blueberries!
[ slurping]
Mmm.
Yum, yum, yum.
I love blueberries.
Blueberries,
blueberries
blueberries!
Hey, Boots!
Boots loves
blueberries, too.
Ooh-ooh, ah-ah!
Blueberries! Yeah, yeah!
Can I have some,
can I have some,
can I have some?
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Aw, Boots, I'm sorry.
I ate them all.
Oh! No blueberries!
No blueberries...
No, no blueberries.
Boots, we can get
more blueberries.
We can?
Let's go on a berry hunt
and find more blueberries.
Ooh, ooh, ooh,
ah, ah, ah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
[ laughs]
Okay, Boots, we need
my little blue pail
so we can carry the blueberries
that we pick.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find my little blue pail
to carry the blueberries?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
I have lots of pails.
But Dora wants her little blue
pail to carry the blueberries.
First let's find all the pails
that are blue.
Is this a blue pail?
[ click, beep]
Now, which pail
is the little blue pail?
[ click, beep]
All right!
You found the little blue pail!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Thanks.
Where do we go, Dora?
Where do we go?
Where do we go
to find blueberries?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map! The Map!
The Map!
That's right.
The Map can tell us
where to go
to find blueberries.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map to see
where to go to find blueberries?
You have to say "Map"!
Say "Map," say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots want to know
where to go to find blueberries.
Well, I know where to go
to find blueberries.
Blueberry Hill!
To get to Blueberry Hill
first you have to go
across the Icy Cold River
then you go through
the Prickly Forest
and that's how you get
to Blueberry Hill.
But watch out
for Swiper the Fox.
He lives on Blueberry Hill.
So here's what you tell Dora:
River
forest
Blueberry Hill.
Say it with me.
River
forest
Blueberry Hill!
River
forest
Blueberry Hill!
River
forest
Blueberry Hill...!
How do we get
to the blueberries?
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
First we go across
the Icy Cold River
then we go through
the Prickly Forest
and that's how we'll get
to Blueberry Hill.
But we have to watch out
for Swiper the fox.
He lives on Blueberry Hill.
Both:
Ooh, Swiper the fox.
I'm not scared.
Me neither.
I'm Dora
the blueberry hunter!
I'm Boots
[ both laugh]
Okay, first we need to find
the Icy Cold River.
Do you see the river?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Vámonos.
Let's go get
the blueberries!
Come on,
say it with us.
Both:
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
River, forest,
Blueberry Hill.
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
River, forest,
Blueberry Hill.
You say what I say.
Going on a berry hunt.
Going to pick
some juicy ones.
We're not scared.
Both:
What a beautiful day!
Could you say it
with us?
Here we go.
Going on a berry hunt.
Going to pick
some juicy ones.
We're not scared.
Both:
What a beautiful day!
Look, Boots.
There's the
Icy Cold River.
Dora, how are we
going to get across it?
We can't go around it.
We can't go through it.
Both:
How can we get across it?
Let's stop and think.
Do you see something
that can help us
across the
Icy Cold River?
[ click, beep]
The boat!
Great.
Lifejackets!
So we can be safe.
Will you help us row
across the Icy Cold River?
You will? Great!
Put your hands out in front
of you and row, row, row!
Both:
Row, row, row!
[ play happy tune]
Yay!
We made it across
the Icy Cold River.
Good rowing.
Dora, I can't wait to
eat those blueberries.
I can't wait, either.
Blueberries are so
sweet and juicy.
Both:
Mmm, yummy!
Where do we go next?
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
We made it across the river.
So next we have to go through...
[ click, beep]
The forest. Right!
The Prickly Forest.
Do you see
the Prickly Forest?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
River, forest,
Blueberry Hill.
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
River, forest,
Blueberry Hill.
Let's say it really loud!
Going on a berry hunt!
Going to pick some juicy ones!
We're not scared!
Both:
What a beautiful day!
Say it really soft.
Going on a berry hunt.
Going to pick
some juicy ones.
We're not scared.
Both:
What a beautiful day.
Even softer.
[ whispering...]:
Going on a berry hunt.
Going to pick
some juicy ones.
Going to pick some juicy ones.
We're not scared.
Both:
What a beautiful day.
Now really, really, really loud!
Going on a berry hunt!
Going to pick
some juicy ones!
We're not scared!
Both:
What a beautiful day!
[ both laughing]
Look, we made it
to the Prickly Forest!
But look, Dora.
Uh-oh...
Both:
Prickers and thorns.
They could stick us.
Can't go around it.
Can't go through it.
Both:
How can we get over
the prickers and thorns?
Let's stop
and think.
Do you see anything
we can use
to get over
the prickers and thorns?
[ click, beep]
Yeah! We can use
the vines
to swing over
the prickers and thorns.
We need your help.
Will you help us swing
over the prickers and thorns?
Grab onto a vine
with both hands.
Hold on tight.
Now swing your arms
back and forth.
Both:
Swing, swing, swing, swing!
[ play happy tune]
Both:
Yay!
We made it
over the Prickly Forest.
Good swinging.
Where do we go next?
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
We went across the river
we swung over the forest
so next comes...
[ click, beep]
Blueberry Hill!
Right!
Do you see
Blueberry Hill?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there it is!
Come on, let's go!
Blueberries,
here we come!
Sweet, juicy
blueberries.
Mmm, yum.
[ laughing]:
Whoa, whoa!
Uh, Gate,
we need you to open.
Hablo español.
Boots, the Gate
speaks Spanish
so we have to say "abre."
Can you say "abre"?
Say it with us.
Both:
iAbre!
One more time.
Say "abre."
Both:
iAbre!
The Gate opened!
Thanks for helping.
iGracias!
Thank you.
De nada.
Come one, let's go get
some blueberries!
But watch out
for Swiper the fox.
He lives
on Blueberry Hill.
Both:
Ooh, Swiper the Fox.
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
River, forest,
Blueberry Hill.
River, forest, Blueberry Hill.
River, forest,
Blueberry Hill!
You say what I say.
Say it fast.
Going on a berry hunt.
Going to pick
some juicy ones.
We're not scared.
Both:
What a beautiful day!
Even faster.
Going on a berry hunt.
Going to pick
some juicy ones.
We're not scared.
Both:
What a beautiful day!
We made it
to Blueberry Hill.
All right.
Blueberries,
blueberries,
blueberries!
But where are
the blueberries?
Do you see
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there are
the blueberries.
Boots! Quiet!
Blueberries!
Boots...
Sweet, juicy...
Shh...
Mmm, yummy.
I love
blueberries!
Boots, shh...
[ whispering...]:
Dora, I love
blueberries.
[ whispering...]
Me, too, Boots.
But we have to be
very quiet.
Why?
We don't want Swiper
to hear us.
He lives
right around here.
Oh, yeah...
[ still whispering...]
Swiper lives
in a fox hole.
Do you see any holes
in the ground?
[ click, beep]
[ still whispering]:
Yeah, there's
his foxhole.
Both:
Ooh, Swiper the fox.
We'd better hurry
and pick the blueberries.
Help us count the blueberries
as we pick them.
Count softly.
Both:
One
two
three
four
five
six
seven
eight
nine
ten
eleven
twelve
thirteen
fourteen
fifteen.
[ loudly]:
Fifteen sweet
juicy blueberries!
Shh...!
Both whisper:
Mmm, yummy.
Thanks for
helping us count.
Come on, Boots.
Let's get out of here
before Swiper sees us.
Yeah, that sneaky fox.
He'll try to swipe
our blueberries.
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
You see Swiper?
Where?
In his foxhole?
I don't see him.
Me neither.
Where is he?
Whoop!
Where?
Both:
Swiper!
We need your help
to stop Swiper.
You have to say
"Swiper, no swiping."
Say it with us.
Both:
Swiper, no swiping.
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Both:
Yay!
Thanks for helping us
stop Swiper.
Now can we eat
the blueberries?
Can we, can we,
can we?
You bet we can, Boots.
Ooh...
Mmm, blueberries.
[ deep voice]:
Mmm, blueberries!
Who said that?
I don't know.
Mmm, blueberries.
Mmm, blueberries!
Who said that?
The bear?!
Where?!
Right behind us?
Both:
Oh, no! Run!
[ bear grunting]
Dora, he's coming
after us!
What do we do?
We have to go back
the way we came.
Here's the gate!
Help us open the gate.
Yell "iabre!"
Both:
iAbre!
Gate:
[ bear grunting]
[ grunting]
Both:
Whoa...!
Look, Dora, here comes
the Prickly Forest!
The Prickly Forest!
Oh, no!
Help us swing over
the prickers and thorns.
Grab onto a vine.
Hold on tight.
Now swing...
Swing, swing!
[ start to play
happy tune]
[ grunting]
Both:
Whoa!
Here comes
the Icy Cold River.
Where's the boat?
[ click, beep]
There! There!
Thanks!
Help us row
across the river.
Put your hands out
in front of you
and row, row, row.
Whoa...!
Brr...!
Dora, wait!
This water is
so icy cold
there's no way the bear
will swim after us.
Both:
The bear's swimming
after us!
Row faster!
Row, row, row!
Faster! Faster!
Row, row, row, row, row,
row, row, row, row!
Is the bear
still after us?
No, Boots, look!
We rowed so fast
across the Icy River
the bear's giving up
and going home.
Yay!
Thanks for rowing so fast.
Dora, we got
blueberries!
And we stopped Swiper.
And got away
from a bear.
And now...
[ slurping]
Both:
Mmm, yummy!
Sweet and juicy.
Delicioso.
We did it!
[ music playing...]
Both:
♪ We did it ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
Lo hicimos.
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We crossed
the Icy Cold River ♪
♪ and went through
the forest ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it ♪
♪ We did it ♪
♪ We did it! Hooray! ♪
♪ We got juicy berries
at Blueberry Hill ♪
♪ We did it ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We were chased
by a bear ♪
♪ But we got away ♪
♪ We ate a lot
of berries ♪
♪ What a beautiful day! ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such an exciting
berry hunt today.
What was your favorite part
of the berry hunt?
I like that, too.
My favorite part was
when we rowed so fast
across the Icy Cold River.
Vroom!
My favorite part was
eating the blueberries.
Both:
Mmm, yummy.
We couldn't have gotten
the berries without you.
Thanks for helping.
[ click, beep]
Dora:
This is my friend the Wizzle.
Can you find the Wizzle?
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Over here!
Whoops!
Hey! [ laughs]
Whoa!
[ laughing]
Yoo-hoo!
Here I am!
Aha! Aha!
Over here!
Missed me!
[ laughing]
[ click, beep]
Hey, you found me!
[ laughing]
[ giggles, laughs]