Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Hi, I'm Dora.
And I'm Boots.
Do you like
to make wishes?
Every night before I go
to bed, I make a wish.
I make a wish on the first
little star I see in the sky.
The little star always come out
next to his friend, the Moon.
Dora, I don't see
the little star.
It's very far away.
We need something that will
help us see very far away.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
for something that will
help us see very far away?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
Hola.I have lots of stuff
but Dora and Boots
need something
that will help them
see very far away.
Will this help them
see very far away?
Will thishelp them
[ click, beep]
Right, a telescope will help
them see very far away.
Good thinking!
iMuy bien!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum...
iDelicioso!
Wow. When I look
through this telescope
I can see
the first little star.
Here, take a look
through this telescope.
Do you see
the little star?
With the telescope,
the little star and the Moon
look bigger
and closer.
Whew, that little star
sure shines bright!
[ giggles]
Now we can make a wish
on the star.
BOTH [ whispering]:
Star light, star bright,
first star I see tonight.
I wish I may, I wish I might,
have the wish I wish to...
Whoa!
What was that?!
I don't know!
Let me see!
It's a comet!
Whoa!
Here it comes again!
Watch out!
Coming through!
Can't stop!
Look out!
BOOTS AND DORA:
Don't fall! Don't fall!
Oh, no!
Whoa...!
She's falling!
BOTH:
Ooh...
Come on!
We've got to find
that little star.
Will you help us find
the little star?
Great! If you see the star,
say "star."
[ click, beep]
Yes! It's the little star
that fell from the sky.
[ whimpering]
Are you okay,
Little Star?
You fell very far.
[ sniffles, cries]
Aw...Aw...
Don't cry.
It's okay, it's okay.
[ crying]
Maybe we should
sing her a song.
Hey, yeah!
That will make her
feel better.
Now, what's a song
about a little star?
"Twinkle, Twinkle"!
"Twinkle, Twinkle,
Little Star," right!
I need your help to make
Little Star stop crying.
Will you sing "Twinkle, Twinkle"
with us?
Great! Sing with us!
BOTH:
♪ Twinkle, twinkle,
Little Star ♪
♪ How I wonder what you are ♪
♪ Up above the world so high ♪
♪ Like a diamond in the sky ♪
♪ Twinkle, twinkle,
Little Star ♪
♪ How I wonder what you are. ♪
Thanks for singing.
You made me feel better.
I'm Dora.
I'm Boots.
I'm Little Star.
Little Star, we were just
about to make our wishes.
I'm the first star
in the sky.
I need to get home
to the Moon
so everyone can
make their wish!
You're right!
Come on!
Let's get Little Star
home to the Moon...
So everyone can make
their wish!
How do we get
to the Moon?
to the Moon?!
Hmm. Let's stop
and think.
Who do we ask
for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map,the Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us
how to get Little Star
home to the Moon.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find out how to
get to the Moon?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map,"
say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to get
Little Star home to the Moon
so everyone can make
their wish.
Now, where is the Moon?
[ click, beep]
Right! The moon is
above the Tall Mountain.
Well, I know how to get
to the Tall Mountain.
First you go
over the Troll Bridge.
Then you go past
Tico's tree.
And that's how you get
to the Tall Mountain
to take Little Star
home to the Moon.
Come home,
Little Star,
come home!
So you tell Dora:
Bridge...
Tree...
Tall Mountain.
Say it with me.
Bridge...
Tree...
Tall Mountain.
Bridge...
Tree...
Tall Mountain.
Bridge...
Tree...
Tall Mountain...!
How do we get Little Star
home to the Moon?
Bridge...
Tree...
Tall Mountain.
First we go
over the Troll Bridge
then we go past Tico's tree
and that's how we'll get
to the Tall Mountain
to take Little Star
home to the Moon.
Come home,
Little Star,
come home!
Then everyone
can make their wish.
Thanks for helping.
So first we need to go
over the Troll Bridge.
Do you see a bridge?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Right, there it is!
There's the Troll Bridge!
Come on, come on!
iVámonos!
Let's get Little Star
home to the Moon...
So everyone can
make their wish!
Come on, say it with us!
ALL:
Bridge, Tree, Tall Mountain!
BOOTS AND DORA:
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Tall Mountain ♪
ALL:
♪ Tall Mountain! ♪
[ laughing]
DORA AND BOOTS:
♪ Tall Mountain! ♪
Ooh, look,
it's the Troll Bridge.
I hope we don't run into
that Grumpy Old Troll.
♪ I'm the Grumpy Old Troll ♪
♪ who lives under the bridge ♪
♪ Hey! I'm
the Grumpy Old Troll ♪
♪ who lives under the bridge ♪
♪ Who's there? ♪
♪ If you want to come over ♪
♪ all you have to do is this ♪
♪ All you have to do
is this... ♪
Solve my riddle!
Good evening,
Mr. Troll.
Can we go
over your bridge?
No one goes
over my bridge!
No one, no one,
no one, no one!
But we have to go
over your bridge.
We have to take
Little Star home.
So everyone can
make their wish.
I said no one
goes over my bridge!
Unless...
you can solve my riddle.
Star light,
star bright
can you see the
stars so bright?
Star light,
star bright
how many stars
are here tonight?
Will you help us
solve the Troll's riddle?
Great! The riddle
goes like this.
ALL:
Star light, star bright
can you see the stars so bright?
how many stars
are here tonight?
We have to count the stars!
Count with us.
ALL: One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight...
nine...
ten!
Ten stars!
[ giggles, laughs]
They're forgetting a star.
They're forgetting a star!
And it's the shiniest
star of them all!
Which star
did we forget?
[ click, beep]
Hey, yeah!
You forgot to count me!
Oops!
Let's count again.
Count with us.
ALL:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight...
nine...
ten...
eleven!
Eleven!
Eleven stars
are here tonight!
We solved
the riddle!
Aw, you win!
[ grumbling]
Oh, all right.
Go on over my bridge.
Aw, they
always win...
Come on!
One day
I'll get them.
[ play happy tune]
Where do we go next?
Bridge, Tree, Tall Mountain.
We made it over the bridge,
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Tree, right!
Now,
where's Tico's tree?
Do you see a tree?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
Tico's tree!
Come on!
iVámonos!
Let's get Little Star
home to the Moon...
So everyone can
make their wish!
Come on, say it with us!
ALL:
Bridge, Tree, Tall Mountain!
BOOTS AND DORA:
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Tall Mountain ♪
ALL:
♪ Tall Mountain! ♪
[ laughing]
DORA AND BOOTS:
♪ Tall Mountain! ♪
Here's Tico
the squirrel's house
And there's Tico!
¿Dónde está la estrellita?
Oh, Tico's looking
for Little Star.
He want to make a wish
on the star before bedtime
just like us.
Tico, mira,
la estrellita está aquí.
Dora, we better hurry
and get Little Star home
so everyone
can make their...
[ rustling]
Oh, no!
Did you hear that?
That sounds like
Swiper the fox.
That sneaky fox is always
trying to swipe our stuff.
He'll try to swipe
Little Star!
Will you help us watch out
for Swiper the fox?
Great.
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
Whoop!
Do you see Swiper?
Where?
BOTH:
Swiper the fox!
Swiper, no...
Zoop!
...swiping.
You're too late!
Ha-ha-ha!
You'll never find
the star now!
I hid the star
in Tico's tree!
[ laughing]
Where did Swiper
hide Little Star?
In Tico's tree?
iVoy a buscar
la estrellita!
Tico's going to climb up
and save Little Star!
iAnda, Tico! iAnda!
Go, Tico!
You can do it!
DORA:
You need to help Tico
find Little Star.
Where's Little Star?
[ click, beep]
Right!
There's Little Star!
BOOTS:
Don't worry, Little Star!
Tico's coming!
DORA:
Oh, no!
We have to tell Tico
to jump over the branch.
Tico speaks Spanish,
so let's say salta.
Can you say salta?
Say salta!
BOOTS AND DORA:
iSalta!
DORA:
Great!
Oh, no, another branch!
Say salta!
BOOTS AND DORA:
iSalta!
DORA:
Another branch!
Say it with us!
BOOTS AND DORA:
iSalta!
DORA:
Say salta!
BOOTS AND DORA:
iSalta!
BOOTS:
Go, Tico, go!
DORA:
Say salta!
BOOTS AND DORA:
iSalta!
DORA:
Again!
BOOTS AND DORA:
iSalta!
iVen, estrellita!
iGracias!
[ kisses]
De nada.
[ giggles]
Thank you for helping
Tico find me!
DORA:
Now let's help Tico get down.
To tell Tico to jump, say salta.
BOOTS AND DORA:
iSalta!
Hooray!
BOTH: Yay!
iFantástico!
iMuy bien!
Awesome, Tico.
Where do we go next?
Where do we go next?!
Bridge, Tree, Tall Mountain.
We went over the Bridge,
past the Tree
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Tall Mountain, right!
Now, where's the Tall Mountain?
Do you see the Tall Mountain?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the Tall Mountain!
Right underneath
the moon!
Come on,
we're almost home!
Moon, Moon!
I'm coming home!
Hurry! It's getting late!
It's getting late!
I'm almost home!
We made it to the top
of the Tall Mountain!
Hurry! There's
almost no time
left!
LITTLE STAR:
Oh, no, oh, no, oh, no, oh, no!
Dora, how are we
going to get
Little Star back up
to the Moon?
How, how,
how, how, how?
Wait a minute!
I've got it!
We can throw her
up to the Moon!
Good thinking!
But hurry! Hurry!
We need your help.
Will you help us throw
Little Star back up to the Moon?
You will? Great!
First, cup your hands
together.
Cup your hands!
Now, on the count
of three
I need you to throw
your hands up in the air.
ALL:
One...
two...
three!
ALL:
Yay!
She made it!
I'm home!
She made it all the
way back to the moon.
Good throw!
And now we can make
our wish.
BOTH [ whispering]:
Star light, star bright
first star I see tonight.
I wish I may, I wish I might
have this wish I wish tonight.
Now whisper your wish.
I wish I could see
Little Star every night.
I wish that I was
eating a banana.
Quiero muchas nueces.
I wish all my friends
could have flowers.
I really want a new teddy bear.
Now you whisper
your wish.
Look! She's twinkling!
That means she heard
our wishes.
I hope all your
wishes come true!
BOTH:
We did it!
[ music playing]
BOTH:
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
♪ iLo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went over the bridge
and past the Troll, yeah ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Hooray! ♪
BOOTS: ♪ We went
up the mountain ♪
♪ to throw Little Star
home, yeah ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Swiper hid Little Star
in Tico's tree ♪
♪ We said,
"Salta, Tico, salta"
and we found
him, hooray! ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such
an exciting trip today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part
was when we all
helped find Little
Star in Tico's tree.
My favorite part was
when we threw Little Star
up to the Moon.
We couldn't have gotten
Little Star back home
and made our wish
without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
DORA:
This is my friend
Baby Blue Bird.
Find Baby Blue Bird!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ giggles]
[ peeps]
[ click, beep]
[ giggles, laughs]