Boots:
DORA!
Dora:
BOOTS!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Kids:
♪ D-D-D-D-D-DORA♪
LET'S GO.
♪ DORA, DORA, DORA
THE EXPLORER♪
DORA!
♪ BOOTS AND SUPERCOOL
EXPLORADORA. ♪
Dora:
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
Boots:
GRAB YOUR BACKPACK!
♪ LET'S GO, JUMP IN...♪
VAMONOS!
♪ YOU CAN LEAD THE WAY♪
HEY! HEY!
♪ D-D-DORA, D-D-D-DORA♪
♪ SWIPER, NO SWIPING♪
OH, MAN!
I SEE YOU!
[ giggles]
HI, I'M DORA.
I'M PLAYING "I SPY."
[ whoops, screeches]
I SPY...
A CUTE LITTLE MONKEY.
DO YOU SEE A MONKEY?
WHERE?
RIGHT, IN THE TREE!
THAT'S MY FRIEND
BOOTS THE MONKEY.
BOOTS!
DORA!
[ both laugh]
HEY, BOOTS, YOU WANT
TO PLAY "I SPY"?
I SPY, I SPY, I SPY!
I SPY...
A PIRATE PARROT.
A PIRATE PARROT?
DO YOU SEE
YOU DO?
WHERE?
WOW! A PIRATE PARROT.
AHOY, MATEYS.
I AM THE PIRATE PARROT,
YO HO HO!
[ whistles]
ARE YOU LOOKING
FOR THE BLUE KEY?
THE BLUE KEY?
WHAT'S THE BLUE KEY?
WHY, IT'S THE KEY
TO THE LOST TREASURE CHEST.
TREASURE CHEST?
THAT'S RIGHT, TREASURE CHEST.
AND WHOEVER FINDS THE BLUE KEY
WILL GET LOTS AND LOTS
OF TREASURE.
[ whistles]
UH...
PIRATE PARROT?
WHAT'S IN
THE TREASURE CHEST?
[ squawks]
GOLD! GOLD!
PIRATE TREASURE ALWAYS HAS
LOTS OF GOLD.
AND TOYS?
YES!
BEADS?
YES.
[ whistles]
CHOCOLATE CUPCAKES
WITH PINK ICING?
YES!
STICKERS?
[ squawks]
YES!
I WANT TO LOOK
FOR THE BLUE KEY.
ME, TOO.
GOOD LUCK.
[ whistles]
I NEED YOUR HELP.
IF YOU SEE THE BLUE KEY,
SAY "KEY."
Dora:
DO YOU SEE
THE BLUE KEY?
WHERE?
THAT'S IT!
THAT'S THE BLUE KEY
THAT OPENS
THE TREASURE CHEST.
THE BLUE KEY.
YOU FOUND IT.
THANK YOU.
GRACIAS.
COME ON, DORA
LET'S GO OPEN
THE TREASURE CHEST.
BUT WAIT A MINUTE,
BOOTS.
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE
THE TREASURE CHEST IS.
OH.
WHO DO WE ASK FOR HELP
WHEN WE DON'T KNOW
WHICH WAY TO GO?
THE MAP! THE MAP!
THE MAP, THAT'S RIGHT.
MAYBE THE MAP
CAN TELL US
WHERE TO FIND
THE TREASURE CHEST.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU CHECK THE MAP AND FIND
OUT WHERE THE TREASURE CHEST IS?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "MAP."
SAY "MAP,"
SAY "MAP."
LOUDER.
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GO ♪
♪ I'M THE ONE YOU NEED TO KNOW ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ IF THERE'S A PLACE
YOU GOT TO GET ♪
♪ I CAN GET YOU THERE, I BET ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
♪ I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP,
I'M THE MAP, I'M THE MAP ♪
I'M THE MAP!
[ song ends]
AHOY, MATEYS.
TODAY I'M A TREASURE MAP.
DORA NEEDS YE
TO FIND THE OLE TREASURE CHEST.
DO YOU SEE THE TREASURE CHEST?
RIGHT!
THE TREASURE CHEST IS HERE
ON TREASURE ISLAND.
TO GET TO TREASURE ISLAND
FIRST YOU HAVE TO GO PAST
THE LOOKOUT TREE
THEN ACROSS CROCODILE LAKE...
AND THAT'S HOW YOU GET
TO TREASURE ISLAND.
SO HERE'S WHAT YOU TELL DORA:
TREE...
LAKE...
TREASURE ISLAND.
SAY IT WITH ME.
TREE, LAKE, TREASURE ISLAND.
TREE, LAKE, TREASURE ISLAND!
HOW DO WE GET
TO TREASURE ISLAND?
TREE...
LAKE...
TREASURE ISLAND.
FIRST WE HAVE TO GO PAST
THE LOOKOUT TREE
THEN WE CROSS CROCODILE LAKE
AND THAT'S HOW WE GET
TO TREASURE ISLAND.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
SO FIRST WE HAVE TO GO PAST
THE LOOKOUT TREE.
DO YOU SEE
THE LOOKOUT TREE?
OVER THERE?
THERE'S
THE LOOKOUT TREE.
COME ON, DORA.
LET'S GET THE TREASURE.
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US.
TREE, LAKE, TREASURE ISLAND.
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TREASURE ISLAND. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE
WE GOING? ♪
♪ TREASURE ISLAND. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
All:
♪ TREASURE ISLAND. ♪
[ laughing]
[ music ends]
[ Swiper rustles]
Both:
WHAT WAS THAT?
THAT SOUNDED LIKE
SWIPER THE FOX.
THAT SNEAKY FOX.
IF HE SEES THE BLUE KEY,
HE'LL TRY TO SWIPE IT.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
IF YOU SEE
SWIPER THE FOX
YELL "SWIPER."
YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
Both:
IT'S THE FOX!
WE NEED YOUR HELP
TO STOP SWIPER.
YOU HAVE TO SAY
"SWIPER, NO SWIPING."
SAY IT WITH US.
Both:
SWIPER, NO SWIPING.
OH, MAN.
HE ALMOST SWIPED
THE BLUE KEY.
THAT WAS CLOSE.
THANKS FOR HELPING US
STOP SWIPER.
LOOK, DORA.
WE MADE IT
TO THE LOOKOUT TREE.
ALL RIGHT!
WE'RE GOING TO FIND
THE TREASURE.
AND LOOK WHO'S UP ON TOP
OF THE LOOKOUT TREE.
IT'S THE PIRATE PARROT.
PIRATE PARROT.
AHOY.
[ squawks]
LOOK.
WE FOUND
THE BLUE KEY.
[ Pirate Parrot squawks]
GOOD WORK, ME HEARTIES.
PUT IT IN YOUR BACKPACK
FOR SAFE KEEPING.
NOW YOU'RE READY
TO FIND THE TREASURE.
YAY!
[ squawks]
ALL RIGHT, MATEYS,
LET'S GO!
CAREFUL, CAREFUL.
TO GET PAST THE LOOKOUT TREE
YOU HAVE TO CROSS
THE ICKY STICKY MUD.
WHAT'S THAT?
[ squawks]
TAKE ONE STEP
IN THE ICKY STICKY MUD
AND YOU'LL BE
STUCK THERE FOREVER.
OOH!OOH!
WE CAN'T GO
AROUND IT.
UNDER IT.
DO YOU SEE
ANYTHING WE CAN USE
TO GET ACROSS
THE ICKY STICKY MUD?
THAT?
THAT BOARD?
IT'S A PLANK.
YOU'LL HAVE TO WALK THE PLANK TO
GET ACROSS THE ICKY STICKY MUD.
WATCH ME.
GOOD LUCK.
[ squawks]
CAREFUL, BOOTS.
PUT YOUR ARMS OUT
LIKE A BIRD
SO YOU DON'T FALL.
WILL YOU HELP US
CROSS THE ICKY STICKY MUD?
GREAT!
PUT YOUR ARMS OUT
LIKE A BIRD.
HERE WE GO.
WHOA!
[ playing fanfare]
WE DID IT.
LOOK, BOOTS!
WE MADE IT ACROSS
THE ICKY STICKY MUD
AND PAST
THE LOOKOUT TREE.
THANKS FOR HELPING.
WHERE DO WE
GO NEXT?
TREE... LAKE... TREASURE ISLAND.
WE MADE IT PAST THE TREE
SO NOW WE HAVE TO GET TO...
THE LAKE, RIGHT--
CROCODILE LAKE.
DO YOU SEE A LAKE?
WHERE?
YEAH, THERE IT IS.
THERE'S CROCODILE LAKE.
COME ON, BOOTS,
LET'S GO GET THE...
TREASURE!
COME ON, SAY IT WITH US.
TREE, LAKE, TREASURE ISLAND.
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ COME ON, VAMONOS♪
♪ EVERYBODY, LET'S GO ♪
♪ COME ON,
LET'S GET TO IT ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT
WE CAN DO IT. ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
♪ TREASURE ISLAND ♪
♪ WHERE ARE
WE GOING? ♪
♪ TREASURE ISLAND ♪
♪ WHERE ARE WE GOING? ♪
All:
♪ TREASURE ISLAND. ♪
[ laughing]
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ TREASURE ISLAND. ♪
[ song ends]
OOH, CROCODILE LAKE!
WE MADE IT
TO CROCODILE LAKE!
COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON!
WE'RE ALMOST
TO TREASURE ISLAND.
THEN WE CAN
GET THAT GOLD!
AND TOYS!
CHOCOLATE CUPCAKES
WITH PINK ICING.
STICKERS!
HMM.
WE NEED TO CROSS
CROCODILE LAKE
SO WE CAN GET TO
TREASURE ISLAND.
WE NEED A BOAT.
I DON'T SEE
A BOAT.
DO YOU?
NO.
NO BOAT.
WHAT'S THAT?
YOUSEE A BOAT?
WHERE?
IT'S THE PIRATE
PARROT!
CLIMB ABOARD MY PIRATE
SHIP, ME HEARTIES.
NEXT STOP,
TREASURE ISLAND!
[ whistles]
THERE'S JUST ONE
LITTLE PROBLEM.
Both:
WHAT'S THAT?
CROCODILE LAKE
IS FILLED
WITH VERY BIG
CROCODILES.
Both:
OH!
NOW, NOW,
DON'T WORRY.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO IS
SING A SONG CALLED
♪ "GRANDE, GRANDE,
GRANDE." ♪
IN SPANISH
WE SAY "GRANDE."
WELL, THOSE CROCODILES
SURE ARE BIG!
UH-OH, HERE COME
THE CROCODILES!
[ Dora and Boots scream]
WILL YOU HELP US
SING TO THE CROCODILES?
GREAT!
FIRST HOLD YOUR ARMS OUT
REAL WIDE
TO SHOW THE CROCODILES
THAT THEY'RE REAL BIG.
NOW WE HAVE TO SING.
♪ GRANDE, GRANDE, GRANDE.♪
SING:
♪ GRANDE, GRANDE, GRANDE!♪
I AM
A BIG CROCODILE!
SOY UN COCODRILO
GRANDE!
LOOK!
UH-OH, ONE OF
THE CROCODILES
ISN'T DANCING.
WE'D BETTER
SING LOUDER!
♪ GRANDE, GRANDE, GRANDE!♪
LOOK,
HE'S DANCING!
THEY'RE ALL
DANCING!
Crocodiles:
♪ GRANDE, GRANDE, GRANDE!♪
♪ GRANDE, GRANDE,
GRANDE!♪
♪ GRANDE,
GRANDE, GRANDE!♪
THANKS FOR SINGING!
♪ GRANDE,
GRANDE, GRANDE!♪
LOOK! WE CROSSED
CROCODILE LAKE.
[ playing fanfare]
WHERE DO
WE GO NEXT?
TREE... LAKE... TREASURE ISLAND.
WE WENT PAST THE LOOKOUT TREE.
WE CROSSED CROCODILE LAKE.
SO NEXT IS... TREASURE ISLAND.
Both:
WE'RE ON
TREASURE ISLAND!
[ squawks]
WE'RE ALMOST
TO THE TREASURE CHEST.
DO YOU STILL HAVE
THE BLUE KEY?
[ gasps]
I THINK I LOST IT!
NO, BOOTS, I PUT IT
IN MY BACKPACK
FOR SAFEKEEPING.
REMEMBER?
I NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU CHECK MY BACKPACK
TO GET THE BLUE KEY?
YOU HAVE TO SAY "BACKPACK."
SAY "BACKPACK,"
SAY "BACKPACK."
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ I'M A BACKPACK LOADED UP WITH
THINGS AND KNICKKNACKS, TOO ♪
♪ ANYTHING THAT YOU MIGHT NEED
I GOT INSIDE FOR YOU. ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK ♪
♪ BACKPACK, BACKPACK. ♪
YEAH!
I HAVE LOTS OF BLUE STUFF.
BUT DORA NEEDS YOU
TO GET THE BLUE KEY.
IS THIS THE BLUE KEY?
IT IS?
GREAT!
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM--
DELICIOSO!
WHERE'S
THE TREASURE?
AH, THE PIRATE PIG--
HE BURIED THE TREASURE CHEST
A LONG TIME AGO.
[ squawks]
Both:
THE PIRATE PIG?
ONLY THE PIRATE PIG CAN TELL US
WHERE THE TREASURE IS BURIED.
DORA, HOW ARE WE GOING
TO FIND THE PIRATE PIG?
TA-DAH!
I'M THE PIRATE PIG!
THE PIRATE PIG!
AH! THE BLUE KEY.
YOU FOUND MY KEY.
♪ MY KEY, MY KEY,
MY KEY! ♪
GOOD WORK, ME HEARTIES!
NOW WE JUST HAVE
TO DIG UP MY TREASURE
AND I'LL SHARE THE
TREASURE WITH EVERYONE!
[ all cheer]
PIRATE PIG, BE CAREFUL
WITH THE KEY.
IF SWIPER THE SNEAKY
FOX SEES THE KEY
HE'LL TRY TO SWIPE IT.
IF YOU SEE THE FOX,
YELL "SWIPER."
YOU SEE SWIPER?
WHERE?
Dora and Boots:
SWIPER, NO... SWIPING.
YOU'RE TOO LATE!
YOU'LL NEVER
FIND IT NOW!
[ crying]
DON'T WORRY,
PIRATE PIGGIES.
IF WE ALL WORK TOGETHER,
WE CAN FIND YOUR BLUE KEY.
I NEED YOUR HELP
TO FIND THE BLUE KEY.
Dora:
LET'S LOOK
FOR EVERYTHING THAT'S BLUE.
IS THIS THE BLUE KEY?
IT'S BLUE, BUT IT'S NOT THE KEY.
LET'S KEEP LOOKING.
IS THIS THE BLUE KEY?
Boots:
YEAH! YOU FOUND IT!
ALL RIGHT, MATEYS
NOW THAT WE HAVE
THE BLUE KEY
WE HAVE TO GO TO
THE TREASURE CHEST.
WHERE IS IT?
I'VE BURIED IT
TO KEEP IT SAFE.
FOLLOW ME!
Boots:
WHERE'S THE TREASURE?
Pirate Pig:
I BURIED IT
UNDER ONE OF
THESE STONES.
WHICH STONE,
PIRATE PIG?
I'LL SHOW YOU.
FIRST WE HAVE
TO WALK EIGHT STEPS
ON THE RED STONES
THIS WAY.
COUNT WITH ME!
All:
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR
FIVE, SIX, SEVEN, EIGHT.
Pirate Pig:
NOW WE HAVE TO GO EIGHT STEPS
ON THE YELLOW PATH.
All:
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR
FIVE, SIX, SEVEN, EIGHT.
YOU DID IT!
NOW LET'S LOOK UNDER THIS STONE.
I'LL LIFT THE STONE.
YOU TELL ME IF YOU SEE AN "X."
[ groans]
DO YOU SEE AN "X"?
YOU DO?
"X" MARKS THE SPOT.
THIS IS WHERE
THE BURIED TREASURE IS!
All:
YAY! TREASURE!
ALL RIGHT!
YOU FOUND IT!
THE TREASURE CHEST
IS BURIED DEEP.
WE'LL HAVE TO DIG
TO GET IT OUT.
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU HELP US DIG
TO FIND THE TREASURE?
GREAT.
FIRST PUT YOUR HANDS
OUT IN FRONT OF YOU.
PUT YOUR HANDS OUT
IN FRONT OF YOU!
GET READY TO DIG.
NOW DIG, DIG, DIG!
DIG, DIG, DIG!
WE FOUND SOMETHING!
GREAT DIGGING.
All:
THE TREASURE CHEST!
OOH!
All:
TREASURE!
GOLD! GOLD! GOLD!
TOYS!
BEADS!
AND CHOCOLATE
CUPCAKES
WITH PINK ICING!
STICKERS!
YAY! WE DID IT!
♪ ♪ ♪
Both:
♪ WE DID IT! ♪
♪ YAY! ♪
♪  LO HICIMOS! ♪
♪ WE DID IT. ♪
♪ ♪ ♪
♪ WE WENT PAST
LOOKOUT TREE ♪
♪ AND ACROSS THE LAKE ♪
♪ WE DID IT, WE DID IT,
WE DID IT! HOORAY! ♪
♪ WE FOUND
THE TREASURE CHEST ♪
♪ BURIED UNDERGROUND ♪
♪ WE DID IT, WE DID IT,
WE DID IT, WE DID IT ♪
♪ PIRATE PARROT HELPED US
ALONG THE WAY ♪
♪ WE GOT PAST THE STICKY MUD,
WE MADE IT-- HOORAY! ♪
YAY! WOO! HOORAY!
WE DID IT!
[ music ends]
WOO!
[ arrow beeps]
WE HAD SUCH
A FUN TRIP TODAY.
WHAT WAS YOUR FAVORITE
PART OF THE TRIP?
I LIKED THAT, TOO.
MY FAVORITE PART WAS
FINDING
THE TREASURE CHEST.
MY FAVORITE PART WAS
GETTING ALL THOSE BIG
CROCODILES TO DANCE.
Both:
♪ GRANDE, GRANDE, GRANDE!♪
WE COULDN'T HAVE
FOUND THE TREASURE
WITHOUT YOU.
THANKS FOR HELPING!
Dora:
THIS IS MY FRIEND
BABY BLUE BIRD.
FIND BABY BLUE BIRD.
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
[Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ child giggling]