Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by The
U.S. Department of Education
and Nickelodeon]
Hi, I'm Dora.
I'm fishing on the river.
Do you see any fish?
Yeah, there's some!
I hope I catch one.
Oh! I caught something!
Wow, it's heavy.
It's too heavy.
I need your help
to wind up my fishing line.
Will you help me wind up
my fishing line?
Great!
Hold your fishing pole
with one hand.
Now make a circle with your
other hand to wind it up.
Wind it up!
It's working!
Keep winding, keep winding!
Keep winding!
Whoa! Here it comes!
We caught a, we caught a...
What are they?
What?
Boots!
That's myname.
My name is Boots.
[ laughing]
Oh, hi, Boots!
We were just saying
what we found
in the river.
Look, it's a pair
of big yellow boots!
Ah, boots!
That's funny.
[ laughing]
Boots, boots...
Boots, boots!
[ laughing]
I love my boots!
That's why my name is Boots.
[ tap-dancing,
music playing...]
♪ I love my boots,
my boots and me ♪
♪ They help me swing
from tree to tree ♪
♪ I feel so happy
with them on my feet ♪
♪ We're best friends,
yeah, my boots and me ♪
♪ I love my boots,
yeah, my boots and me... ♪
Whoa!
Oh, no!
My boot!
Dora, my boot
is floating away.
Where is the river
taking it?
I don't know.
I'm not sure
where the river goes.
But I have to get my boot back.
Let's check the Map.
The Map knows
where the river goes.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map and
find out where the river goes?
You have to say "Map"!
Say "Map"!
Both:
Louder!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots need to find out
where the river goes
so they can get
Boots' boot back.
Well, I know
where the river goes.
First, the river goes
under the bridge.
And then it goes
past the Froggy Rocks.
And then it gets
to the waterfall!
So you tell Dora:
Bridge...
rocks...
waterfall!
Say it with me:
Bridge...
rocks...
waterfall!
Bridge... rocks... waterfall!
Where does the river go?
Bridge...
rocks...
waterfall.
The river goes under the bridge
past the Froggy Rocks
and then it gets
to the waterfall.
Thanks for helping.
Now, where's the bridge?
Do you see the bridge?
[ click, beep]
Yeah! There it is!
Come on, Dora!
Let's go get my boot.
My boot! My boot!
My boot!
How are we going to
get my boot?
We need something
to ride on the river.
Then we can catch
the boot.
Do you see anything we can use
to ride on the river?
[ click, beep]
The boat! Right!
Good thinking!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
A boat! A boat!
But look, the boat
has holes in it.
It's missing some pieces.
Oh, no!
Where are
the missing pieces?
Do you see
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there are
the missing pieces.
Right there.
Great!
Let's count the holes
and then we can fill the holes
with the missing pieces.
Count with us.
Both:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven!
Dora:
Seven holes.
Now count the missing pieces.
Both:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven!
Dora:
Now let's put the missing pieces
into the holes.
Count with us.
Both:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
Is that enough?
How many more
do we need?
Two more.
Both:
Six...
seven!
Thanks!
Good counting.
Yay! Now we can
go find my boot.
[ rustling]
Boots, did you
hear that?
We better watch out
for Swiper the fox.
Yeah, that
sneaky fox
will try to
swipe our boat.
Can you help us look for Swiper?
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
Whoop!
You see Swiper?
Where?
I don't see him!
Where is he now?
Behind the tree?
There he is!
We need your help
to stop Swiper.
You have to say
"Swiper, no swiping!"
Say it with us...
Both:
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Thanks for helping us
stop Swiper.
Life jackets.
So we can be safe.
Come on, Boots.
Let's go
get your boot!
All right!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Bridge, rocks, waterfall.
Bridge, rocks,
waterfall.
Bridge, rocks, waterfall!
♪ Come on, vamonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Waterfall! ♪
All:
[ both laughing]
♪ Waterfall! ♪
We made it
to the bridge!
But, Dora,
where's my boot?
I don't know, Boots.
I don't see it.
Do you see Boots' boot?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Right!
Look, there's your boot.
It's on the other side
of the bridge.
All right!
Let's go get it!
Oh, no!
This boat won't fit
under the bridge.
I've got to get my boot!
Don't worry, Boots.
The bridge can open up
and let us through.
It can?
Yeah, we just
need to find
someone
who can open it.
Do you see anyone
who can open the bridge?
The squirrel?
Right!
That's Tico.
Tico can open
the bridge for us.
Tico, open the bridge,
please!
Remember, Boots,
Tico speaks Spanish.
So, we have to
say "abre".
Say "abre"
to open the bridge.
Can you say "abre"?
Say it with us.
Both:
iAbre!
Louder!
Both:
iAbre!
Abre? iSi!
He said yes!
[ play happy tune]
Yay!
We made it
under the bridge!
All right!
Thank you for helping us
say "abre."
Thank you, Tico!
Gracias,Tico.
De nada.
My boot, my boot!
Dora, where do we
go next?
Bridge... rocks... waterfall.
We made it under the bridge
so next we go to...
[ click, beep]
The rocks! Right!
The Froggy Rocks.
Now where are the rocks?
Do you see the rocks?
Where?
[ click, beep]
Yeah! There they are!
All right!
Let's go!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Bridge, rocks, waterfall.
Bridge, rocks,
waterfall.
Bridge, rocks, waterfall!
♪ Come on, vamonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Waterfall! ♪
All:
[ both laughing]
♪ Waterfall! ♪
I see my boot!
Careful, Boots.
The river's
going faster!
And my boot
is going faster!
Look, your boot is going
under those branches.
Both:
Branches!
How are we
going to get
under the
branches?
We'll have to
duck down
or we'll bump our heads
on the branches.
Will you duck your head so
we can get under the branches?
Great!
When I say duck, duck your head.
Here comes
the first branch.
Duck your head!
Uh-oh, here comes
another branch!
Duck your head!
Yikes!
Duck!
Oh, no.
It's another branch!
Duck!
Wow! We made it past
all those branches!
Good ducking.
Come on, Dora.
Let's go get
my boot.
All right!
Let's go!
Come on, say it with us.
Both:
Bridge, rocks, waterfall.
Bridge, rocks,
waterfall.
Bridge, rocks, waterfall!
♪ Come on, vamonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Waterfall! ♪
All:
[ both laughing]
♪ Waterfall! ♪
[ ribbiting...]
Hey, Boots,
do you hear that?
[ ribbiting...]
Yeah, what is it?
What animal goes
"ribbit, ribbit"?
[ ribbiting...]
Right! Frogs!
That must mean
we're at the...
Both:
Froggy Rocks!
[ ribbiting...]
Uh-oh, those rocks
sure look big.
We have to row
around the rocks
or we'll crash
right into them.
We need your help to row
the boat around the rocks.
Put your hands out in front
of you and start rowing.
Row, row, row!
Row, row, row! Row, row, row!
Both:
Whew!
That was close.
[ play happy tune]
We made it past
the Froggy Rocks.
Thanks for rowing.
Hey, Dora, look!
I see my boot!
I see my...
My boot's gone again.
Where is it going,
Dora?
Bridge...
rocks...
waterfall.
We went under the bridge...
past the Froggy Rocks....
and next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Both: Waterfall!
The waterfall!
Boots:
Oh, no!
My boot!
It's going over the waterfall.
Uh-oh! Wemight go
over the waterfall, too!
Ooh, ooh, ooh!
Ah, ah, ah!
We've got to row away
from the waterfall.
Now put your hands out in front
of you and row, row, row!
Row, row, row!
But Dora, how are we
going to get my boot?
We can't go
over the waterfall.
We need a way
to go around it.
I need your help to see
if there's another way
around the waterfall.
Do you see another way to go?
You do? Where?
[ click, beep]
Boots:
Yeah, look!
A little river!
It's like
a water slide.
Dora:
Everybody say "Whee!"
Both:
Whee!
[ both laughing]
Both:
We made it past the waterfall!
But where's my boot?
Don't worry, Boots.
If we all work together,
we can find your red boot.
I need your help to find
Boots' red boot.
First let's look
for everything that it red.
This is red.
[ click, beep]
[ bell dings]
That's a buoy.
This is red.
[ click, beep]
That's a butterfly.
This is red.
[ click, beep]
That's a fish.
This is red.
Is this the red boot?
[ click, beep]
Right! There it is!
Boots:
There, there!
You found it!
Good looking!
My boot! My boot!
Now we can get
my boot!
I love my boot,
I love my boot.
I love... my...
Whoa!
Careful, Boots!
You almost fell
in the water.
But my boot!
I think I might have
something in my backpack
that can help us
get your boot.
I need your help.
Will you check my backpack
and find something
we can use
to fish out the boot?
You have to say "Backpack".
Say "Backpack"!
Both:
Louder!
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack,
Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
Hola.
I have lots of stuff.
But Dora and Boots need to find
something to fish out the boot.
Will this help them
fish out the boot?
[ click, beep]
A fishing pole will help them
fish out the boot.
Good thinking!
iMuy bien!
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
The fishing pole!
Great!
Now let's get
that boot!
[ grunting]
Come on, Boots.
You can do it!
I... got it!
Good work!
Now we have to
wind it up.
Will you help us
wind up the fishing line
so we can get the boot?
Great!
Hold your fishing pole
with one hand.
Now make a circle with
your other hand to wind it up.
Wind it up!
It's working!
Keep winding!
Here it comes...
Both:
Yay!
My boot, my boot!
[ rustling]
Oh, no!
Did you hear that?
That sound like
Swiper the fox!
Oh, no!
He's going to swipe
my boot!
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
You see Swiper?
Where?
Oh, no! It's Swiper!
We need you to help stop Swiper.
You have to say
"Swiper, no swiping!"
Say it with us.
Both:
Swiper, no swiping.
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Thanks for helping us
stop Swiper.
My boot! My boot!
I'm so happy!
I love my boots!
[ tap-dancing,
music playing...]
♪ I love my boots,
my boots and me ♪
♪ They help me swing
from tree to tree ♪
♪ I feel so happy
with 'em on my feet ♪
♪ We're best friends,
yeah, my boots and me ♪
♪ I love my boots,
♪ I love my boots, yeah,
my boots and me! ♪
Both:
Yay!
We did it!
Both:
♪ We did it ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
♪ Lo hicimos♪
Both:
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went under the bridge
and past the rocks ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! Hooray! ♪
♪ We went around
the waterfall ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! We did it! ♪
♪ We said "abre"
at the bridge ♪
♪ so we could
get through ♪
♪ I lost my boot
in the river... ♪
♪ But we found it,
whoo-hoo! ♪
Both:
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such a fun day
on the river.
What was
your favorite part?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part was
getting my boot back.
My favorite part was going
around the waterfall.
It was like a water slide.
Whee!
We couldn't have found
Boots' boot without you.
Thanks for helping.
[ click, beep]
Dora:
This is my friend the Map.
Find the Map!
[ click, beep]
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ click, beep]
[ giggles, laughs]