Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
Hi, I'm Dora.
And this is
my friend Boots.
And my wonderful
grandma, mi Abuela.
Can you say Abuela?
Say Abuela.
Ooh... muy bien!
You said that so well.
Abuela, will you
tell us a story
about when you were
a little girl?
Oh, sí.
When I was your age, I had
a special chocolatetree.
A chocolate tree?!A chocolate tree?!
Oh, Abuela,
tell us the story!
Tell us! Tell us!
When I was a little girl
just like you, Dora
I lived in a little house.
And near my house there grew
the sweetest little
chocolate tree.
This tree wasmi querido amigo,
my dear friend.
We used to play together.
And if I was sad,
he would give me a big hug
and make me feel better.
TheChocolate Tree
taught me a song
to help make thechocolate.
The tree would wiggle
his tree trunk and sing:
BOTH:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
♪ Mix your chocolate,
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate!♪
But Abuela, what happened
to the Chocolate Tree?
Yeah, what happened
to the tree?
When I grew up
our family moved far away
from the ChocolateTree.
Abuela, will you teach us
the ChocolateSong?
Con mucho gusto.
Will you sing the ChocolateSong
with us?
Great!
Sing along
with Abuela.
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
BOOTS AND DORA:
♪ Bate, bate,
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
♪ Mix your chocolate,
chocolate♪
BOOTS AND DORA:
♪ Mix your chocolate,
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
BOOTS AND DORA:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate!♪
[ giggling and laughing]
iMuy bien!Very good!
Abuela!
I loved the story
of the Chocolate Tree.
Me, too.
I really miss
that ChocolateTree.
She misses her tree.
I've got an idea!
Maybe we can find
Abuela's Chocolate Tree
and bring her
some chocolate!
Ooh, ooh, ah, ah!
Yes, sir!
Oh, she would be
so happy.
And then she could make
us a chocolate treat!
Chocolate, chocolate, chocolate!
Mmm...
Yummy!
Let's go get chocolate
for Abuela!
Hey, Dora, how are we going
to find the Chocolate Tree?
Let's stop and think.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map!
The Map, that's right!
The Map can tell us
how to find
the Chocolate Tree.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find out how to get
to the Chocolate Tree?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map," say "Map"!
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots want to find
Abuela's special Chocolate Tree.
Well, I know how to get
to the Chocolate Tree.
First you go
through the Jungle...
then you go past
the Bear's Cave...
and that's how you get
to the Chocolate Tree
so you can bring chocolate
to Abuela!
So here's what you tell Dora:
Jungle...
Cave...
Chocolate Tree.
Say it with me.
Jungle...
Cave...
Chocolate Tree.
Jungle...
Cave...
Chocolate Tree.
Jungle...
Cave...
Chocolate Tree...!
How do we find
the Chocolate Tree?
Jungle...
Cave...
Chocolate Tree.
First we go through the Jungle.
Then we go past the Bear's Cave.
And that's how we'll get
to the Chocolate Tree.
Thanks for helping!
So first we have to
find the Jungle.
Do you see a jungle?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's the Jungle!
Come on, let's go get
chocolate for Abuela!
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Jungle, Cave, Chocolate Tree.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Chocolate Tree ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Chocolate Tree ♪
ALL:
♪ Chocolate Tree! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Chocolate Tree! ♪
Cuidado! Cuidado!
Who's that?
Look, it's Señor Tucán!
Cuidado! Cuidado!
Cuidado!
Señor Tucán wants us
to watch out!
Dora! Boots!
En la selva hay...
iTortugas mordedoras!
In the Jungle there
are snapping turtles!
iCulebras largas!
Long... snakes.
iY un cocodrilo grande!
And one big
crocodile!
Necesitan galletas
para dar a los animales.
The animals won't
let us go by
unless we feed them
some cookies.
Gracias, Señor Tucán.
De nada.
I have some cookies
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
to find the cookies?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iHola!
I have lots of stuff,
but Dora needs cookies
to feed las tortugas,
las culebras, y el cocodrilo.
The cookies are
in a round container
that's yellow with a blue star.
Do you see a round container
that's yellow with a blue star?
Where?
[ click, beep]
You found the cookies!
iMuy bien! Excelente!
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum!
iDelicioso!
Thanks.
Now we have 12 cookies.
Ooh, I hope it's enough.
Come on...
Look! iTortugas!
Ooh, snapping turtles!
Give us your cookies!
Or we won't let you by!
ALL:
Snap, snap, snap,
snap, snap, snap...
Let's count the snapping turtles
to see how many cookies we need.
Count with me.
BOOTS AND DORA:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight!
DORA:
Eight snapping turtles.
Now let's feed the turtles
the cookies.
Count with me.
BOTH:
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight!
Good counting.
ALL:
Snap, snap, snap,
snap, snap, snap...
All right, you can go by.
Dora, do we have
any cookies left?
How many cookies
do we have left?
We had 12 cookies.
We gave away eight
so now we have...
Four, right!
Four cookies.
Ooh, I hope
it's enough.
Look, iculebras!
Give us your cookies!
Or we won't
let you by.
[ all hissing]
We have to give them
their cookies!
How many snakes
are there?
Count with me.
One...
two...
three.
Now let's feed the snakes.
Count with me.
BOTH:
One...
two...
three!
[ gobbling]
[ all gulp]
[ hisses]
Okay, you can go by.
How many cookies
do we have left?
We had four cookies
we gave away three
and now we have...
one cookie left.
Right!
One cookie left...
How many crocodiles are there?
Great!
I won't let you by
unless you give me
a cookie.
We've got a cookie
for you, cocodrilo.
[ chomps, gulps]
All right...
you can go by.
[ play happy tune]
We made it
through the Jungle!
Where do we go next,
Dora?
Jungle...
Cave...
Chocolate Tree.
We made it through the Jungle
so next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Cave, right.
The Bear's Cave.
Now, where is
the Bear's Cave?
Do you see a cave?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's a cave.
The Bear's Cave!
Come on, let's go get
chocolate for Abuela.
Come on, say it with us!
BOTH:
Jungle, Cave, Chocolate Tree.
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Chocolate Tree ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Chocolate Tree ♪
ALL:
♪ Chocolate Tree! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Chocolate Tree! ♪
Dora, what happens
if we meet... the Bear?
We better be careful.
BOTH:
Aah!
Sorry. I didn't mean
to scare you.
Boots, it's not the Bear.
It's Isa the Iguana.
Hi, Dora.
Hi, Boots.
Come on, Isa.
Where are you going?
We're going
to the Chocolate Tree
to get chocolate for my Abuela.
But first we have to go
past the Bear's Cave.
Oh. Well, you better be
ready to sing a song.
BOTH: A song? Why?
The Bear likes songs,
and they put him to sleep.
I hope you know a song
to sing to this bear.
BOTH: We know a song!
[ whispering]:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate.♪
♪ Bate, bate,
chocolate...♪
[ whispers]:
No Bear.
Where is the Bear?
Oh-oh,
here he comes!
We have to sing
to put the Bear to sleep!
Will you help us sing
the ChocolateSong?
Great. Sing with us.
ALL:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
♪ Mix your chocolate,
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate,
chocolate!♪
[ yawns]
Chocolate,mmm, yummy.
[ whispering]:
It's working!
Sing very softly!
Sing with me!
ALL [ softly]:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
♪ Mix your chocolate...
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate.♪
[ yawns]
Chocolate.
[ snoring]
[ whispering]:
It worked! Look!
The Bear is sleeping!
Thanks, Isa!
Come on, let's go get
chocolate for Abuela.
[ play happy tune]
[ yawns]
Phew!
We made it past the Bear's Cave!
Where do we go next?
Jungle...
Cave...
Chocolate Tree.
We made it through the Jungle.
We made it past the Bear's Cave.
So next comes the...
[ click, beep]
Chocolate Tree! Right!
We should be able to see
the Chocolate Tree from here.
I don't see it.
Do you see
the Chocolate Tree?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's
the Chocolate Tree!
You found it!
Come on! iVámonos!
DORA:
Chocolate Tree!
Hola.
Look, Boots.
It's the
Chocolate Tree.
Little girl, you
remind of someone--
another little girl
I used to know
a long time ago.
That's mi Abuela.
She's all grown up now.
So am I!
[ chuckles]
She taught us
your chocolatesong.
Really? Can you
sing it for me?
Sure!
Will you help us sing
the ChocolateSong
for the Chocolate Tree?
Great! Sing with us!
BOTH:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
♪ Mix your chocolate,
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate!♪
[ laughs]
iMuy bien!
iExcelente!
That was wonderful!
Chocolate Tree,
Abuela misses you.
Aw, I miss her,
too, little monkey.
Ah, but I've got
an idea.
Here, give her this.
It has chocolate
beans inside.
You can plant it
for Abuela.
Gracias, ChocolateTree.
Thanks.
[ rustling]
Boots, did you
hear that?
That sounds like
Swiper the fox.
That sneaky fox will try
to swipe our chocolate beans!
I need your help!
If you see the fox,
yell "Swiper!"
We have to say,
"Swiper, no swiping."
ALL:
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
Thanks for helping us
stop Swiper.
You better
run on home now.
♪ Bate, bate,
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate...♪
BOTH:
A Chocolate Tree!
Abuela!
Look!
A ChocolateTree!
Right in my backyard!
Hola.
ALL:
iHola!
[ giggling]
Hey, Chocolate Tree,
can we have some chocolate?
Anytime you like.
BOTH:
Yay!
I think it is time
to mix up a batch
of the most
delicious chocolateever!
Will you help us
make the chocolate?
Great.
First you put
your hands together
to hold your big spoon.
Now...
mix the chocolate!
Mix the chocolate.
Mix, mix, mix!
Now sing with me
while you mix the chocolate!
ALL:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
♪ Mix your chocolate,
chocolate!♪
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate!♪
We have to sing faster if
we're going to make chocolate!
Sing faster!
Mix your chocolate
and sing with us!
ALL [ faster]:
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate♪
♪ Mix your chocolate,
chocolate♪
♪ Bate, bate, chocolate!♪
It's ready.
Oh boy, oh boy! Yes!
ALL:
Mmm...!
That's the best chocolate
I ever had.
I told you!
BOOTS, DORA, TREE:
We did it!
[ music playing]
BOTH:
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ Yay! ♪
♪ iLo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went
through the jungle ♪
♪ and past the cave ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
BOOTS:
♪ We did it!
Hooray! ♪
♪ We helped Abuela ♪
♪ grow the
Chocolate Tree ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We gave cookies
to the turtles ♪
♪ and they went away ♪
♪ We sang the Bear to
sleep and got past him ♪
♪ Hooray! ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such
an exciting trip
to the Chocolate Tree.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that, too.
My favorite part was
singing to the Bear.
My favorite part was making
chocolate with mi Abuela.
We couldn't have found
the Chocolate Tree without you.
Thanks for helping.
[ click, beep]
DORA:
This is my friend the Wizzle.
Can you find the Wizzle?
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
Over here!
[ laughing]
Whoops.
Yoo-hoo!
Here I am!
Psst!
Hey!
[ click, beep]
You found me!
[ laughing]
[ giggles, laughs]