Dora!
Boots!
Come on, Dora!
♪ Do-Do-Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
All right!
Let's go!
♪ Dora, Dora,
Dora the Explorer ♪
Dora!
♪ Boots and super-cool
explorer Dora ♪
Need your help,
so grab your backpack.
♪ Let's go, jump in ♪
iVámonos!
♪ You can lead the way ♪
♪ Hey, hey! ♪
♪ Do-Do-Dora, Do-Do-D-Dora ♪
♪ Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping! ♪
Oh, man!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON]
[ birds chirping...]
Hi, I'm Dora.
And I'm Boots.
[ beep, mooing]
What animal makes
that sound?
A cow! A cow!
Right, a cow goes
"Moo! Moo!"
Boots and I
are reading a book
about animals and
what sounds they make.
[ beep]
Cock-a-doodledoo!
What animal makes
that sound?
A rooster,
a rooster!
A rooster, right!
A rooster says,
"Cock-a-doodledoo!
Cock-a-doodledoo!"
[ both giggle]
Hey, Dora,
what sound
does the little
frog make?
That's a special
kind of frog, Boots.
Listen.
[ beep]
iCoquí! iCoquí!
That's a funny
frog, Dora.
This little frog
is called a coquí
just like his song.
[ beep]
iCoquí! iCoquí!
[ strums guitar]
Look, it's
a little frog!
And he has
a guitar!
iUna guitarra!
Hey, Dora, he looks
just like
the picture
of the coquí!
Hey, Boots,
I think he is a coquí!
Ooh-ooh, ah-ah!
Maybe he'll sing
for us.
Sing, Coquí, sing!
[ whispers hoarsely]:
Coquí, coquí.
Dora, I don't think
he can sing.
Boots, it says
in this book
that Coquí lives
on a beautiful island.
Uh-oh! If he leaves
the island
and is away from his
family and friends
he gets sick
and he can't sing!
Coquí, is that true?
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí.
Don't worry, Coquí.
Boots, we have to
take Coquí home.
So he can sing!
[ whispers]:
Coquí.
Come on, let's go!
Boots!
Yeah, Dora?
We need to find out
how to getto Coquí's Island.
Who do we ask for help
when we don't know
which way to go?
The Map! The Map!
The Map, that's right.
The Map can tell us how to get
Coquí home to his island.
I need your help.
Will you check the Map
and find out how to get
to Coquí's Island?
You have to say "Map."
Say "Map,"
say "Map!"
[ fingers snapping,
music playing...]
♪ If there's a place
you got to go ♪
♪ I'm the one you need to know ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ If there's a place
you got to get ♪
♪ I can get you there, I bet ♪
♪ I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map,
I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map, I'm the Map ♪
♪ I'm the Map! ♪
Dora and Boots want to know
how to get to Coquí's Island
so Coquí can sing.
Well, I know how to get
to Coquí's Island.
First, you go through
the Echo Bush.
Through the Echo Bush!
Then you go over the Ocean.
And that's how you get
to Coquí's Island.
Coquís:
Coquí, coquí!
So you tell Dora:
Bush...
Ocean...
Coquí's Island.
Say it with me.
Bush...
Ocean...
Coquí's Island.
Bush...
Ocean...
Coquí's Island.
Bush...
Ocean...
Coquí's Island!
How do we get to Coquí's Island?
Bush...
Ocean...
Coquí's Island.
First we go through the...
Echo Bush...
Through the...
then over the Ocean...
and that's how we'll get
to Coquí's Island
to take Coquí home.
Coquís:
Coquí, Coquí!
So he can sing!
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí.
First we have to find
the Echo Bush.
Do you see an Echo Bush?
[ click, beep]
Hey, yeah,
there's the Echo Bush!
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí!
All right!
Come on, ivámonos!
Let's take Coquí home!
So he can sing!
Come on, say it with us.
BOTH:
Bush, Ocean, Coquí's Island!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Coquí's Island ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Coquí's Island ♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí's Island! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Coquí's Island! ♪
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí.
Don't worry, Coquí,
we're almost...
[ rustling]
Did you hear that?
That sounds like
Swiper the fox!
That sneaky fox is always
trying to swipe our stuff.
DORA:
He'll try to swipe
Coquí's guitarra!
I need your help.
If you see Swiper the fox,
yell "Swiper."
Do you see Swiper the fox?
Where?
Yeah!
Help us stop Swiper.
You have to say,
"Swiper, no swiping!"
Say it with us.
BOTH:
Swiper, no swiping,
Swiper, no swiping
Swiper, no swiping!
Oh, man!
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí.
Yes! We stopped Swiper!
Thanks for helping us.
Come on, let's take Coquí home!
So he can sing!
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí.
iVámonos!
Who said that?
Yeah, who's talking?
The bush talks!
That bush says
everything we say.
Is that the Echo Bush?
BOTH [ whispering]:
It's the Echo Bush!
[ giggle]
[ giggles]
Ooh-ooh! Ah-ah!
[ both laugh]
[ laughs]
Dora, how are we going
to get through the bush?
Ah...!
[ whispering]:
I have an idea.
If we open our mouths
really wide and say "Ah..."
the bush will echo us
and say "Ah..."
and then we can jump right
through it to the other side!
[ whispering]
...other side!
I need your help.
Say "Ah..."
BOTH: Ah...!
Ah...!
[ louder]:
BOTH:
Yay!
[ play happy tune]
We made it through
the Echo Bush!
Thanks for saying "Ah..."!
Where do we go next?
Bush...
Ocean...
Coquí's Island.
We went through the bush...
Through the bush...
so now we have to
go over the...
[ click, beep]
Ocean, right!
Now, where is
the Ocean?
[ click, beep]
Yeah, there's the Ocean!
Come on,
let's take Coquí home!
So he can sing!
Come on, say it with us.
BOTH:
Bush, Ocean, Coquí's Island!
♪ Come on, vámonos♪
♪ Everybody, let's go ♪
♪ Come on,
let's get to it ♪
♪ I know
that we can do it ♪
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Coquí's Island ♪
BOTH:
♪ Where are we going? ♪
♪ Coquí's Island ♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí's Island! ♪
[ laughing]
BOTH:
♪ Coquí's Island! ♪
[ waves crashing gently]
Boy, this ocean
sure is foggy!
Sure is, Boots.
Coquí, coquí...
Don't worry, little buddy.
We'll get you home.
[ whispers]:
How are we going to
get him home?
We just have to find a way
to get over the ocean.
Let's stop and think.
Do you see anything
that can take us over the Ocean?
Right, the boat!
A boat can carry us
over the Ocean
and take us
to Coquí's Island!
So he can sing!
[ strums guitar]
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí!
Look, it's our friend
Señor Tucán.
Hola, Dora y Boots.
Hola, Coquí.
iHola!Hi!
Señor Tucán, ¿nos puedes llevar
a la isla del coquí?
iSí, pues claro!
Pero tienen que apurarse.
Señor Tucán can take us
to Coquí's Island
but we have to get tickets
to go on the boat.
[ beeping]:
Una moneda, por favor.
Dora, what's it saying?
Tickets cost one coin each!
Oh no, I don't have
any coins!
I bet I have coins
in my Backpack.
I need your help.
Will you check my Backpack
and find the coins?
You have to say "Backpack."
Say "Backpack,"
say "Backpack"!
[ music playing...]
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ I'm the Backpack, loaded up ♪
♪ With things
and knickknacks, too ♪
♪ Anything that you might need ♪
♪ I got inside for you ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack ♪
♪ Backpack, Backpack, yeah! ♪
iHola!I'm the Backpack.
I have lots of stuff.
But Dora and Boots need
the red coins with five dots
so they can buy tickets
to get on the boat.
First, let's find
all the red coins.
[ click, beep, click, beep]
Right! Now, which are
the red coins with five dots?
[ click, beep]
Right! iExcelente!
You found the red coins
with five dots!
Yum, yum, yum! iDelicioso!
The coins! Great!
We need a coin
for each of us.
So how many coins
do we need?
Three coins, right!
The ticket machine
speaks Spanish
so let's counts the coins
in Spanish.
Repeat after me.
Uno...
dos...
tres.
That's three coins
for the three of us.
[ beeping]
BOOTS AND DORA:
Yay!
Thank you for helping us
count to three in Spanish.
iTodos a bordo! iApurense!
We better hurry!
We're going to have you
home soon, Coquí!
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí!
Here comes the fog, Dora.
And a lot of it.
I can't see a thing.
Good thing
there aren't
any other ships.
We could bump
right into them!
What's wrong, Coquí?
You see what?
A ship?
Ooh-ooh, ah-ah!
BOOTS:
Look, it's a big ship
and it's coming
straight at us!
We have to tell the
big ship to watch out
or it will bump into us!
iCuidado! iCuidado!
DORA:
The big ship's
not stopping, Dora!
I need your help.
Put your arms
in the air
and wave them
back and forth.
Now say "cuidado."
Say it with us.
BOOTS AND DORA:
iCuidado!
iCuidado! iCuidado!
[ toots horn]
BOOTS AND DORA:
Yay!
Thanks for helping us
say "cuidado"
to warn the other ship.
[ play happy tune]
We made it
across the Ocean!
BOTH:
All right!
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí!
We have to get Coquí home.
So he can sing!
[ whispers]:
Coquí, coquí!
Dora, where do we
go next?
Bush...
Ocean...
Coquí's Island.
We went through the bush...
Through the bush.
...over the Ocean...
so next is...
[ click, beep]
Coquís:
Coquí, coquí!
Coquí's Island, right!
Do you see
Coquí's Island?
You do? Where?
[ click, beep]
[ whispers]:
Coquí, Coquí!
Yeah, there it is!
There's Coquí's Island!
Let's go!
Oh, Boots, the ship
can't go any further
because of all the rocks
in the water!
Oh, no!
How are we going to get Coquí
home so he can sing?
Look at Coquí!
He's jumping
across the rocks!
Yeah, just like a frog!
I know, we can
jump like Coquí
across the rocks.
Will you help us jump
across the rocks?
Great!
You have to stand up
to jump like Coquí.
Stand up, please.
Stand up!
Up, up, up! Up, up, up!
Now bend your knees
and crouch down low.
Crouch down,
crouch down!
Now jump up
like Coquí.
Jump!
Jump...
jump...
jump!
BOTH:
Yay!
Good jumping!
[ play happy tune]
You're home now, Coquí!
You're home!
Hey, Dora, now that
Coquí's home
do you think he can sing?
Yeah, Coquí,
sing us your song!
Go ahead, Coquí.
You can do it!
[ loudly]:
Coquí, coquí!
[ playing tune]
♪ Coquí... coquí... ♪
He's singing,
he singing!
♪ Coquí... coquí... ♪
Listen, Dora!
He's all better
now!
♪ Coquí! Quí! Quí... ♪
He sure is, Boots.
♪ Coquí... Coquí... ♪
♪ Coquí! Quí! Quí! Quí! Quí! ♪
Ooh, look!
It's Coquí's
friends!
♪ Coquí... ♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí...♪
♪ Coquí... ♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí! Quí! Quí! !
♪ Quí! Quí! ♪
♪ Coquí... ♪
♪ Coquí...♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí! Quí! Quí! !
♪ Quí! Quí! ♪
Wow! That sounds
so beautiful.
I want to sing, too!
Let's all sing with Coquí!
Sing with us!
ALL: ♪ Coquí... ♪
♪ Coquí...♪
♪ Coquí... ♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí! Quí! Quí! Quí! Quí! ♪
♪ Coquí... ♪
♪ Coquí...♪
BOTH:
♪ Coquí... ♪
♪ Coquí...♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí! Quí! Quí! Quí! Quí! ♪
BOTH:
♪ Coquí... ♪
♪ Coquí...♪
ALL:
♪ Coquí! Quí! Quí! Quí! Quí! ♪
[ kisses]
BOTH:
We did it!
[ music playing]
BOTH:
♪ We did it! ♪
Yay!
♪ iLo hicimos!♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We went
through the bush ♪
♪ and over the Ocean ♪
♪ Yeah, we did it! ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We did it! Hooray! ♪
♪ We helped Coquí
get home to his island ♪
♪ We did it! ♪
♪ We said "Ah..."
at the Echo Bush ♪
♪ and we made it
through ♪
♪ Coquí got home,
he sang loud ♪
♪ Whoo-hoo! ♪
Yay!
Whoo! Hooray!
We did it!
Whoo!
[ click, beep]
We had such an exciting
adventure today.
What was your favorite
part of the trip?
I liked that too.
My favorite part was
when we said "Ah..."
and the Echo Bush
opened its mouth
and we jumped through
to the other side.
My favorite part was
when we got to hear Coquí sing.
We couldn't
have brought Coquí
home to his island
without you.
Thanks for helping!
[ click, beep]
DORA:
This is my friend
Isa the Iguana.
Find Isa!
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
and NICKELODEON
Captioned byThe Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[ click, beep]
[ giggles]
[ giggles, laughs]